[{"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "In our industry you will communicate with customers of all kinds including designers, builders, commercial companies, and private customers. How will you adjust to the variety of contacts?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you can communicate with a wide range of customers who have varying needs. Talk about the scope of customers that you deal with in your current position.", "\"In my current position I work with a large range of clients that include walk-ins as well as taking orders over the phone and by email. Everyone has their communication style, and I am confident in my ability to meet their needs.\"", "\"I have always had a knack for getting along with a variety of personalities. I have full faith in my ability to adjust to a variety of contacts. I do have some training in customer service and dispute resolution, which I believe will help.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "At Company ABC we understand that our market is a competitive one. In your opinion, what makes us stand out from the crowd?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC before your interview. Take a good look at their competitors and make a note of any awards or recognition that Company ABC may have received. Be sure to compliment them on what they are doing right!", "\"Through some online research I see that your reviews are much stronger than those of your competitors. Your product lines are superior, and your reputation for great customer service seems to be unmatched. I am very excited to work with such a thoughtful and responsible company.\"", "\"I understand that this market is competitive; however, this is where my family and I have always shopped for our appliance and furniture needs. My experiences have always been amazing, so I would be honored to work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "As a manager, what is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Everyone has their weaknesses, and that is okay! Talk to the hiring manager about what you feel you could work on the most, and what you are doing about it. Avoid discussing a weakness that could be detrimental to you securing the position.", "\"As a manager, I feel that my greatest weakness is in terminating employees at the first sign that they are not going to work out. I try to give people the benefit of the doubt and have been guilty of trying to nurture people when they are overdue for termination. I have worked on this and am becoming much better at \"", "\"The feedback that I have received in the past is that I could improve my technical skills when it comes to Microsoft Excel and PowerPoint. I have enrolled myself in a course for next month where I should come out as an intermediate user.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"When my manager went on unexpected medical leave for three months last year I was asked to step into her position in the interim. I knew the basics but was certainly not trained on the specifics of the role. I was able to take it on successfully by leaning on my team, reading a lot of company manuals, and asking many questions. Once my manager returned she was very pleased with the progress that I made, and I was awarded a promotion.\"", "\"In my current position, I was put on the sales floor before I received any training. It was certainly more than I expected; however, my natural sales instinct kicked in, and I had a successful first day, and beyond!\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking your work and proofreading are critical parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean, work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is essential to submit error-free work.\"", "\"I try to double check or proofread my work on a regular basis, as time allows. I can say that I do have a stronger level of attention to detail than most.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"When I feel listened to, and appreciated, I am very motivated to do my best. It isn't difficult to keep me motivated on a daily basis when I enjoy what I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "What part of this career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (IE: a bus driver should not find driving to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"The part of my career that brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on my teams part. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that my clients are assisted properly.\"", "\"I find that the primary stressor in my current position is the fact that my team is not as reliable as I would like. For this reason, I am seeking a new opportunity, within a professional environment, with a team who values their job as much as I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who want a long-term fit. What is your long-range career objective?", "answers": ["Onboarding new employees is a time consuming and costly endeavor so the interviewer wants to make sure that this role will be a long-term fit for you. Be open with the interviewer about your dreams within Company ABC, on a long-term basis.  Share what promotions you hope to eventually receive and discuss what you wish to learn from being a part of their organization. The key to answering this question is to express to the interviewer that you plan to be employed by the company for many years to come.", "\"While visiting your company website I noticed that you have some leadership opportunities available in a variety of locations. I would love to work my way into a management or leadership role with your organization and would be willing to relocate to do so. I really like what your organization stands for, and I hope to see a current fit, and future growth, here.\"", "\"I am looking for a position with which I can grow, specifically into a Director of Marketing position. I know it's a few years off, of course, but that's where I am looking to end up within the next 5 or so years.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "What do you know about wholesale pricing and how we come to a manufacturer's suggested retail price (MSRP)?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you understand the basics of pricing when it comes to wholesale and manufacturer markups. This knowledge will help you to understand how discounting works when it comes to negotiating with your customers. In this industry, strong negotiation skills can be the key to your success. Assure the interviewer that you are familiar with a variety of pricing practices. Be sure to mention any business classes you may have taken as well.", "\"I learned a bit about competitive pricing, markups, and successful price-driven promotions when I was taking my business degree. I understand that most companies seek a markup of at least 60 points and can discount from there if they are overstocked or need room for negotiations.\"", "\"I am new to retail pricing, and this industry; however, I am great with math calculations as well as negotiations, so I am confident in my ability to pick up the idea of MSRP.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "At Company ABC we like to hire team members who value customer service as much as we do. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["When you are in a competitive market such as this, you need to bring your 'A' game when it comes to customer service. Draw on any compliments or feedback that you have received from your customers in the past. Assure the interviewer that you are ready to uphold their customer service standards.", "\"My customer service philosophy is that you should always say 'yes' or 'I will try.' When it comes to customer service, I avoid saying the word 'no' as often as possible. Even if I can't make it happen for my customers in the end, at least I tried. Many customers have given my supervisor positive reviews on their experience with me. It's always nice to be told that you're doing a great job!\"", "\"Even though I am new to my career in customer service, I can confidently say that the key to great customer service is actively listening and being a friendly individual. I am prepared to uphold the customer service standards of Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Do you have experience working with a point of sale (POS) system and inventory management software?", "answers": ["Give the interviewer a brief overview of the POS and Inventory Management software and systems that you have used in the past. You can also list any additional programs that you are well versed in.", "\"I am an intermediate user in Microsoft Dynamics and Retail Pro. In addition to these point of sales systems, I have 3 years' experience in Paragon ERP.\"", "\"I have not worked directly with a point of sale system; however, I am very savvy when it comes to technical systems.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Company ABC has many competitors in the area. Are you currently interviewing with any of them? If you were offered multiple positions, why would you choose us?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are currently meeting with any of their competitors to discuss open positions. If you were to receive multiple offers that were similar, why would you choose Company ABC? Assure the interviewer that you are genuinely interested in joining them, and not just looking for any job to fill your time at the moment.", "\"I have sent out only a few resumes, and the majority of them are within this industry. With that said, my first choice would be with Company ABC. I like that you promote from within and give opportunities based on performance.\"", "\"You are the only company with which I am currently interviewing. I have been very selective with my job applications.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "At Company ABC we have a wide range of products and SKU's. Are you able to learn about a wide range of products without becoming overwhelmed?", "answers": ["Handling a multitude of SKU's is a tricky skill. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of learning a significant amount of information in a short amount of time. What will you do to make sure that you are a quick study?", "\"In my current position we have approximately 150 different SKU's which doesn't seem like a lot; however, we have many different color and design options within each SKU. If awarded this position, I can certainly commit to spending overtime hours studying and memorizing your product base.\"", "\"I am fully prepared for the learning curve ahead, should I be the successful candidate with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Do you have experience in managing online sales?", "answers": ["For most industries, online sales and marketing have become incredibly important. Talk to the interviewer about your experience and understanding when it comes to social media and online marketing efforts. Has there ever been a time that your online sales efforts have made a significant impact on your employer?", "\"A couple of years ago I worked as a sales manager for a local furniture store. Our sales were slower than usual, so I started an Instagram account for the store where we would feature particular pieces. We garnered quite a strong following, and we did see an increase in walk-in traffic over time. I am also well versed in managing web-based sales as my current employer has a strong e-commerce presence.\"", "\"I have a lot of experience with social media marketing, and even attended a few online marketing courses while attending my business degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Tell me about a contribution you made to the last team you worked on.", "answers": ["It is essential to show the interviewer that you are a team player. Talk about a time that you were recently expected to achieve a goal in a team setting. How did you go over and above to ensure that your contribution was felt?", "\"Last month our company asked upper management to complete a full inventory audit. There were 4 of us in total and so we broke the audit requirements into shifts. These shifts had to take place when the warehouse was closed. In the end, there was one additional shift that nobody wanted to take. I volunteered myself to do that shift to show my dedication to my job and my co-workers. The gesture was appreciated, and the audit was completed on time.\"", "\"The most recent team-based project that I was a part of was in University while earning my Business degree. I worked on a final project with four others, and my contribution was strong. I found myself stepping into a leadership role where I delegated tasks and helped the team maintain a good pace. We hit our deadline and received a solid grade.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I am happy with my career progression and wouldn't change a thing. Great opportunities have come my way at the best times, and I believe that this position is a perfect fit for me at this stage in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "How do you handle a situation where your supervisor does not properly communicate information to you?", "answers": ["You cannot force others to communicate with you in a way that you would always prefer. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have handled a supervisor who does not interact with you in a way that you like.", "\"Whenever I have had a supervisor who does not properly communicate with me, I try to learn their style of communication and emulate it. Sometimes you have to relate to others in their style to be understood.\"", "\"It is not always up to my supervisor to communicate everything to me, exactly. I believe that I should also take responsibility for my learning. If a supervisor is not meeting my communication expectations, I will find the answer through my efforts.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "How do you believe you will complement our department, if you were hired?", "answers": ["If awarded the position, what would you bring to the department or organization? Assure the interviewer that you are the right fit for this position.", "\"If hired, I feel that I would compliment your organization because I am a fast learner and I already bring six years' experience in this industry. The time to train me will be reduced significantly.\"", "\"If hired, I will bring a powerful portfolio of clients with me which will make a financial impact on Company ABC almost immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I am an active person and believe in the importance of pursuing creative interests outside of work. I most enjoy working out and going to pottery classes.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "We are asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"My five years of experience have been strong ones, with great results, and true dedication. I am confident in my ability to thrive in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Do people see you as a trustworthy and honest individual?", "answers": ["It is easy to say that you are trustworthy and honest, but it's best if you can back it up with a review or words from a previous supervisor.", "\"I am told quite often that I am an honest and trustworthy individual and you will be able to hear that directly from my supervisor when you call for a reference. I hold honesty and trustworthiness as fundamental virtues.\"", "\"Yes, people see me as trustworthy and honest. I was raised with a strong moral compass, and I try hard to be my best, every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "How competitive are you?", "answers": ["Being a competitive person is an excellent thing if you are appropriately competitive in the workplace. Assure the interviewer that you have a tremendous competitive edge when necessary but are still able to balance that competition healthily.", "\"I think that on a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as a 7 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last years' numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my team or colleagues.\"", "\"I can be competitive when it's required. For instance; when a sales goal is at hand, or a contest is offered. Other than that, I prefer a balanced team environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"Although my current salary is $45K/year, I am seeking $52K in my next position. Because I work for a very small organization, they are not able to offer me a competitive compensation compared to the industry marketplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Tell me about a time when you received criticism from your manager. How did you react to that criticism? How did you make improvements based on that criticism?", "answers": ["When you are thinking about examples of criticism, it's best to show that you want to grow as an employee and that you can handle constructive criticism because it helps you learn and improve the quality of your work.", "\"I was instructed to create some presentations for our events. After my manager reviewed my work, some of the slides required additional copy, and he had different design concepts in mind. He had a background in graphic design, and since I do not, I listened to his ideas and incorporated them. I thought they looked very professional and in the following presentations I tried to include those design concepts.\"", "\"My current manager is quite critical of my work and often double checks to ensure that I am following protocol at all times. I understand that he values thoroughness and it doesn't bother me much because I am very detail oriented, anyways. Anything he catches, I am quick to fix. I believe that our customers deserve that level of attention and care.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "What questions do you have for me about working with Company ABC?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"Assuming that the projects have different stakeholders, I interview each to determine the value of increased productivity, morale or revenue, decreased costs, and the overall impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Appliances+and+Furniture", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Merely share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. My vehicle is well maintained, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to your office every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations are to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000 and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"In my most recent position, I was earning $15/hour. Since then, I have taken additional automotive courses. I would like to earn at least $17/hour in my next position.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a very honest person or do you have room for growth? This could be a tricky question as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your personal ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself a 9 because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I was raised to be honest and sincere. Honesty is a value that is very important to me so I'd like to rank myself high on the honesty scale.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Judging by your resume, you appear to be overqualified for this position. What would keep you here, if you were offered the position?", "answers": ["Sometimes, hiring an overqualified individual can mean that they will leave when a better opportunity arises. Talk to the interviewer about why this position would be satisfying for you, long term.", "\"I do have more years' experience than what you have outlined in your job posting;however, there are aspects of this position that would be new and exciting for me as well.\"", "\"I would really enjoy the exposure to more client development. that this position offers. Despite my level of experience, there would be much for me to learn here.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "At Company ABC we try very hard to get the best price on parts so that we can pass those savings on to our customers. Do you have strong negotiation skills? Have you ever negotiated price with a vendor?", "answers": ["Negotiating the price of a part, or even the cost of shipping, can have a very positive impact on an organizations' bottom line. Display to the interviewer that you have an awareness of this practice and that you are comfortable in negotiations.", "\"In my current position I will negotiate price and breaks on shipping all of the time. A few dollars here and there can make a huge difference in the end. The majority of negotiations that I have successfully completed were for bulk orders where the price per part was reduced by a small amount and free shipping was included.\"", "\"I understand that negotiations are an important part of running a successful auto parts business. I am comfortable working in a client facing role where negotiations are required.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to promote our staff internally. Do you have interest in a leadership or management role in the future?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any ambitions you may have when it comes to career growth with Company ABC. Why do you feel this is a long term fit for you? Do you have plans of being promoted into a new position in a short amount of time?", "\"I really like that you choose to promote your current staff before you go outside of the company to hire. I have some leadership experience in my current role and plan to prove my skills very quickly after being hired on here.\"", "\"I am newer to my career so I haven't really given leadership and management a lot of thought but yes, I have to say that I would like to be further trained in a leadership role one day.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of focus on having the best inventory over our competitors. Have you ever made a suggestion on a product line or item?", "answers": ["An engaged employee will notice when changes are required. They make recommendations and suggestions they feel will benefit the organization. Have you ever taken the lead by making a recommendation to your employer?", "\"I made a recommendation last month that we try a new line of parts after one of our particular vendors shorted us on inventory. The vendor that I suggested was newer to the industry but their customer service was impressive and their pricing was more competitive. We gave them a shot and it worked out really well for us, resulting in cost savings and happier customers.\"", "\"I often make small suggestions in the workplace. Minor tweaks here and there that will improve productivity. I prefer working in an environment where employee suggestions are welcomed.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Briefly tell the interviewer about your search so far.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for suitable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"Although I am being selective, I am actively pursuing other similar opportunities. Do you have a time frame for when you would like to have this position filled?\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "How many people did you supervise at your last position?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your level of responsibility in your current position. If you have managed larger teams than you currently are, you can also discuss that particular role from your work history.", "\"Currently, I am supervising 12 employees with an overall budget responsibility of $4M. In my role, prior to this one, I managed 23 employees but with a smaller portfolio of $2MM. I am able to handle a large range of employees.\"", "\"This position would be my first official leadership role; however, I have jumped into unofficial leadership duties in the past. Currently our team is made up of 15 individuals with 8 being quite new to the industry. I have taken them under my wing and train them quite often on process and product knowledge.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "How do you handle a situation where your supervisor does not properly communicate information to you?", "answers": ["You cannot force others to communicate with you in a way that you would always prefer. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have handled a supervisor who does not communicate with you in way that you like.", "\"Whenever I have had a supervisor who does not properly communicate with me, I try to learn their style of communication and emulate it. Sometimes you simply have to relate to others in their own style to be understood.\"", "\"If I were to have a supervisor who did not communicate properly with me, I would be open and ask them to be clearer on their expectations of me.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"Diversity is everywhere, even outside of the workplace, and I embrace that. My current company offer a lot of diversity when it comes to the workforce, which I appreciate.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "How would your co-workers describe your attention to detail?", "answers": ["It is always best to support your reply with a real life example. Talk to the interviewer about your level of attentiveness when it comes to details on the job.", "\"My co-workers would describe my attention to detail as very strong. I can very easily point out spelling discrepancies in communication and will notice the small things. I think big-picture as well but have always had a knack for details.\"", "\"I have always been known for being a bit picky when it come to details, proofreading, and documentation. I'm okay with that though because attention to detail is a great skill to have!\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their own particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not a mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "Try turning your answer into a positive tone, versus talking about your dissatisfaction. \n\r\nFor example: \"I feel most satisfied on the job when I feel valued, listened to, and am continually learning.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "What would you do if you were made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company?", "answers": ["Companies want to know they are hiring loyal employees. Make sure that you demonstrate in your answer that you would do the right thing and represent the company you are working for.", "\"Unfortunately, dishonest employees are everywhere and I certainly would not consider myself a 'whistle-blower' in the workplace. If I found that a co-worker was stealing, or doing anything to harm the company, I would approach them directly to ask what was going on. There is a good chance of the situation being a simple misunderstanding. If it wasn't a misunderstanding and the co-worker was being outright defiant with their damaging actions then I would bring it up, in a professional manner, to the appropriate parties.\"", "\"Dishonesty is unacceptable, in my opinion. If I was made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company, I would notify my supervisor immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Where did you come across our job posting?", "answers": ["The employer would like to know what methods you are using in your job search, and which job posting  methods are working for them. \n\r\nYou can expand your answer to include any other exposure you have had to the company.", "\"I initially saw your job posting on LinkedIn, however; I have been exposed to your organization many times before through your radio commercials and advertisements on Facebook.\"", "\"I have had an eye on your company website for some time now. A friend of mine has worked for your organization and she said it was the best place to work. So, I've had an ear to the ground for new openings at Company ABC. When I saw the posting on your website, I was so excited to apply!\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Have you ever been in charge of sales and promotions during periods of overstock?", "answers": ["Time to put on your sales and marketing hat! Talk to the interviewer about any exposure you have had to promoting a sale or particular service. What steps did you take to make the promotion successful? Was it a success in the end?", "\"Every year our company has a year-end promotion where we offer a free service with another booked service. For instance; we will offer free tire rotation with an oil change. Or, we will offer BOGO on our overstocked parts. It's always been a great success; however, this year I recommended that we promote the event on our business Facebook page. Taking the promotion to social media created so much more awareness that we actually sold 28% more than we did last year!\"", "\"I have actively participated in sales and promotions, in my previous positions. Even though I was not considered an official leader, I did take some initiative when it came to planning our last inventory blowout event.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Do you have experience with stock control software or programs related to the analysis of parts sales and movement?", "answers": ["There are many options when it comes to stock and inventory control systems. Some are for the masses and other organizations may have proprietary software. When asked about your exposure to these types of programs it is important to remember that most of them function the same because the desired outcome is always similar. If you know one, you should be able to more easily understand another. Avoid focusing on what you don't know and focus on what you DO know. Assure the interviewer that you can learn their system quickly.", "\"You mention in your job posting that you are looking for someone with experience in Software ABC. I have worked with Software XYZ which is very similar. The functions are essentially the same and since I am an expert level user in XYZ. I am confident that I will be a fast learner when it comes to ABC and your other internal programs.\"", "\"I am a quick study when it comes to software and other technical requirements in the workplace. I may not have experience with your exact program but I am very confident in my ability to learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire individuals with a true interest in our industry. Do you have any formal education or training in an automotive related field?", "answers": ["Discuss any post-secondary education and training that you may have. How does it relate to a career with Company ABC? Assure the interviewer that you have a keen interest in the auto parts industry.", "\"I have always had a very strong interest in the automotive industry. My grandfather had an auto parts shop where I spent most of my summers working and training under him. I went on to business school so that I could eventually help him with some of the finer aspects of his business.\"", "\"I have some educational background in the automotive and mechanics industry. This is definitely a focus for me in my career and I look forward to expanding my knowledge through my time with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Proper inventory management is very important for the success of our business. Do you have any inventory management experience?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any exposure, big or small, that you have had with managing inventory. It is preferable that you talk about inventory experience in the auto parts industry but not necessarily a deal breaker if you don't have any. Have you ever caught an inventory error that saved the company money? Talk about any inventory wins you may have.", "\"In my current position I was trained on their proprietary inventory management software. My manager wanted me to learn how to forecast trends in inventory needs for the shop. I am not at the level where I can make decisions yet but I am definitely getting there.\"", "\"I understand that inventory management is important to the success of Company ABC which is why I am willing to do what it takes to learn your inventory management system. Although I don't have experience working with inventory management programs, I am confident in my abilities to manage inventory because I am well organized and pay attention to the small details.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "If you could choose, would you prefer working in auto parts and service or in auto part sales?", "answers": ["When it comes to a career in the auto parts industry, there are many different avenues you can choose. Do you consider yourself more of a salesman and people person, or are you more technical / analytical with a preference for the parts and service side? It's great to express a preference, if you have one, but you also want to show the interviewer that you are multi-faceted and able to work in most areas of their business.", "\"I have always had a strong lean towards sales and service; however, I am also very knowledgeable when it comes to mechanics and parts. I feel that my mechanical knowledge is key to my success in auto part sales. This makes me a very well rounded candidate for you since I can work successfully in most functions.\"", "\"I have always had a preference for sales so I do feel that I would prefer to land in a sales driven role. I am very knowledgeable with a variety of parts and would be a valuable member of your auto parts sales team.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Do you have experience working directly with parts manufacturers and vendors?", "answers": ["Have you ever been asked to call a manufacturer or vendor directly? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to clearly communicate parts and inventory needs to the appropriate vendors. If you do not have experience in dealing directly with vendors or manufacturers, be sure to speak highly about your communication skills - be that over email or phone. \n\r\nIf you have experience working directly with parts manufacturers and vendors:\n\r\n\"Yes, I was the primary point of contact with many vendors in my most recent position. I have strong relationships established with A, B, and C (list the vendors that Company ABC may have current relationships with) and I am happy to bring that rapport with me, should I be the candidate that you choose. \"", "\"Yes, I was the primary point of contact with many vendors in my most recent position. I have strong relationships established with A, B, and C (list the vendors that Company ABC may have current relationships with) and I am happy to bring that rapport with me, should I be the candidate that you choose. \"", "If you do not have experience working directly with parts manufacturers and vendors: \n\r\n\"My experience with vendors is limited; however, I am confident in my communication skills and know that I could take that task on effectively.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "At Company ABC we do our best to satisfy every customer. How do you go above and beyond for your customers?", "answers": ["Great customer service is the backbone of any company's success. Talk to the interviewer about your customer service philosophy. In which ways do you go above and beyond for your customers? Be specific.", "\"In my current position I will go above and beyond by making customer service follow up calls. I want to know how our customers feel about the service they receive and if they would be a returning customer. Knowing how we can improve our service and product offerings always gives a competitive edge.\"", "\"I go above and beyond for the customers that I work with by actively listening to them and working with them on their needs. I am very happy to dedicate myself to your customers and their needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "What qualities do you feel a successful manager should have?", "answers": ["Some great qualities of a manager are:\n\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\n- Strong relationship building skills\n- Taking ownership of the team's errors and mistakes\n- Excelling at motivating others\n- Providing kudos/recognition to your team\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\n- Having a vision for the future\n\nThese are just a few to get started!", "\"Leading by example is the number one characteristic a great manager should have. Followed by, listening and being stern with employees when needed. Having great customer and product awareness are great characteristics as well.\"", "\"I feel that a successful manager should be someone who is observant, knows how to coach others, and leads by example. I strive to be all of these things so that I can jump into a management role in the future.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Tell me about one of the most rewarding experiences you had working on a team.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you feel accomplished through teamwork.  Get excited to share about a time when you really felt fulfilled through a team effort!  \n\nThis might have been a college team project, a recent experience at work, or possibly coaching a little league team.  \n\nStart off by giving the interviewer an overview of the purpose of the team. Next, dive into the results of the team and how you attained a positive outcome as a group.  \n\nBe sure to mention why the experience was so rewarding!", "\"Most of my jobs in manufacturing have been rather isolated experiences, but my last company, challenged all of the employees to have zero workplace injuries for the year. Before we began the year, we set out and looked over all the equipment and where most injuries occur and tried to place safety practices or protocols for those areas. We ended up having one injury throughout the year, but it was still a very fun and engaging experience.\"", "\"My favorite team project was a large group project I completed in my final semester of business school. The project was an important part of our grade and we had to re-create a business marketing strategy for an auto related company of our choice. I learned a lot of great habits from my teammates, primarily related to multitasking and time management.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "What part of this career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (IE: a bus driver should not find driving to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"The part of my career that brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on my teams part. I really like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that my clients are assisted properly.\"", "\"If I had to say that one area of my career in auto parts was more stressful than another, I would say that it takes a lot of work and dedication to keep up with the changes in the industry. For instance, the new parts, and all of the SKU's. I am up for the challenge though!\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "If you could alter your career path, in any way, what would you change?", "answers": ["This question will help the interviewer to understand if you have a long and continued passion for your career in the auto parts industry. Talk to the interviewer about an alternate career path that you might choose but be sure to keep it related to the position you are interviewing for.", "\"If I could change anything about my career path, I would have stayed in post-secondary studies for longer in order to upgrade in my field. I feel that this would have given me the advancement I seek now, many years earlier.\"", "\"I truly like the path that my career has taken and cannot say that I would change a thing. I am always happy to take additional coursework, and improve on my skills, but I am happy with a career in auto parts.\""]}, {"topic": "Auto+Parts", "question": "Tell me about a time when you made a suggestion requesting change in an organization.", "answers": ["In addition to being able to handle change, can you also recognize when change is required and be confident enough to present that to your organization? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to make a suggestion for change in the workplace.", "\"Last year when I was managing dispatch for my company I noticed a pretty solid opportunity for us to save on overtime hours. I created a presentation and gave it to my manager who took it to upper management. The changes were implemented and I was very proud of the suggestion that I made.\"", "\"This year I asked my manager if we could look at some new options for parts vendors. We ended up finding a couple of vendors who were more competitive with their pricing, so we made the switch. I am estimating that the change saves us close to $1000 per week.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "How do you motivate others on your team?", "answers": ["You don't have to be a manager or a team leader in order to motivate others. \n\r\nIf you have worked in a leadership role, think of ways you set clear goals or helped individuals cultivate a new skill. Reflect on your experience and share some ways that you help others to keep up the good work!", "\"I believe that offering a listening ear or encouraging words from time to time can make a huge difference for your team. Being positive and showing up consistently can also make a difference, so I try to exercise these ideas every day.\"", "\"I like to motivate others on my team by creating a fun and healthy competition. Most people that I know respond really well to that type of motivation. It could be in the form of a small sales contest or challenge. This week, I offered my team a $100 gift card for whomever could gain the most business through referrals.\"", "\"I believe that offering a listening ear or encouraging words from time to time can make a huge difference for your team. Being positive and showing up consistently can also make a difference, so I try to exercise these ideas every day.\"", "Consistency and positivity are fantastic points to make here. Good!"]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "How competitive are you?", "answers": ["Being a competitive person is a great thing if you are appropriately competitive in the workplace. Assure the interviewer that you have a great competitive edge, when necessary, but are still able to balance that competition in a healthy way.", "\"I think that on a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as a 7 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last years' numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my team or colleagues.\"", "\"I consider myself to be more internally competitive. I have high expectations of myself and will strive to do better than the day before.\"", "\"I think that on a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as a 7 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last year's numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my team or colleagues.\"", "A 7 is a great rating, and it's nice that you still mentioned the respect you maintain for your team."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "How do you organize your day?", "answers": ["Share some of the tools you have found helpful to stay on task and organized. If you keep a day planner or an organizer on your phone, explain how they have helped you keep track of assignments and tests. If you like to make to-do lists, this is a great example of tool that can help you stay organized and prioritize.", "\"I keep an updated Outlook calendar to keep track of work appointments, deadlines, and all of my outside activities. I am good at managing my time so that I complete projects on time and am prepared for customer appointments.\"", "\"A few of the tools that I use during the day to stay organized include Google Calendar, Slack, and Freedcamp. These tools help me to stay on top of my schedule, and easily collaborate with my team.\"", "\"I keep an updated Outlook calendar to keep track of work appointments, deadlines, and all of my outside activities. I am good at managing my time so that I complete projects on time and am prepared for customer appointments.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Tell me about your sales performance this year.", "answers": ["Numbers and percentages don't lie! This is the best time to brag about yourself and your achievements in your current / most recent position.", "\"So far this year, I am 113% to target with 3 more months to go. I have been the top sales performer in our dealership for the past 5 months. I attribute this to my great follow up habits as well as my strong cold calling skills.\"", "\"My supervisor is very happy with my performance so far this year. I fully expect to exceed my targets this quarter.\"", "\"My supervisor is very happy with my performance so far this year. I fully expect to exceed my targets this quarter.\"", "If you have further details (without breaking any non-disclosure agreements) then try to add some numbers and percentages into your response. Interviewers love specifics!", "\"My supervisor is thrilled with my performance so far this year. I am currently 94% to goal with another three months remaining until year end. I was top sales person of the month for the past four months running, and plan to take it again this month.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "What has been your biggest sale, to date?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are capable of handling all purchases, big and small! Talk about your largest sale and how you were able to close that particular deal.", "\"My largest sale, to date, was actually last week! I sold two top of the line models to one customer who paid in cash. It was the best sales day of my career so far.\"", "\"The biggest sale that I have made to date was around $40,000. It was really exciting to close that deal and I can't wait to do it again!\"", "\"My largest sale, to date, was actually two years ago when I worked in a book store! The week before Christmas, I sold an average of 10 books a day, which made me the employee who sold the most books in that store.\"", "Top sales! This is a solid example of knowing your numbers and readily offering them up in an interview."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who have a keen interest in the automobile industry. What interests you most about what we do?", "answers": ["Having a genuine interest in the automobile industry is going to be very important to the interviewer. A keen interest in this industry tells the hiring manager that you will most likely be engaged throughout your tenure.", "\"I have always had a keen interest in the automobile industry because style and technology is always changing. It's an exciting industry to be in! I am really interested in learning more about the technology that you have in your latest SUV models.\"", "\"The automobile industry is always changing, and what interests me most about this industry is that almost everyone takes note when a breakthrough is made. Even if you don't consider yourself a vehicle lover, you can't help but take note of new trends and exciting innovations.\"", "\"The automobile industry is always changing, and what interests me most about this industry is that almost everyone takes note when a breakthrough is made. Even if you don't consider yourself a vehicle lover, you can't help but take note of new trends and exciting innovations.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Are you experienced in warm and cold calling?", "answers": ["Not everyone likes to cold call, but it's still a very effective way of up-selling and ensuring that you are top of mind when it comes to customer purchases. Assure the interviewer that you understand the importance of follow up sales calls in the automotive industry.", "\"I have a lot of experience in cold and warm calling. Many of my sales have come from great follow up habits. I will also call previous buyers to up-sell on our maintenance services as well as to ask for referrals. I find that it's a lucrative way to spend any of my downtime.\"", "\"I have called on existing customers; however, I would benefit from additional training when it comes to warm, and cold calling.\"", "\"I have called on existing customers; however, I would benefit from additional training when it comes to warm, and cold calling.\"", "Perfectly said. It's so great that you asked for additional training. This shows strength of character and an eagerness that the interviewer will appreciate."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "What would you do if you were made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company?", "answers": ["Companies want to know they are hiring loyal employees. Make sure that you illustrate in your answer that you would do the right thing and represent the company you are working for.", "\"Unfortunately, dishonest employees are everywhere and I certainly would not consider myself a 'whistle-blower' in the workplace. If I found that a co-worker was stealing, or doing anything to harm the company, I would approach them directly to ask what was going on. There is a good chance of the situation being a simple misunderstanding. If it wasn't a misunderstanding and the co-worker was being outright defiant with their damaging actions then I would bring it, in a professional manner, to the appropriate parties.\"", "\"Dishonesty is unacceptable, in my opinion. If I was made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company, I would notify my supervisor immediately.\"", "\"Dishonesty is unacceptable, in my opinion. If I was made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company, I would notify my supervisor immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many great skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include skills that will potentially benefit Company ABC, if you are hired.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "\"In my most recent position, the skills that I am most proud of acquiring would include my well-honed leadership skills, my scheduling abilities, and my cold calling skills.\"", "\"In the past few years, I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel. In my most recent position, the skills that I am most proud of acquiring would include my well-honed leadership skills, my scheduling abilities, and communicative ability.\"", "Excellent! If you can, mention the education that you upgraded as the interviewer will likely be curious."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position we have a leader board and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition in me as well.\"", "\"I am competitive by nature so the best way to motivate me on the job would be to give me a contest or challenging goal.\"", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, I can sometimes feel that I do not get it, so I manage it by praising myself or asking for feedback.\"", "The fact that you can also self-motivate when you are not readily offered this, is a nice touch."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Why do you believe you will have success at this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Why are you the right fit for this particular position with Company ABC? This is a good time to highlight the skills you possess and show the interviewer that you are the best choice for the position.", "\"I feel that I will be successful in this position because I am passionate about what your organization stands for. I can clearly see your vision and have already drafted some great ideas on how I can help you to get there.\"", "\"My organizational skills will be a major asset to you and I also bring with me a strong track record of increasing sales and client base. These are just a couple of the reasons I feel that I'll be successful in this role with Company ABC.\"", "\"I feel that I will be successful in this position because I am passionate about what your organization stands for. I can clearly see your vision and have already drafted some great ideas on how I can help you to get there.\"", "Mentioning that you have already drafted some ideas is an excellent way to pique the interviewers' interest. This is good material for a second interview!"]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "How would you prefer to be compensated?", "answers": ["Are you looking for a compensation structure based primarily on salary, commission, or a blend of both? Discuss with the hiring manager how you would prefer to be compensated.", "\"I am currently compensated primarily on a base pay of $60,000 with the opportunity to earn a quarterly bonus based on the company's profits. I would like to be compensated in a similar way in my next position.\"", "\"Could you share with me a bit about your compensation structure? Currently I receive a small monthly guarantee; however, the bulk of my earnings come from commissions.\"", "\"I am currently compensated primarily on a base pay of $34,000 with the opportunity to earn a yearly bonus based on the company's profits. I would like to be compensated in a similar way in my next position.\"", "It's best to keep your compensation answer simple, which you have clearly done. Good job!"]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "We are moving quickly into second interviews. What is your availability like over the next few days?", "answers": ["Good news! If they are asking for you availability in the next few days, you likely made it to the next round. Try to be as flexible as possible with your availability.", "\"I can make myself available at any time, with some notice. The most ideal times for me to interview are between 8-9 AM and 4-5 PM Monday through Friday.\"", "\"I am happy to make myself available at your earliest convenience. I am very interested in this role and will be flexible when it comes to interview times.\"", "\"I am happy to make myself available at your earliest convenience. I am very interested in this role and will be flexible when it comes to interview times.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "The automobile industry is competitive. Are you comfortable working in a competitive environment?", "answers": ["Often times, positions within the automotive industry are sales and numbers driven. Assure the interviewer that you are comfortable and capable to work within a highly competitive environment.", "\"I am certainly accustomed to working in a competitive environment. My previous positions include keeping track of daily, weekly, and monthly sales metrics. I am absolutely able to thrive in a competitive environment.\"", "\"I have always been a competitive individual. From playing team sports my entire life, to working in commissioned retail environments. I am definitely comfortable with some friendly competition!\"", "\"I have always been a competitive individual. From playing team sports my entire life to working in commissioned retail environments. I am definitely comfortable with some friendly competition!\"", "When it comes to sales, many hiring managers like to hire those who have played sports in a competitive environment. This question is a very good time to mention your athletic background."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Walk me through your automobile industry experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer will likely already have your resume in front of them which means they are not looking for a dull play-by-play on your work history. They are asking you to bring your resume to life for them! This means talking about your key successes. Take a few minutes to highlight each position briefly. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a little bit.", "\"I started my career in the automobile industry in 2009 with Company XYZ. In that role I was the top employee for 9 months running. I was offered a promotion and moved to Chicago where i stayed for 4 years. After being offered a regional sales manager role with Company ABC. In total I have 6 years of automobile industry experience with great results and successes.\"", "\"I am a recent graduate from Cambridge University. There, I took many classes on business, sales, and marketing. While attending University, I worked part time for my uncle's auto dealership. I wasn't in a sales function but did act as a sales support to the existing sales team. I look forward to expanding my knowledge in the automotive industry, and working for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we set daily, weekly, and monthly targets for all of our sales employees. Have you worked with very specific KPI's as of late?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are comfortable with strict sales targets. If you have worked in this type of environment before, talk about what you did to ensure that your KPI's were met. Discuss your ability to work under the pressure associated with sales expectations.", "\"In my current position, we have many KPI's and other metrics that are measured and discussed in our weekly sales meetings. I am consistently a top performer in my company. I do thrive on the high expectations because the rewards are so high as well.\"", "\"My current position is 100% commission driven, so I fully understand the importance of meeting KPI's. Currently, my targets are very specific and I exceed them on a regular basis.\"", "\"My current position is 100% commission driven, so I fully understand the importance of meeting KPI's. Currently, my targets are very specific and I exceed them on a regular basis.\"", "Perfectly crafted response! If you have an example of a significant sale you have made, for instance, you could add in some more detail."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we like to train our employees in their particular areas of interest. If you could have training in any specific area, which topic would you choose?", "answers": ["Many companies will offer training to their top performing employees. If you could take additional training in any related area, what would you choose? Talk to the interviewer about the topics that interest you.", "\"If I could take training in any area with Company ABC I would first like to become a subject matter expert on your particular products and technology.\"", "\"I would be thrilled to take additional training on negotiations and closing a sale. I'm happy to hear that you offer continued training for your employees!\"", "\"I would be thrilled to take additional training on negotiations and closing a sale. I'm happy to hear that you offer continued training for your employees!\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we like to hire those who see a future in the automobile industry. Where do you see this position taking you in the future?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the type of career growth that you would like to see with Company ABC. Why do you want a career in the auto industry, and how do you think this position will help you to get there?", "\"I love sales and would be thrilled to have a lucrative career in sales with Company ABC. What excites me most about this opportunity is that there is room for advancement into a team leadership role. I would definitely like to work my way to a sales management position with Company ABC.\"", "\"I would like to learn as much as possible about this industry and eventually be in charge of a team within the service department.\"", "\"I love strategy and would be thrilled to have a lucrative career in sales with your company. What excites me most about this opportunity is that there is room for advancement into a team leadership role. I would definitely like to work my way to a sales management position with your company.\"", "Your response is specific and helpful to the interviewer. Well done."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "I see that you have recently worked for one of our direct competitors. Do you have a non-compete agreement in place?", "answers": ["In competitive markets such as the automobile industry you may sometimes be asked to sign a non-compete or non-disclosure agreement. Be honest and open with the interviewer about any existing restrictions you may have when it comes to working for a competing organization.\n\r\nIf you have a non-compete agreement: \"I did sign a non-compete with my current company; however, it just asks that I do not purposefully poach any of my clients from the past 3 years. I am not restricted when it comes to accepting offers of employment from competing dealerships.\"", "\"I did sign a non-compete with my current company; however, it just asks that I do not purposefully poach any of my clients from the past 3 years. I am not restricted when it comes to accepting offers of employment from competing dealerships.\"", "If you do not have a non-compete agreement: \"I am happy to say that I do not have any restrictions to my employment.\"", "\"I did sign a non-compete with my previous company; however, it just asks that I do not purposefully poach any of my clients from the past 2 years. I am not restricted when it comes to accepting offers of employment from competing dealerships.\"", "Excellent! It's great to always have that information on hand for an interview."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we have many competitors. Why do you want to work for us?", "answers": ["Researching the company before your interview is a very important task. After you have conducted your research, why do you want to work for Company ABC as opposed to their competitors? Be positive and talk to the interviewer about the great attributes of Company ABC that make you want to work specifically for them.", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because you have a reputation of putting your customers first, building a pristine product, and being fair to your employees. Your industry reputation is impressive and I would be proud to work here.\"", "\"I have a couple of friends who work for Company ABC and they only have great things to say about working here. I'd be thrilled to join your team.\"", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because you have a reputation of putting your customers first, building a pristine product, and being fair to your employees. Your industry reputation is impressive and I would be proud to work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Many positions in our company are fully commissioned. Are you confident enough in your sales abilities to work on 100% commission?", "answers": ["Talking about salary and compensation expectations can be uncomfortable but it is a very necessary conversation between yourself and the hiring manager.  Have you recently worked in a commission driven type of role? How are you currently compensated? Be open and communicative when it comes to your needs and compensation desires.", "\"I have worked on 100% commission in my last two sales positions; however, that is not my preference for the first few months as I become comfortable in a new position. Currently I am on a compensation guarantee of $4K/month or full   commission, whichever is greater. What are you offering in this particular role?\"", "\"I have worked in a 100% commission role for many years. I am comfortable enough with my sales abilities and customer base to take on another commission driven role.\"", "\"I have worked in a 100% commission role before. I am comfortable enough with my sales abilities and customer base to take on another commission-driven role.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "In your opinion, what sets our product apart from our competitors?", "answers": ["All you need to know is one major point that sets Company ABC apart from their competitors. Perhaps it's their product pricing, their technology, their overall reputation, or longevity in the industry. Choose one factor that impresses you the most and briefly discuss this with the interviewer.", "\"I have researched Company ABC a great deal and feel that the one thing that sets your product apart from others is the fact that you have the most incredible manufacturer's guarantee on the market. Buyers want security when they make such a large purchase and Company ABC offers just that.\"", "\"I believe that what sets your product apart from others is that it is already fairly priced, without having to add the gimmicks of steep discounts, family pricing, and blowout sales; for example. Your brand is trusted and you know how to show the value of your product through more than just the price tag.\"", "\"I believe that what sets your product apart from others is that it is already fairly priced, without having to add the gimmicks of steep discounts, family pricing, and blowout sales, for example. Your brand is trusted and you know how to show the value of your product through more than just the price tag.\"", "Bravo! Solid response that shows research and genuine interest."]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of pride in our customer service. How do you go above and beyond for your clientele?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you take customer service seriously. Use an example of a time when you have gone over and above the general expectations in order to make a customer happy. Be sure to acknowledge the customer service efforts that Company ABC puts forward.", "\"I go above and beyond with my customers by committing to my follow up calls with them. I have a very strong sense of organization and I always follow up when I say that I will. My customers appreciate my sense of responsibility and respect for their time.\"", "\"I always have a smile on my face! Another way that I go above and beyond for my customers is by never saying 'no'. I will say 'let me check into that for you' or 'let me see what I can do' or 'I will certainly try to find that answer for you'. It's amazing how a positive spin on all communication can improve a customers' level of satisfaction.\"", "\"I always have a smile on my face! Another way that I go above and beyond for my customers is by never saying 'no.' I will say 'let me check into that for you' or 'let me see what I can do' or 'I will certainly try to find that answer for you.' It's amazing how a positive spin on all communication can improve a customer's level of satisfaction. I have a very strong sense of organization, and I always follow up when I say that I will.\"", "It's these smaller details such as putting a positive spin on your wording that will make you a stand-out candidate every time. Great response!"]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Have you ever had a conflict with a boss or professor? How was it resolved?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you are respectful of your leaders, and while you do not always have to agree with your leader, that you communicate respectfully.  \n\r\nShare with the interviewer a time when you have disagreed with your boss or professor, but you did not argue or have conflict with that person.", "\"I believe that it's my job as a professional to adapt to all types of people, and respect leadership even when I disagree with decisions they make. My previous employer was very hung up on old-school sales techniques so I simply had to adapt while putting my own twist on the process, to make myself comfortable.\"", "\"I have been lucky enough to work with some great people and have not experienced conflict with a boss in the past. If I were to experience conflict in the workplace, I would address the situation right away through conversation. It's never a good idea to let conflict simmer and I'm not afraid to have an uncomfortable conversation to sort a situation out.\"", "\"I believe that it's my job as a professional to adapt to all types of people and respect leadership even when I disagree with the decisions they make. My previous employer was very hung up on the old-school approach to solving problems so I simply had to adapt while putting my own twist on the process, to make myself comfortable\"", "Adapting is good, and it's nice that you added in how you ensure that you respect your leadership. Right at the start, be sure to address the question more clearly. I have added a sample, below.", "\"I have never had a conflict with a boss. I believe that it's my job as a professional to adapt to all types of people and respect leadership even when I disagree with the decisions they make. My previous employer was very hung up on an old-school approach to solving problems, so I simply had to adapt while putting my twist on the process, to make myself comfortable.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Looking at your resume, I see multiple gaps between employment. What were you doing during those gaps?", "answers": ["There are many reasons for having a gap in your resume and it's best to be honest, and up front, about the reasons. Gaps are okay to have so long as there is a legitimate reason behind them. Also, show the interviewer that you did not remain dormant during that time. Talk about any courses you took, volunteer work you did, or any lucrative hobbies that filled your time.", "\"I had a gap from 2009-2010 while I was on maternity leave and then another for 6 months in 2015 while I cared for an ailing parent. During that time I was vigilant in keeping up to date on the market so that my knowledge did not become redundant.\"", "\"I was laid off in December of 2016 and, due to the recession, found it difficult to land employment for the 8 months following that lay off. Luckily, I received a good severance package from my previous employer. I took the time to travel around east Asia, and I even learned a second language. It was time very well spent.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Tell me about a time when you took the initiative to improve work related procedures.", "answers": ["Have you ever taken the opportunity to present your employer with potential change? Talk to the hiring manager about a time when you took initiative in the workplace.", "\"I was able to present and implement one specific change in the office this past year. It was a recycling program that I felt was very important, even for our smaller office. We had significantly less waste after my initiative was implemented and I enjoyed seeing others take pride in helping our environment.\"", "\"This year I asked my manager if we could look at some new options for parts vendors. We ended up finding a couple of vendors who were more competitive with their pricing, so we made the switch. I am estimating that the change saves us close to $1000 per week.\"", "\"I was able to present and implement one specific change in the office this past year. I took the initiative to female account lunches where we met each other to discuss different equality topics in work life.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any interest that you have in creativity and how you have implemented that creativity in the workplace.", "\"I do consider myself to be a creative individual. One example of this would be the telephone sales scripts that I crafted for our inside sales team. They were lively and effective, and sales increased by 23% in the first 90 days of implementation.\"", "\"I believe that creativity shows itself in many forms so, although I am not an artsy creative type, I do still consider myself creative. I come up with original ideas on a regular basis, and am a very strong creative writer.\"", "\"I believe that creativity shows itself in many forms so, although I am not an artsy creative type, I do still consider myself creative. I come up with original ideas on a regular basis and am a very strong creative writer.\""]}, {"topic": "Automobiles", "question": "What experience do you have using team-based messaging applications?", "answers": ["There are many options for communication software and messaging applications. Give the interviewer a brief overview of the applications you are experienced in and assure them that you can learn their internal system, should it be new to you.", "\"I have used a variety of team based messaging applications. I am best versed in Brosix, AOL Instant Messenger, and Freedcamp. No matter which system you use I am sure that I can pick it up very quickly.\"", "\"In my previous positions I have not used any team-based messaging applications; however, I am technically savvy and confident that I can pick up any program you need me to. Which team-based messaging application do you use at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"If I had to start my career over again, I would take the same direction! Working in this industry has been incredibly fulfilling for me, and I have zero regrets with the path my career has taken me.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "This position is an entry level role. Where would you like to see your career with Company ABC take you?", "answers": ["Interviewing and hiring new employees is a time consuming and often costly venture for Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that you genuinely want to work for Company ABC by talking about the career growth that you anticipate.", "\"I saw on your website that you are hiring estimators. I would like to work my way into an estimator role with Company ABC once I have proven my capabilities and completed any required education.\"", "\"I would love the opportunity to stay with Company ABC for the long term; eventually growing into a management position. I see that many of your management level employees started in entry-level roles. I appreciate that you promote from within, whenever possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Tell me about your most significant work experience that relates to this position.", "answers": ["This question is an excellent example as to why it is crucial for you to review the job description, in detail, before your interview. Have you ever held a similar position to this one? Can you draw any similarities between this role and another job that you have had?", "\"3 years ago, I worked for Company X in a very similar position. It required less team supervisory experience but additional educational components. The role also involved shift work and the ability to lift up to 50 lbs on a regular basis. These factors prepared me for a position like this one with Company ABC.\"", "\"This position with Company ABC would be my first role in the building products/construction materials industry; however, I have worked for manufacturers in the past. These roles taught me useful transferable skills such as customer service, inventory management, and health and safety best practices.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Company ABC has taken much care over the years to create healthy vendor relationships. How would you handle it if a vendor shorted you on inventory, resulting in a costly project delay?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you can work proactively with vendors when it comes to fixing errors and managing inventory expectations. Display your ability to remain professional, yet firm.", "\"In my current position, I have strong relationships with my vendors. If it ever happens that inventory is short, they will usually go out of their way to source the product from another one of their contacts.\"", "\"If a vendor shorted me on inventory, which resulted in a project delay, I would be clear with them about the repercussions while, at the same time, giving them the wiggle room to work hard to fix the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "When have you taken an existing process and used your own creativity to make it better?", "answers": ["Are you given the creative freedom to improve existing processes? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to take an existing process and develop it creatively.", "\"Last month my supervisor asked me to take our existing sales training package and improve it. My goal was to make the system more engaging for recruits. Once we implemented my ideas, we increased our new trainee retention rate by 16%. I was quite proud of what my creativity could do!\"", "\"I created a new training manual for our labor employees, last year. It included safety tips, training suggestions, and how-tos. Our employees appreciated having the resource, and I enjoyed creating it!\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. Traits could include buzzwords such as extroverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "Here are some other words you can use to describe your personality without using overused keywords: \n\n- Adaptable\n- Balanced\n- Capable\n- Disciplined\n- Eloquent \n- Flexible"]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get more comfortable. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "At Company ABC we do what we can to take environmentally friendly actions. Are you familiar with the U.S Green Building Council and their purpose?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are familiar with environmental standards and efforts when it comes to the building products and construction industry. \n\nIf you are familiar with the U.S Green Building Council: \"The U.S Green Building Council is a member-based community of businesses and professionals who are active in green based building initiatives. They are a great resource for the construction community in ways that we can be more environmentally conscious during our projects.\"", "\"The U.S Green Building Council is a member-based community of businesses and professionals who are active in green based building initiatives. They are a great resource for the construction community in ways that we can be more environmentally conscious during our projects.\"", "If you are not familiar with the U.S Green Building Council: \"I have not had direct exposure with the U.S Green Building Council; however, it sounds as though they would be a great resource for those wishing to take greener initiatives in the building products and construction industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "What is LEED and how do you think it affects our day to day operations at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) is a must-know topic for anyone in the building products and construction industry. Take a moment to explain your understanding of LEED briefly and be sure to ask about the level of involvement Company ABC has with LEED initiatives.", "\"From my understanding, LEED is the largest green building certification program in the world. It has significantly changed the way companies build. I would think that the LEED, and other environmental building initiatives, would greatly affect your day to day operations with Company ABC. Do you find that these initiatives significantly affect your business?\"", "\"Because I am new to this industry, I am likely not as familiar with LEED as you are. I have conducted some research and believe that LEED in an environmental based building initiative. Could you elaborate for me? I would love to learn more.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "At Company ABC we have many strong competitors. In your opinion, what sets us apart from the others?", "answers": ["It is essential to research Company ABC before your interview so that you can fully understand why they are the top choice for your particular job search. Go to the Company ABC website and check out any recent news, press releases, announcements, or awards/accolades they have recently achieved. Keep your answer brief and decisive.", "\"What sets Company ABC apart from the others in your industry is the fact that you have won so many awards for environmental innovation as well as customer service. I would be proud to work here over any of your competitors. Company ABC is doing a great job!\"", "\"Through my research on Company ABC I have found that you have the best online reviews and some very loyal customers. Company ABC has the strongest reviews on Google and Yelp, which is great to see!\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "At Company ABC our customers, vendors, manufacturers, and wholesalers are all important to us. How do you keep a healthy balance to ensure that everyone is happy?", "answers": ["Balancing the needs of multiple parties can be a challenge. Discuss with the interviewer how you ensure that everyone involved in a project is feeling happy and listened to. Provide some information in regards to how your current position requires the same of you.", "\"In my current position I am tasked with anticipating the needs of our customers based on last years' trends. This approach means ensuring that our vendors keep us stocked - and at the price that our customers have come to expect. I find that the best way to keep a balance of satisfaction is by always being honest. When all parties maintain a healthy and realistic expectation, projects seem to run smoother.\"", "\"It certainly can be a juggling act to keep customers, vendors, manufacturers, and wholesalers happy...all at the same time! I know that situations come up and you cannot make all parties happy at the same time. With that said, my relationship with my customers always come first. I am kind and patient with our manufacturers and wholesalers because we need them too, but I am always clear with them on our project needs and deadlines.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "At Company ABC we treat each of our customers, and their projects, as a priority. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["Your attitude towards customer service will reveal to the interviewer a lot about your work personality. What can Company ABC expect from you when it comes to your interactions with their customers?", "\"My customer service philosophy is that knowledge is power. The more I can inform my customers about the products available to them, the more educated their decisions are. This approach results in a better-finished product where everyone wins.\"", "\"My philosophy is to treat every single customer the same, regardless of the size of their project. Everyone should feel heard,  and receive great service at all times.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Every step counts for a successful project so at Company ABC we prefer to hire those who come highly trained. Do you have any post-secondary education related to project management, or construction?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you come equipped with the knowledge level appropriate for this position. If you do not have a post-secondary education, then be sure to make a statement regarding your ability to perform the tasks required of you for this role with Company ABC.  \n\nIf you have project management or construction related post-secondary education: \"I am PMP Certified from the Project Management Institute. In addition to this certification, I also possess a degree in Business Management from Strayer University. These education related successes have helped me to learn more about multitasking during complex projects, anticipate building product needs, and put safety at the forefront of a project.\"", "\"I am PMP Certified from the Project Management Institute. In addition to this certification, I also possess a degree in Business Management from Strayer University. These education related successes have helped me to learn more about multitasking during complex projects, anticipate building product needs, and put safety at the forefront of a project.\"", "If you do not have project management or construction related post-secondary education: \"My formal education, related to building products and construction is limited; however, I bring 15 solid years' experience in the industry. My knowledge level is strong, and I am confident in my ability to surpass your expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "At Company ABC we use robust internal inventory management and project management systems. Do you have experience in SAP, Auto CAD, or Project Insight?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have the technical skills and abilities required of you in this role. You may not have experience in the specific programs and software systems used at Company ABC but perhaps you have a general understanding of how they work. Briefly discuss the programs you have used in your recent positions and rate your level of expertise with each.", "\"I have used Program ABC for Inventory Management which I understand is similar to Project Insight. I am an intermediate user in SAP and also have about ten years' experience in Auto CAD. I am confident in my ability to learn your programs quickly as I consider myself to be a robust technical user.\"", "\"I am well versed in SAP, Auto CAD and Project Insight. I used SAP for approximately 12 years when I was with Company A. With Company B; I used Project Insight for about two years. I am more advanced with AutoCAD, having taken some college coursework in this program.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Where did you come across our job posting?", "answers": ["The employer would like to know what methods you are using in your search and which job ad methods are working for them. You can expand your answer to include any other exposure you have had to Company ABC.", "\"I initially saw your job posting on LinkedIn, however; I have been exposed to your organization many times before through your radio commercials and advertisements on Facebook.\"", "\"I have had my eye on your organization for some time now and keep an auto-alert on Indeed for new job postings with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Looking at your resume, you've had a number of job changes, what would make me think that you will stay with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Most hiring managers will consider more than two jobs in the past five years to be frequent movement. Take some time to explain your career progression to the interviewer. Be sure to avoid speaking poorly of any of your previous employers. This question is not the time to ramble on about how your former company did you wrong. The only appropriate answer is a short and sweet one.", "\"Leaving Company X was due to a merger, and my role was eliminated. Company Y was a seasonal role, and I am now looking for a new position because my contract with Company Z is complete this March.\"", "\"I have had a couple of positions in the past that I took too quickly, and should have researched further. I am much more selective in my job search this time. I appreciate what Company ABC stands for, and I see a long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Tell me about a time at work when your integrity was challenged. How did you handle it?", "answers": ["Have you ever faced a time, in the workplace, where you were put to the test when it came to your integrity? Perhaps a co-worker has asked you to lie, or you were tempted to be dishonest on your time sheet when the boss was away. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you overcame the temptation to be dishonest.", "\"Last year our manager went away on vacation for three weeks. Some of my co-workers wanted to falsify our time sheets to reflect overtime hours that we did not work. I disagreed and was able to convince them that it was a bad idea and certainly not worth being fired over.\"", "\"I worked with a Project Manager some time ago who always wanted to cut corners to save time and cost. It challenged my integrity because I value putting out great work. I ended up leaving that position because I was unhappy with the low standard of work expected of me.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "What kind of people do you enjoy working with?", "answers": ["Culture fit is a significant factor when looking for a new position. Talk to the interviewer about the types of personalities that you best work with. Be sure to remain positive and avoid using this as an opportunity to speak poorly of previous colleagues.", "\"I best enjoy working with individuals who are driven, positive, energetic, and take accountability for their work. I do have the ability to work with a large variety of individuals; however, these are the ideal traits I would see in future colleagues.\"", "\"I work well with a wide variety of personalities; however, I work best with those who are honest and hard working. Working alongside like-minded people, versus those you are at odds with, always makes a project run smoother.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky one as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself a nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"Honesty is fundamental to me, and I was raised to be a truthful person at all times. For this reason, I would rate myself as a 10/10 for honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "When given an important assignment, how do you approach handling it?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who will approach an assignment head-on, or do you need to research and plan first? Do you jump in and get it all done immediately or do you balance it with other assignments? Talk to the interviewer about how you approach essential assignments at work.", "\"When my supervisor gives me an important assignment or task I am sure to assess the depth of the project then take a look at my schedule to see how I can appropriately balance it with my other work. I do not procrastinate because then it's easy to forget to fit them in.\"", "\"When given an important project, I will first review all of the details while gathering any questions that come to my mind. From there, I will research answers to the questions and then approach my supervisor with any questions that remain unanswered. At that point, I will dive into the project. My method is very calculated, and I have never missed a deadline.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "What feedback did you receive at your last job?", "answers": ["Every manager has a different approach to giving feedback. Some prefer to save it for the performance review while others dish it out on the regular. Your response to feedback is much more important than the input itself. Even if it was negative, if you can take it as constructive criticism, you can improve yourself and your skills.", "\"My manager told me that I was spending too much time on the details of a project. I realized that I could be such a perfectionist that I lose track of time and hyper-focus on things that aren't that important. I'm learning to prioritize the steps I need to take and the tasks that need completion when working on a bigger project.\"", "\"Every performance review, in my previous position, was very positive. I like to achieve greatness in everything that I do, and my manager appreciated that.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "How would you describe your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Being a clear communicator, in written form, is a crucial skill to master. Have you taken any courses in communication and writing? Are you confident in your written communication skills? Talk to the interviewer about your written communication abilities and support your answer with a brief example or story.", "\"I would describe my written communication skills as very strong and would rate myself as a 9/10. I have always had a penchant for writing and have taken university courses related to communication, writing, and journalism.\"", "\"Although my written communication skills are strong, I am still working on improving them because I do find verbal communication to be a more natural skill. One way that I am improving my written communication skills is by spending more time crafting emails and other forms of written communication to my staff and clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "How do you handle conflict in the workplace?", "answers": ["The tension between coworkers can be draining, mainly if you work in a high-stress work environment. When asked a question about dealing with conflict or overcoming a challenge, think of an example first. Having a concrete situation to draw from will help you to think through the steps you take to deal with conflict.", "\"My coworker and I had a misunderstanding about the schedule. We both got frustrated, so I took a step back and asked if we could talk about it when we were both calm; so the tension didn't escalate. The next day I pulled him aside and asked if we could talk. We both shared our sides of the story and realized it was just a miscommunication.\"", "\"Conflict in the workplace is sometimes unavoidable when you have so many personalities working together. When faced with conflict, I will remind myself to keep a level head, hear all sides of the story whenever possible, and remove myself from any situation that becomes heated.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you had to make a decision without all the information you needed.", "answers": ["Everyone has difficult decisions they have made in their career where little information was present. Focus on a choice you made in your job where you wanted more time to gather information, but instead, had to make a fast decision. Remember to pick an example that results in a positive outcome.", "\"I was an executive for a Home Renovations DIY blog, and after a google search algorithm update, our traffic declined 30% overnight. I quickly researched what the change was, how websites were affected and made the decision to hire more writers immediately. The decision created better content on the blog, and our traffic gained 50% by the end of the year.\"", "\"I had a customer who was unhappy with the performance of one of my project managers. I had heard this complaint about the PM before so it was not completely out of the blue, but I did want to get his side of the story before taking disciplinary action. He would not return my calls, so I decided to take disciplinary action without his side of the story, going primarily by his work history and previous actions.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "When were you able to resolve a problem within work?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are fundamental skills to possess. Display to the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace.", "\"In my most recent position we had a consistent problem with employees showing up late for their shifts or calling in sick at the very last moment. Rather than the typical documenting and reprimanding style that management usually takes, I decided to track the results of an accountability reward system. For 180 days, my employees received a reward for coming to work 10 minutes early. Also, for every month with zero sick days, a bonus was added. In the end, we awarded those with perfect attendance a $600 bonus. The bonus' cost us less money, in the end than the cost of lowered productivity due to absent employees. The program was a success, and upper management chose to keep it implemented for another six months. We will re-assess in December, but it seems to be working very well.\"", "\"We have a problem with being short on labor hands quite often, due to the high employee turnover in our industry. I solved this issue by engaging a placement agency that specializes in temporary labor staffing. Whenever we are short on labor hands, they have a roster of individuals we can hire last minute and for the short term. Surprisingly, before I started with this company, they had never utilized this resource. Everyone is quite pleased with how this has worked out so far.\""]}, {"topic": "Building+Products+and+Construction+Materials", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently earning less than the average professional in my line of expertise. In my next position, I would like to make a base salary in the $80-$84K range. What salary range are you offering at Company ABC?"]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Do you have experience when it comes to appropriate shipping and handling of chemicals and other potentially toxic products?", "answers": ["Proper shipping and handling of chemicals are of utmost importance to the success of most chemical companies. Talk to the interviewer about your experience in transportation of chemicals.", "\"I have experience in shipping and handling of chemicals by road transportation and air. I have been formally trained in Hazardous Material Transportation Act (HMTA) and have a spotless record when it comes to transportation safety.\"", "\"Because I am new to the chemicals industry, I do not have specific experience when it comes to the appropriate shipping and handling of chemicals. I am here to learn, and will do so, enthusiastically.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "We are asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in this industry, I have worked near it my entire career, and I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "If you were hired today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would first work on obtaining all of the industry certifications and training that Company ABC needs me to complete. This will enable me to work independently, and gain traction in my new role.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "At Company ABC we try to hire individuals dedicated to their own professional development. If you could take any related coursework, what would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are willing to expand your industry knowledge through further professional development and coursework. Talk to the interviewer about any additional education you may have been considering and assure them you are interested in the professional development options they may be offering.", "\"I am very dedicated to my professional development and am happy to attend any coursework that you may recommend. If I could choose any related coursework, I would choose further education on leadership and team engagement.\"", "\"GLP and Quality Assurance are topics of interest to me. I appreciate that Company ABC emphasizes the professional development of their employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "When have you used an inventive method to stretch company resources beyond the normal level?", "answers": ["Every company likes to hire those who are respectful of company resources and finances. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been able to stretch company resources.", "\"I have recently implemented a schedule that allows for ride-sharing rewards which have cut down on our company's fuel expense by $9000 per month. I am quite proud of this initiative because it is not only financially responsible but also environmentally friendly.\"", "\"This is a practice I often utilize to maximize company resources and optimize value to the clients. I recycle a lot of company materials to make the most of our resources. I also do this with people regarding cross training and sharing understanding across departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "How would your co-workers describe your attention to detail?", "answers": ["It is always best to support your reply with a real-life example. Talk to the interviewer about your level of attentiveness when it comes to details on the job.", "\"My co-workers would describe my attention to detail as very strong. I can very easily point out spelling discrepancies in communication and will notice the small things. I think big-picture as well but have always had a knack for details.\"", "\"Overall, my attention to detail is strong. My current supervisor asked me a few months ago to improve the detail in my documentation, so I have been avidly working to improve in that area.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "In your chemicals career have you ever experienced a chemical related emergency such as a spill or injured co-worker due to exposure?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are well equipped when it comes to handling an emergency situation in the workplace. Do you have any training when it comes to chemical safety, chemical spills, etc.?", "\"I have a spotless safety record in my work history, so I have not experienced a chemical related emergency at this point in my career. I have great amounts of training in emergency situations, as well as WHMIS and OSHA certified.\"", "\"I experienced a chemical spill in one of our warehouse facilities last year. A forklift operator accidentally pierced a container. In my current position, we have rigorous spill protocols. We followed those protocols and were able to avoid any injury and toxic exposure.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture here at Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is critical that you spend time researching Company ABC and it's workplace culture before your interview. What did you find impressive about their culture? How do you see yourself fitting in?", "\"I am impressed with the culture at Company ABC. There are many great reviews online, and I have spoken with one of your current employees whom I know. I like that you have strong performance incentives in place for your employees and offer a safe and comfortable workplace for all. Your zero tolerance employee discrimination program is inspiring as well.\"", "\"I have conducted a great deal of research on Company ABC and the workplace culture that you discuss on your website. From my understanding, you boast a workplace culture of tolerance, diversity, and transparency.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "At Company ABC we ask for active contribution from our employees. Tell me about a contribution you made to the last team you worked on.", "answers": ["It is essential to show the interviewer that you are a team player. Talk about a time that you were recently expected to achieve a goal in a team setting. How did you go above and beyond to ensure that your contribution was felt?", "\"Last month our company asked upper management to complete a full inventory audit. There were 4 of us in total and so we broke the audit requirements into shifts. These shifts had to take place when the warehouse closed. In the end, there was one additional shift that nobody wanted to take. I volunteered myself to do that shift to show my dedication to my job and my co-workers. The gesture was appreciated, and the audit completed on time.\"", "\"My most notable contribution was my ability to analyze and predict market trends, and then create a successful marketing strategy.  Before me, there was no one with a true marketing background on the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see progress and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to Company ABC, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"I define success by what we achieve as a team. The project, as a whole, needs to deliver on expectations before I consider the job a success.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "At Company ABC we take every step possible to be a leader in our industry. In your opinion, who are our competitors and what sets us apart from them?", "answers": ["It is vital to research the company before your interview. You should learn who the company's competitors are. Discuss your findings with the interviewer and be sure to speak highly of Company ABC while answering this question.", "\"I have researched Company ABC and see that you truly are an industry leader in the chemicals arena. From my research, I believe what sets you apart is your incredible customer service and dedication to safety. Also, it appears that your employee benefits package is one of the best in the industry.\"", "\"From my research, I understand that your biggest competitors are companies X, Y, and Z. Your branding is what sets Company ABC apart from its competitors. A good brand equals trust and with your strong branding comes a great deal of public trust in your product.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "At Company ABC we put safety first when it comes to our employees and the handling of our products. How important is safety to you?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are as concerned about safety as they are. In which ways do you put safety first? Talk about the importance of safety in the workplace.", "\"One of the reasons why Company ABC stands out to me as a potential employer, is your dedication to workplace safety. I feel that safety should be the number one consideration in this industry. It determines employee engagement, company profitability, and ensures a strong industry reputation.\"", "\"Safety is the most important factor in the workplace, in my opinion. When working with chemicals, especially! I have attended a variety of safety training including Decontamination, Responding to Chemical Emergencies, and CPR / First Aid.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "In the chemical industry there is always potential for dangerous spills and exposure to toxic chemicals. Are you willing to work in an industry that poses this type of risk?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can professionally handle an emergency situation. Have you ever encountered a chemical spill or other emergency situation in the workplace? Talk to the interviewer about how you reacted. If you have not experienced this, discuss how you feel you would respond in this type of situation.", "\"I have experienced a couple of different scenarios surrounding chemical spills. When situations like this occur, I am sure to rely on my training when it comes to chemical related emergencies. I feel well equipped to handle a situation like this in a professional manner.\"", "\"I am well trained for these scenarios and fully understand the risks that come with working for Company ABC, and the chemicals industry in general.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Tell me about any safety related training you have received when it comes to the handling of chemicals and other toxic substances.", "answers": ["Give the interviewer a concise overview of your formal and on the job training related to chemical safety and proper handling. You can be brief when answering this question but be sure to give the interviewer confidence in your abilities.", "\"I am certified in chemical safety and currently hold a valid WHMIS certificate as well as a valid OSHA certificate. I am confident in the training I have received and understand the importance of caution and safety while working around chemicals and potentially toxic substances.\"", "\"As I am new to this industry, I have not taken any safety-related training related to chemicals. If you could suggest some specific training, I would be happy to get a head start while you make your hiring decision.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "In your opinion, what do you think has been the biggest change in the chemicals industry in the past 10 years?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the most significant changes you have seen in the chemicals industry. Keep your answer positive by focusing on the changes that have been good for the industry.", "\"I feel that the biggest change in the chemicals industry has been the amendment to the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). These amendments have greatly assisted with the consistency of communication and expectations in the chemicals industry.\"", "\"The chemicals industry is always faced with new challenges as policy changes come all the time. The biggest challenge that stands out to me is increasing capital costs that cause knee-jerk reactions such as cost-cutting measurements that end up being poor decisions further down the road.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "At Company ABC we try to hire people who want to stay with us long term. What are your long term career plans and how do we fit into your plans?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your longer-term career plans and how they fit into the career path being offered by Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that you are looking for a longer term fit.", "\"I am looking for a long-term career path which is one of the reasons I applied to work with Company ABC. I like that you have opportunities for advancement within your team and that you offer professional development coursework. If hired, I would seek to work my way into a leadership role with Company ABC.\"", "\"I plan to have a long-term career in the chemicals industry. My education is geared to this as I recently graduated from Chemical Engineering. I would be happy to enjoy a long-term career with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "What accomplishment do you believe was the most difficult for you to achieve?", "answers": ["Being able to face a challenge or stressful situation, and still gain some accomplishment, in the end, is very satisfying. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to come out on top despite being faced with an obstacle.", "\"In my career, so far, I feel that the most difficult accomplishment for me to achieve were the three back-to-back promotions in my current company. Because promotions are granted based on results, I had to put in a lot of overtime hours, and hustle, to get there.\"", "\"My proudest accomplishment to date was completing my Degree in Chemical Engineering while also being a single parent to two young boys. The level of dedication that I had to give to both my family and my education was very tough. I couldn't be prouder of myself for never giving up.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "When have you faced an unexpecting difficulty?", "answers": ["How you face unexpected difficulty can say a lot about your character. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have encountered an unexpected challenge. How did you handle the situation?", "\"The biggest unexpected difficulty that I have faced was my unexpected lay off during the last recession. I had to adapt to a new economy and search deeply for other skills and opportunities. I was able to earn enough to avoid financial strain and am quite proud of my ability to be versatile when required.\"", "\"I faced unexpected difficulty last year when Company X swiftly acquired our company. With nobody aware of the change, it was emotional chaos in our offices for some time. I chose to remain calm, avoid jumping to assumptions and continued doing my job as usual. This approach helped me to get through the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "When have you had to shift your priorities in response to sudden changes?", "answers": ["Have you been asked to change your priorities on a dime? How do you react to this kind of shift in priorities? Assure the interviewer that you can respond professionally when it comes to sudden changes.", "\"In my current role, our schedule is changed on a regular basis and always at short notice. I have been able to adapt very well to these frequent, sudden changes.\"", "\"In my current position, I have to respond to sudden change on a regular basis. This situation always occurs when my clients need changes to their projects, and it often happens right before the deadline. I am accustomed to situations like this and welcome the challenge!\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Budget is important for Company ABC. What was the greatest cost-cutting measurement you accomplished at your previous employer?", "answers": ["If you are in a management type of role, you will often be asked to keep your eyes open for cost-saving opportunities. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of understanding the importance of this practice and give a strong example of a time when you have done so.", "\"I have been able to present cost-cutting suggestions many times to my previous employer. The one that I feel had the biggest impact was when I suggested additional warehouse staff. We had three various shifts and still an average of 100 hours of overtime per week. I presented to my employer that we hire one more warehouse employee for each shift, keeping the hours to just 120 regular vs. 100 hours of overtime pay (@1.5x) This recommendation saved the company $31,000 per year. They implemented this change across 15 warehouses the following year, amounting to nearly half a million dollars in savings per year.\"", "\"My biggest cost saving measure comes regarding productivity on my team. I was able to craft email copy that I saved as a template and could send out a dozen emails at a time, all personalized, to targeted audiences to set appointments. I was able to do this multiple times per day, while also making calls, and doubled my productivity. I shared this tactic with the team and saw it implemented across the board.  While I was not in a managerial role, I was able to roughly double productivity, thereby preventing the need for new hires and surpassing our financial targets for KPIs and financial metrics.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"I have attended multiple interviews as of late, and when I walk into the offices of Company ABC, it already feels like home. I believe that my advancement goals will be respected here and that I can flourish in this position. Your willingness to mentor and encourage professional development is another factor that makes this role with Company ABC the right one for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "We value a harmonious culture within Company ABC. How do you handle conflict in the workplace?", "answers": ["The tension between coworkers can be draining, mainly if you work in a high-stress work environment. When asked a question about dealing with conflict or overcoming a challenge, think of an example first. Having a concrete situation to draw from will help you to think through the steps you take to deal with conflict.", "\"My coworker and I had a misunderstanding about the schedule. We both got frustrated, so I took a step back and asked if we could talk about it when we are both calm, so the tension didn't escalate. The next day I pulled him aside and asked if we could talk. We both shared our sides of the story and realized it was just a miscommunication.\"", "\"I do not enjoy conflict in the workplace; however, it does happen from time to time. When conflict does arise, I am sure to nip it in the bud right away. When moments of miscommunication fester or swept under the rug, they become bigger than they need to be.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is crucial, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive at Company ABC.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized, and the vibe is positive. I value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"Work situations that excite and motivate me to include fun internal contests, camaraderie among the staff, and the ability to participate as a creative thinker.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Tell me about a time when you took the initiative to improve work related procedures.", "answers": ["Have you ever taken the opportunity to present your employer with potential change? Talk to the hiring manager about a time when you took the initiative in the workplace.", "\"I was able to present and implement one specific change in the office this past year. It was a recycling program that I felt was very important, even for our smaller office. We had significantly less waste after my initiative was implemented and I enjoyed seeing others take pride in helping our environment.\"", "\"I always have my eye out for opportunities to improve procedures. I have taken courses in organizational behavior and effective management, so I often have ideas, big and small. Recently, I helped to implement a new customer management software. This implementation has greatly improved the time frame between customer touch points.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include capabilities that will potentially benefit Company ABC.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "Some skills that you could mention are: \n\n- Written Communication \n- Verbal Communication \n- A particular software program \n- Collaboration \n- Initiative \n- Ability to work autonomously"]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision-making requirements in this possible position. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in tech support, you faced problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you might have to know how to negotiate and make decisions on prices and benefits you can give your customers. \n\nYou may have faced decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision-making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"I regularly made decisions regarding pricing and discounts for customers. I had a standard set of criteria that I created, and I tried to let that guide me for consistency.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Company ABC has seasons of peak times where the workload is high.  How do you handle a larger than average workload?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can handle the workload required of you in this position and that you will not become overwhelmed if/when workloads unexpectedly increase. When workloads increase, stress levels do too. How do you react?", "\"When I have a large workload on my plate, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a lower priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I can focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\"", "Here are some suggestions on how to handle a large workload:\n\n- List your tasks and prioritize them\n- Think of which tasks add to the company's bottom line, and start there (Closest to the money!)\n- Exhale. Relax for a minute and collect yourself\n- Organize your tasks by which ones you can complete independently and which ones you need help with\n- Take sufficient breaks, so you do not exhaust yourself \n- Communicate your struggles with your leadership or team"]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"In my most recent position, I was earning below the average for my area of expertise. I am targeting a base salary of $92-$98K in my next position.\""]}, {"topic": "Chemicals", "question": "Tell me a little bit about yourself.", "answers": ["Many interviewers will start off with this question, which could throw you off a bit. You've done all of this research on the company but have you prepared to talk about yourself?  \n\nThe interviewer is looking for relevant information to the position for which you applied. Respond by mentioning your education, how many years of experience you have in your field, and be sure give some details about your most current position. Conclude your response with a statement about what you are looking for in a job at this time.", "\"I started my sales career in a large corporate setting, and there I received a promotion within only a few months. I decided that I wanted to stretch my wings and made the leap to a startup. I have had continued success there and am in my preferred sales territory; however, I feel that I may have outgrown the position. Right now there isn't an opportunity for a managerial position here, so I'm looking at outside opportunities, such as this one with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["Performance incentives can be very motivating. Talk to the interviewer about your feelings regarding performance incentives.", "\"I feel that performance incentives are a great idea. They keep an employee motivated to do a great job and ensure that they are on top of their KPI's. The majority of people are very enthused about being rewarded for their successes.\"", "\"Although performance incentives are not required to motivate me, I do enjoy the healthy competition involved with them.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I would take the same direction! I truly love what I do and would never change the course of my career. It's so fulfilling.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"This job is right for me at this time in my career because I am prepared and ready to take on a management position. I feel that Company ABC would nurture my desire for growth and prepare me by providing the appropriate training.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with experience in manufacturing. Do you have any exposure to a manufacturing, production, or mill environment?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer any experience that you have in a manufacturing or textile mill environment. If you do not have experience in manufacturing and production, be sure to let the interviewer know that you can quickly learn the industry.", "\"I have eight years' experience in a clothing manufacturing setting with Company X and Company Y. I am well versed in production and know I would succeed at Company ABC, if given the opportunity.\"", "\"Although I do not have direct experience in a manufacturing plant or production environment, I am very familiar with the inner workings of manufacturing. Rest assured I can learn quickly and am ready to apply my existing knowledge to this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Do you prefer doing work on a routine day-to-day basis or do you prefer mixing up your routine occasionally?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who prefers to know what the routine will be, or do you thrive on the challenge and excitement of unpredictability? Talk to the interviewer about your preference and be sure to show that you can be useful in both situations.", "\"I prefer working in a more predictable environment because I can be more effective in my tasks. With that said, I can certainly work in an unpredictable environment from time to time.\"", "\"I am more accustomed to working in an unpredictable environment, so I do work quite well and efficiently in those types of situations. I can certainly learn to work well on a more routine basis if needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What was your greatest cost-cutting measurement you accomplished at your previous employer?", "answers": ["If you are in a management type of role, you will often be asked to keep your eyes open for cost-saving opportunities. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of understanding the importance of this practice and give a strong example of a time when you have done so.", "\"I have been able to present cost-cutting suggestions many times to my previous employer. The one that I feel had the biggest impact was when I suggested additional warehouse staff. We had three various shifts and still an average of 100 hours of overtime per week. I presented to my employer that we hire one more warehouse employee for each shift, keeping the hours to just 120 regular vs. 100 hours of overtime pay (@1.5x) This recommendation saved the company $31,000 per year. They implemented this change across 15 warehouses the following year, amounting to nearly half a million dollars in savings per year.\"", "\"My biggest cost saving measure comes regarding productivity on my team. I was able to craft email copy that I saved as a template and could send out a dozen emails at a time, all personalized, to targeted audiences to set appointments. I was able to do this multiple times per day, while also making calls, and doubled my productivity. I shared this tactic with the team, and it was implemented across the board.  While I was not in a managerial role, I was able to roughly double productivity, thereby preventing the need for new hires and surpassing our financial targets for KPIs and financial metrics.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "At Company ABC we like to be a step ahead of our competitors at all times. How do you stay on top of industry trends?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you ensure you stay on top of trends. It is vital to Company ABC that they remain ahead of their competitors and every team member will have a hand in making that happen.", "\"I subscribe to a few blogs and online magazines related to the industry. Every morning I take about 20 minutes to update myself on the current happenings in the clothing and textile industry. I also have Google Alerts set so that I can have real-time industry updates.\"", "\"I am always reading! The clothing and textile industry is fast-changing, and I feel that to keep up, you have to be plugged in. This includes reading magazines, blogs, books, and more.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire individuals with formal education in business or design. Do you have any post-secondary education? How do you feel it will help you in this role?", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your formal post-secondary education and discuss how that education has prepared you for this role.", "\"I have a Bachelors Degree in Art and Design. This education has prepared me in many ways including helping me to understand the cycle of certain elements of fashion including the use of color and patterns. I also attended business classes and some sales training.\"", "\"Even though I do not have a completed degree, my business knowledge is strong. I believe in continuous professional development and have taken multiple courses throughout my career including business administration, human resource management, and social media marketing.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "I would like to know more about your knowledge of importing and exporting.  Are you familiar with NAFTA and the regulations that come along with this agreement?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are not a liability when it comes to costly decisions surrounding importing and exporting a product. Are you familiar with NAFTA and the most critical parts of the agreement?", "\"I have studied and worked with NAFTA regulations for the past eight years. I would consider myself an expert when it comes to the rules and regulations surrounding free trade.\"", "\"I have a small amount of exposure to NAFTA but will commit myself to learning the ins and outs so that I am ready to apply my knowledge before starting this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "In your opinion, what do you feel has been the biggest advancement in the clothing and textiles industry over the past 10 years?", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you are capable of keeping on top of the latest industry advances and that you have a keen and genuine interest in the industry.", "\"I feel that the biggest advancement in the clothing and textiles industry has been surrounding advancements in communication and technology. We can stay connected with anyone around the world in real time which has significantly increased productivity and profitability in the textiles industry.\"", "\"In my opinion, the biggest advancement in the clothing and textiles industry has been the fact that people have become more aware of best practices in the industry. It's become more ethical as of late when it comes to production, the purchasing of materials, and focus on the environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Tell me about the types of products you are most experienced with.", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the products and materials with which you have experience. If your experience does not align correctly with the offerings at Company ABC, be sure to address that. Avoid any objections from the hiring manager when it comes to offering you the role.", "\"I understand that Company ABC works primarily with X, Y, and Z. I have four years experience with these types of products. In addition to this experience, I also bring valuable knowledge in A, B, and C  - totaling approximately 15 years.\"", "\"I bring 15 years total experience in the clothing and textiles industry. The majority of what I have done would include products such as A, B, and C. Although this isn't the same space as Company ABC I am confident that my skills are transferable.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Who do you feel are the biggest competitors of Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is essential that you have researched Company ABC before your interview. After getting to know the company better, which industry players do you feel are the strongest? When you answer this question, you will want to end with a statement that solidifies your confidence in Company ABC and their ability to beat out their competitors.", "\"I have researched the competitive space and feel that the more significant competitors of Company ABC are A, B, and C. Even though they are competitors, I feel that Company ABC brings the strongest reputation in customer service and product quality.\"", "\"Every organization has competitors, and if I were to guess, I would say that your biggest competitors are companies X, Y, and Z. With that said, I think that Company ABC does an incredible job of standing out in the crowd. Your branding is impeccable, and you have a great reputation for how you treat your employees and clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What do you know about sales and market research in the clothing and textiles industry?", "answers": ["Having a full understanding of market research methods is an excellent asset to any resume. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of understanding the needs of the industry and how to maximize profitability.", "\"I took courses in market research during my time in University. I have a strong understanding of market research and how it relates directly to sales in the clothing and textiles industry. The market has seen a 134% increase in sales since the launch of social media marketing which is incredibly impressive. This way is just one exciting example of how I have seen the market research benefit the textiles industry.\"", "\"Although I am new to the clothing and textiles industry, I do have a lot of sales and market research experience. I obtained my BA in Marketing and Design from the University of Montreal and since then have been working as a Marketing Associate for Company XYZ. I am ready to shape my career in the clothing and textiles industry so that I can further utilize the design aspect of my formal education.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "When it comes to clothing and textiles, where do you gain your inspiration from?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your inspiration when it comes to the clothing and textile industry. What inspires you to stay in this industry and what do you enjoy most about it?", "\"When it comes to clothing and textiles, I gain my inspiration from everyday events and a variety of environments. I truly feel that inspiration can be found anywhere if you are creative enough. That is one of the things I enjoy most about the industry - there are no restrictions to the inspiration!\"", "\"I follow a few great influencers in the clothing industry including Shini Park, Sophia Amoruso, and Tom Ford. They all have a unique style and a great story. I find the most inspiration from those who aren't afraid to take a risk.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["It is imperative to research the workplace environment before you attend your interview. What does Company ABC offer that you don't currently receive from your employer? Talk to the interviewer about what is attracting you to their organization.", "\"I have spent some time researching Company ABC and am very impressed with what I have come across so far. I see that you put a lot of effort into giving back to the community and other charitable organizations. One stand-out factor for me is your competitive benefits and employee packages.\"", "\"I have a friend who has worked with Company ABC for the past three years, and she raves about the culture here. From my understanding, I believe that you value growth, professional development, and creativity.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "The clothing and textiles industry is very competitive. In which ways do you feel you will give Company ABC a competitive edge?", "answers": ["When you are applying to a competitive industry, you need to be prepared to assure the hiring manager that you will be an active part of their winning team. In which ways will you bring a competitive edge to Company ABC, if hired?", "\"I enjoy the competitive environment that comes with working in the clothing and textile industry. If hired, I will bring a keen eye and strong attention to market trends.\"", "\"I feel that I will give Company ABC a competitive edge because of my eight years experience in the industry as well as the formal education that I bring in social media marketing and fashion design. Also, I have traveled a great deal and bring a perspective from a variety of cultures.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "If you were hired today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate with Company ABC.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If I were hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact at Company ABC very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would first work on obtaining all of the industry certifications and training that you need to be completed. This approach will enable me to work independently, and gain traction in my new role.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "When have you faced an unexpected difficulty?", "answers": ["How you face unexpected difficulty can say a lot about your character. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have encountered an unexpected challenge. How did you handle the situation?", "\"The biggest unexpected difficulty that I have faced was my unexpected lay off during the last recession. I had to adapt to a new economy and search deeply for other skills and opportunities. I was able to earn enough to avoid financial strain and am quite proud of my ability to be versatile when required.\"", "\"I faced unexpected difficulty last year when Company X swiftly acquired our company. With nobody aware of the change, it was emotional chaos in our offices for some time. I chose to remain calm, avoid jumping to assumptions and continued doing my job as usual. This approach helped me to get through the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Describe a situation when you have motivated yourself to complete an assignment or task that you did not want to do.", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you will still get the job done even when you aren't excited about the task at hand. Think about a time when there was a work-related task that you did not want to do. Perhaps the dreaded file room needed to be purged of outdated files to make room for new files. Tell the interviewer what your task was, and explain why you were not excited about it. Be sure to tell the interviewer that even though you were not enthusiastic about the work, you made it happen promptly knowing that it would help the organization as a whole.", "\"I like to set rewards for myself when there are undesirable tasks at hand. For instance, a large part of what I do is review all of the resumes that come into our job portal on a weekly basis. Sometimes there will be up to 200 resumes to review. They all begin to look the same after awhile, so I have set a goal to look at 20 at a time, give myself a quick break, then return to the task.\"", "\"As the new employee at my first job, I was delegated the task of scanning in old contracts and related documents. It was overwhelming and not exactly the learning experience I was going for, but I knew I had to complete it and accepted it as my responsibility. As a team member, I maintained a positive attitude about my contribution and formulated a plan to tackle this project. I divided the work into the most important to least important stacks and set out to scan all the documents.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Company ABC likes to hire calculated risk-takers. What is the riskiest decision you have made? What was the situation? What happened?", "answers": ["As a successful professional, you know to calculate risk in your industry. Tell the interviewer about a work-related risk you have taken and what the outcome was. \n\nStart with an overview of the decision you needed to make, and explain why the situation was risky. Describe who the situation affected, as well as the possible outcomes. Complete your answer by sharing how the decision paid off, or by mentioning any recognition you received for your success.", "\"The riskiest decision I ever made was to leave the office supplies industry to move into manufacturing, as a consultant. The risk meant that if I were unsuccessful, I would be looking for a new job in a really slow economy. The pay off would be that I would finally be in a sector that I was truly interested in. I made a great career for myself for the next eight years, which has brought me here today - with an exceptional opportunity in front of me.\"", "\"One of the riskiest decisions I made was to leave the corporate world and join a textiles startup with an innovative idea.  The company was seeking to provide a product/service that would pioneer a new industry.  We worked hard and started to launch and create a new space in the textiles marketplace. We failed a lot along the way, but we learned to fail fast, and it made us all better professionals.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Think about a difficult boss, professor or other person. What made him or her difficult? How did you successfully interact with this person?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you work well with most personalities even though you recognize there are some folks out there who are quite difficult to please. \n\nThink about that one person at work who is seen as hard to please. Perhaps there is someone at work who tries to intimidate others. Talk to the interviewer about what made this person challenging and what their relationship was with you. Avoid speaking poorly of anyone and be sure to end your response on a positive note.", "\"I once worked at a locally owned shop where the owner was very demanding. When the owner would walk into the store, employees would announce over their headset system that the owner was in the building, so that everyone could be prepared for his entrance into their department.  The owner had great intentions; however, his people skills were a little rough. I could see that he meant well, and I recognized that he wanted to do a lot of good things. When we interacted, I always took his feedback with the understanding that he didn't mean things as harshly as he might say them.\"", "\"I struggled most with a newly appointed Director in my most recent position.  I did not feel that she was knowledgeable enough to hold the title successfully; however, she was my boss, and for me to be successful, I needed to have a better rapport with her. I chose to invite her on a business trip for an out of town client so that she could see our process in action. We bonded as humans, mothers, and sales executives. She learned a lot about the company and industry, and I learned a lot about her strongest skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Do you consider yourself a patient person? How do you increase your patience level in challenging situations?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you consider yourself a patient individual. Impatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in coworkers, so it is essential that you can showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations. \n\nPatience is indeed a virtue but can be challenging to maintain when it seems that situations continue to push your buttons. Show the interviewer that you possess the ability to keep your cool in challenging conditions.", "\"I do consider myself a patient person. I would rate myself an 8 /10 for patience because I certainly have room to grow, but I do have a very long fuse. If I need a boost of patience in a challenging situation, I will take a step away, count to 10 and then return to the situation. I recently read a book, 'The Power of Patience' by M.J. Ryan which also gave me some excellent new methods for coping with stress.\"", "\"I was once working with a group that could not quite get along and it tested my patience a bit because it prevented us from staying on track and focusing on the goals.  I went above and beyond in helping the group get along by scheduling lunches as a team and helping to mediate situations that needed it.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Company ABC likes to hire go-getters. Have you requested extra responsibilities in any of your previous roles?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have a desire to learn, grow, and try on new challenges! No hiring manager wants to hire the complacent employee so show them you are willing to see opportunity when it arises!", "\"In my current role I asked my boss if I could take over the social media marketing. We are a small company, and my supervisor was struggling with it. Being a millennial, I am always on social media, and I understand what types of posts gain attention. After taking over the task, I grew our Instagram following from just 400 to 2000 in 2 months! I am always game for taking on new tasks, especially when they are in my wheelhouse.\"", "Your willingness to take on additional tasks, with a positive attitude, gives the interviewer all the more reason to want to get to know you better. Hiring managers are looking for people who will be proactive and help to carry the team. \n\nHere are some ways you can gain extra responsibilities in the workplace:\n\n- Talking to your boss about your career goals and having a conversation about new tasks that may help to get you there. \n- Offering to take work off of a colleague's plate, if they seem stressed.\n- Studying hard to become an SME (Subject Matter Expert) in software or another topic that your boss would find useful.\n- Just jumping in and taking on a new responsibility!"]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "At Company ABC we are looking for reliable employees. How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I cannot recall the exact number, but I think it was around three days total. All absences were excused and with notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"In my most recent position, I was earning below the market average for my position and education level. In my next role, I am targeting a base salary of $89-94K.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "We are asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in this industry, I have worked near it my entire career, and I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "If you had $50,000 to build your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["If money was no object, what kind of business would you start? The interviewer will be able to learn something new and unique about you through this question. Avoid answers that would include building a business that competes with the hiring company.", "\"If I had $50,000 to build my own business I would open up a community center in my neighborhood that offered inexpensive childcare, cooking classes, and other life skills programs. I am passionate about volunteering and see a strong need in those particular areas.\"", "\"I have a keen passion for design so I would say that $50,000 would be spent on a new industrial sewing machine, and some great fabrics! I would love to have my small clothing line someday that focus' on environmental sustainability and social responsibility.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What unique qualities about yourself would you bring to our company?", "answers": ["There are some things that your resume cannot do. Showing off your fabulous personality is one of them, for instance! Talk to the interviewer about some of your unique qualities and be sure to tie these qualities into how they will benefit the company, should they hire you.", "\"I have a unique ability to strike up a conversation and build rapport with nearly anyone. This ability is a great help when it comes to customer service and sales. My up-selling percentages are always very high.\"", "\"I am unique in a variety of ways! My dedication and tenure are rare. I was in my most recent position for eight years and previous to that; 6 years. Also, I speak multiple languages. I am fluent in English, French, and Spanish.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "Looking at your resume, you've had a number of job changes, what would make me think that you will stay with our company?", "answers": ["Most hiring managers will consider more than two jobs in the past five years to be frequent movement. Take some time to explain your career progression to the interviewer. Be sure to avoid speaking poorly of any of your previous employers. This question is not the time to ramble on about how your former company did you wrong. The only appropriate answer is a short and sweet one.", "\"Leaving Company X was due to a merger, and my role was eliminated. Company Y was a seasonal role, and I am now looking for a new position because my contract with Company Z is complete this March.\"", "\"I have been looking for some time now, for a long-term fit. A place that I can call home! I feel that Company ABC will be the long-term fit that I have been craving.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "We are looking for team players at Company ABC. What role do you usually take in team projects?", "answers": ["The interviewer truly wants to understand the role that you naturally take on, when put into a team-based environment. If you tend to take the lead, let the interviewer know this, but avoid sounding overbearing. If you usually like to generate new ideas and allow someone else to execute them, share your creative side but express that you prefer for others to take the lead.", "\"I am usually the 'ideas person' in team projects. In my current position, I am not the strongest salesperson, but I am highly creative. This means that, in most projects, I am great at creating a plan of action but am most comfortable passing the final client-facing tasks to our more extroverted personnel.\"", "\"I like to take the lead on team projects. I am very vocal and organized which makes me a natural leader. At the same time, I enjoy drawing the leader out in others by asking them for their ideas and encouraging full participation.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What qualities do you feel a successful manager should have?", "answers": ["Some great qualities of a manager are:\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\n- Strong relationship building skills\n- Taking ownership for the team's errors and mistakes\n- Excelling at motivating others\n- Providing kudos/recognition to your team\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\n- Having a vision for the future\n\nThese are just a few to get started!  With which qualities do you most identify?", "\"I feel that a successful manager will have the ability to motivate their team as a whole, while recognizing their individual achievements. A vision for the future is really important as well. Without a long-range vision, it's difficult to know where to take your team next.\""]}, {"topic": "Clothing%2C+Textiles+and+Accessories", "question": "What is your personal mission statement?", "answers": ["Not everyone has a mission statement or personal mantra just off the cuff. In business, especially when entering leadership, this is an important question to ponder. Do you have a quote that inspires you or a saying that you grew up with that resonates with you?", "\"My mantra is that 'people who shine from within do not need the spotlight.' I feel that it is essential to be a humble leader and I take this mission statement very seriously. I want my team to be in the spotlight rather than being the kind of leader that takes credit for good work.\"", "\"My mission is to give my best 100% of the time. It's important to me that I have a great reputation in this industry through hard work and a positive attitude.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation? How did you handle this ethical dilemma?", "answers": ["Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you can handle these types of difficulties with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie, I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"Yes, I have been asked to lie on the job before. In a previous role, our inventory count was off. My co-worker wanted to go home, and he suggested that I lie about our count. I refused to lie, and we stayed late. I would always choose honesty over lying, any day.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if the are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"I am actively seeking a new opportunity; however, will be choosy in my final decision. I am very excited about this opportunity with Company ABC and look forward to next steps in the interview process.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for us?", "answers": ["Bragging about yourself in an interview can be tough to do, but this is your time to shine! Which characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a stand-out candidate? Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given special accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer.", "\"I am the best candidate for you because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current company. In addition to these successes, I have excellent cold calling skills which I will put to work immediately after being hired by your company.\"", "\"I believe I'm the best candidate because of my decade of experience at your competitor in anything from entry-level sales to managing various departments. I have experience in the specific department in question as an assistant manager, and I look forward to building on those skills with Company ABC.  I know I can make an immediate and long-term impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "We have a variety of career paths available at Company ABC. What kind of growth would you like to see here?", "answers": ["Interviewing, hiring, and onboarding is an expensive and time-consuming process for Company ABC. Since there are so many career opportunities and specialties available to you at Company ABC, be prepared to discuss how you would like to see your career grow. This shows the interviewer that you are engaged in this process and interested in becoming a long-term fixture at Company ABC.", "\"I was looking around on your websites job board as well as your LinkedIn jobs to see what types of growth opportunities were available with Company ABC. One role that stood out to me was the QA Department Manager position. It seemed that this could be a very natural step in my career once I have grown with you for a couple of years. I'd like to learn more about what I can do to prepare myself for a role like that.\"", "\"I am looking to join a company that will allow me to continue my education and grow into a leadership position over time.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Tell me about a project you completed recently that was ahead of schedule.", "answers": ["Is it essential for you to meet and exceed work-related deadlines? Assure the interviewer that you can remain focused on a project and accomplish your goals ahead of schedule.", "\"In my current position I am expected to cold call 100 customers per week. Most of our associates will break this down into 20 per day, five days per week. What has attributed greatly to my success in this role is that I call 50 customers each day for the first two days and then have time to make additional calls throughout the week. This generally equals a 25% surplus of cold calls to my portfolio. I am always ahead of target by going over and above that cold calling schedule.\"", "\"The majority of my projects are completed ahead of schedule. I believe that my clients deserve the best of me and I will work overtime when I can to deliver faster than expected.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I am satisfied with my career progression.  Everyone, including me, hits roadblocks or setbacks, but I have been able to push through them and stay on track.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Considering your background is in an industry different from ours, what skills and characteristics do you have that qualify you for this position in the electrical equipment industry?", "answers": ["There are many ways that you can be a fit for a position, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit another employer, despite the industry. These are your transferable skills, and they can include sales abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities.", "\"Although my background is not in your precise industry, I have worked with many clients who have been in your industry. I bring excellent transferable skills that qualify me for this position. These skills include my advanced abilities in Excel, my outstanding cold-calling abilities as well as my proven background in team leadership.\"", "\"I bring a lot of transferable skills to this position and industry.  My talents and skills revolve around helping people and making companies profitable. Customer service, problem-solving, and analytical skills can cross any industry, and I am a pro at all three.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I think I missed ten days, counting vacation time. Of those, five were for my vacation.  For three days, I was excused under a doctor's note.  The other two absences were pre-approved family days.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "What is your personal mission statement?", "answers": ["Not everyone has a mission statement or personal mantra just off the cuff. In business, especially when entering leadership, this is an important question to ponder. Do you have a quote that inspires you or a saying that you grew up with that resonates with you?", "\"My mantra is that 'people who shine from within do not need the spotlight.' I feel that it is incredibly important to be a humble leader and I take this mission statement very seriously. I want my team to be in the spotlight rather than being the kind of leader that takes credit for good work.\"", "\"My mission is to give my best 100% of the time. It's important to me that I have a great reputation in this industry through hard work and a positive attitude.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC our equipment standards are highly regulated. Do you consider yourself meticulous and detail-oriented?", "answers": ["Equipment standards should be high so be sure to address with the interviewer how important the small details are to you. The interviewer would like to be assured that you have a keen interest in the details. Give an example of a time when your attention to detail saved the company from an expensive error or a safety issue.", "\"After researching Company ABC I could see that your organization has a keen eye for the details. I, too, am a detail-oriented person. Two months ago, during our quarterly audit, I noticed a couple of discrepancies that ended up saving my company $45,000. My supervisor was very thankful for my keen eye and ended up making me the inventory lead for future audits.\"", "\"I do consider myself meticulous and detail-oriented. In this industry, attention to detail is a matter of safety. Also, mistakes are expensive. In my last performance review, my supervisor commended my efforts when it comes to precision in my work.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "We put the safety of our employees first at Company ABC which includes extensive safety training for our new hires. Walk me through your current safety training and safety related education.", "answers": ["Your safety-related training may or may not be listed on your resume. Either way, be prepared to discuss your training in greater detail. This includes any coursework, certifications, or informal on-the-job learning. Perhaps you have also led a safety course or trained new employees on safety protocols. \n\nIf you have particular safety tickets or certifications, you can bring those with you to the interview. There is a good chance that Company ABC will want a scan for your employee file. \n\nBe sure to acknowledge the safety standards at Company ABC as well.", "\"I am formally trained in Fall Arrest, WHMIS as well as Confined Space. I have been an ESTS trainer as well. In addition to this experience, I have many hours of on-site safety training in my previous roles. I brought my current documents with me if you would like to make a copy. I am confident that my level of effort when it comes to safety will meet your high expectations at Company ABC.\"", "\"Because I  am newer to the industry, I have not completed a lot of related training. I am CPR, and First Aid certified. Could you tell me which safety training you would like to see me complete? I would be happy to get a head start.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we offer a range of equipment and services. How familiar are you with our business?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC before you go into your interview so that you have a firm understanding of the range of equipment and services offered, as well as their business strategy. \n\nYou should have a strong idea of the company vision as well as their most recent wins. All of this information can be found on the Company ABC website by reviewing their 'news' or 'about us' sections. Google search for any recent blog posts, press releases, etc.", "\"I have read up on Company ABC quite extensively since being invited to interview with you. From my understanding, the bulk of your business comes from A, and B. I read the press release posted on your blog last month and see that you are opening a new location in XYZ. Congratulations on that growth! I am very excited to join an organization as successful and progressive as yours.\"", "\"I've had an eye on Company ABC for quite some time and have worked for one of your competitors in the past. I am familiar with your product line and do know that your best selling equipment includes A, and B. Is there anything in particular that you would like to share with me about Company ABC, today?\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "The electrical equipment industry is vast. What area do you consider your specialty and why will your specialty help us at Company ABC?", "answers": ["If you have a particular strength in your skills toolbox, then this is a great time to highlight those. It can be tough to brag about your skills, but the way you answer this question will likely be what sets you apart from the other candidates interviewing for this position. \n\nIf Company ABC highlights any particular skills in their job posting/job description, it is a great idea to draw on those keywords as a reference when you are answering this question.", "\"I have approximately 12 years experience in the electrical equipment industry with 6 of those years being on equipment nearly identical to what you have in place at Company ABC. In your job posting you requested candidates with exposure to A, B, and C. In my current role I am considered the subject matter expert with A, and C. My understanding of B can be classified as an intermediate level. If hired, my training time would be minimal compared to someone with less comprehensive experience within A, B, and C.\"", "\"I consider my specialty to be in A, and B. With that said, I do have a wide range of knowledge in other electrical equipment and services. Is there a particular specialty that you are hoping to highlight in your next hire?\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "We have a few local competitors at Company ABC. In your opinion, what makes us stand out from the rest?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC before your interview and be sure to learn about their business landscape. Who are their competitors? What are customers saying online? Check out some favorite review sites to get an idea of what the public is saying about Company ABC vs. their local competitors. Keep your answer positive and complimentary.", "\"After researching Company ABC online, I found that you stand out from the many ways that you give back to your community. On the Company ABC website, as well as third-party review sites, people are talking about the charitable contributions and generosity coming from Company ABC. This makes your company a big stand-out to me because I am serious about working for an organization that is aware of their social impact.\"", "\"In the electrical equipment industry, it is rare to have a fun and energetic vibe on social media. I think that Company ABC stands out from the competition by being present on those platforms.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Do you have any post-secondary education directly related to what we do here at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Most job postings and job descriptions will outline the ideal educational background for which the company is looking.\n\nIf you do not have the specific educational background requested of Company ABC - do not fret! Since you are being interviewed, they naturally place value in your experience which, for them, outweighs your educational background. Highlight some of your career wins and how those are directly related to your potential success with Company ABC.", "\"The majority of my knowledge has come from on-the-job training, and other workplace provided courses and workshops such as A, B, and C.  Last year I was recognized as the #1 employee for productivity and participation. My industry knowledge has also gained me a leadership role in my current company where I am able to train a lot of new college graduates who are just starting out in the industry.\"", "\"The majority of my post-secondary education is focused on mechanics and electronic engineering. Is this the educational background that you feel is the best fit for this role with Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of emphasis on product knowledge. List the equipment you have the most exposure to and strongest knowledge of.", "answers": ["Your equipment knowledge is listed on your resume, but the interviewer would like to see you go into further detail on your level of expertise. Be sure to highlight your knowledge with any equipment used at Company ABC if you are privy to that information.", "\"Every piece of equipment that I have solid knowledge in is listed on my resume; however, I would say that my strongest skills are with A, B, and C. I understand that you use all of this equipment at Company ABC as well. This is great news since it means that there will be little downtime in training me on the majority of your equipment and tools.\"", "\"I have had experience with a multitude of equipment. To ensure that I am focusing my answer on the equipment experience you are most interested in, could you share with me the strongest areas of interest when it comes to equipment knowledge?\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we like to hire those who are natural leaders. When have you taken on a leadership task in the workplace without being asked?", "answers": ["Most companies want to know that they are hiring someone who can grow with their company, show initiative, and be an excellent example to others. Talk to the interviewer about a time, big or small, when you took the initiative to go above your regular duties and set an example of leadership for your co-workers.", "\"Last month when our supervisor was out unexpectedly we had a couple of temporary employees not show up for their assignment. We were short-handed, and volumes were high. I decided to step up for the team, like a leader would do, and offered to work a double shift so that last-minute overtime was not expected of my team members. I enjoy setting an example of teamwork while maintaining a positive mindset.\"", "\"I naturally take on a leader and mentor-ship type of role with my co-workers. In one instance, I had a new coworker who was having some troubles fitting in. I took her out for lunch and talked to her a bit about the workplace culture and semantics surrounding the various departments. I wanted her to stay and enjoy her employment with us, so I took the responsibility of ensuring she was settling in well. I believe there are always opportunities for leadership - you have to keep your eyes open!\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we strive to be the best in our industry. What do you think we could improve on?", "answers": ["A great organization will always be open to improvement and innovation. The interviewer would like to know if you have suggestions for improvement; however, they are indeed not asking you to reinvent their wheel. The worst thing you could do here is speak negatively about the company without any constructive feedback or recommended solution. If you do have a suggestion, keep it light-hearted and be sure to end your remark with a positive comment.", "\"I think that you are doing an impressive job at Company ABC and I look forward to coming to work with you. If I could make any suggestion, I would suggest more updates on the company blog. I believe your vendors and distributors are interested in what Company ABC has to say and where you are taking the company in the future!\"", "\"It is difficult for me to comment on where Company ABC could improve without having worked here. From a consumer perspective, I would suggest that additional forms of advertising could not hurt. I see many commercials and ads for your competitors and fewer for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "When have you had to adapt your workload due to increasing demand from your supervisors?", "answers": ["Workloads will increase and decrease as the market demands. How do you adapt to these changes?", "\"In my current position, my workload changes depending on the team and their needs. I can adapt to those needs quickly and effectively. Just last week I had two team members who were sick, and my workload increased significantly. I worked overtime and met my deadlines.\"", "\"My workload changes by the minute.  I keep a to-do list every day and push unfinished items to the next.  Then, the next day I come into 150 emails and have to completely re-prioritize yesterday's to-do leftovers with today's emergencies.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to analyze information and make a recommendation.", "answers": ["With this question, the interviewer is looking at your thought process and your level of logic. Begin by discussing the problem you were trying to solve. Next, consider the data set you used to analyze the problem. Lastly, talk about the recommendation you gave, and the positive outcome of your recommendation.", "\"I recently wrapped up an organizational effectiveness survey with our team.  I analyzed the results by leader, location, and department then came up with recommendations of how the company can improve trouble areas.\"", "\"Once it appeared that productivity was slowing down, so I was asked to look into it.  I pulled data from a variety of sources and poured through it, from order types, changeovers, employee turnover, absenteeism, etc.  I identified all of the changes from the previous quarter to the current and made several recommendations.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "How would you describe your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Being a clear communicator, in written form, is a crucial skill to master. Have you taken any courses in communication and writing? Are you confident in your written communication skills? Talk to the interviewer about your written communication abilities and support your answer with a brief example or story.", "\"I would describe my written communication skills as very strong and would rate myself as a 9/10. I have always had a penchant for writing and have taken university courses related to communication, writing, and journalism.\"", "\"My written communication skills are solid. I often utilize written communications as a follow up to verbal communications. They provide a great resource for associates to go back to and reference, plus might answer any questions that come up along the way.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "How did your job change over the years you worked there?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know more about your career progression. Additional responsibilities, promotions, and changes in your job title all indicate that you were competent and successful in your role. \n\nTake some time to highlight any successes for the interviewer. This question gives you an opportunity to go more in-depth about how your role has evolved. If nothing has changed much over the past couple of years in your position, focus on what you have learned. Are you better at managing teams now that you have gone from supervising one to five people? Are you exceptionally good with problem-solving now that you've learned to troubleshoot related technical problems? Talk about how the changes in your job have taught you new skills and helped you develop the ones you already have.", "\"When I initially started my job four years ago I was a junior level associate. Today, I am responsible for leading a team of 8 junior associates. My role does not look the same at all, and I am thankful for the growth opportunity that my current company has offered me. In addition to the change in leadership responsibilities, I have also enjoyed two major promotions. I attribute this to hard work and dedication.\"", "\"Change was a constant in my most recent role. I worked with a rapidly growing organization.  In the beginning, I was the one doing a lot of the work where over the years, I was leading a team to accomplish those goals. You could say I grew professionally as much as the business did!\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I love to explore my creative side.  I practice photography for fun and dabble in the arts.  As an avid reader, I also explore writing.  Cooking is also an art for me, and I try to incorporate creativity into the fun meals I prepare for family and friends.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get more comfortable. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "What kind of people do you enjoy working with?", "answers": ["Culture fit is a significant factor when looking for a new position. Talk to the interviewer about the types of personalities that you best work with. Be sure to remain positive and avoid using this as an opportunity to speak poorly of previous colleagues.", "\"I best enjoy working with individuals who are driven, positive, energetic, and take accountability for their work. I do have the ability to work with a large variety of individuals; however, these are the ideal traits I would see in future colleagues.\"", "\"I enjoy working with people who are driven to succeed, but not at the expense of others.  I want to be around people who pick each other up and keep the team moving.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "What do you see as the most difficult task in being a manager?", "answers": ["Being in a management role is always a significant challenge. Share with the interviewer what you feel is the most challenging part of being a manager, and why. Also, discuss what you are currently doing to make this task less stressful in the future.", "\"As a manager, the most difficult task for me is to delegate the work evenly. You will always have team members who are absolute rockstars, then some who are a bit less enthusiastic or are lower producers. I have to remind myself to distribute the work and responsibilities evenly despite my natural inclination to give more work to the high performers. I am currently working with my underperforming team members to prepare them for a larger workload.\"", "\"Working with people and being responsible for business operations are two of my favorite things. It can be easy to get caught up in these important aspects and forget to carve out time regularly to develop - myself and my team. I have set reminders and triggers to help me stay focused on doing this in the background.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "When change occurs in the workplace, it can create new problems. Do you see these as an inconvenience or as opportunities to learn?", "answers": ["When a change occurs in the workplace, often problems arise due to new procedures being implemented, or unforeseen kinks needing to be worked out. Do you approach these problems positively or do you resist the change? Talk to the interviewer about how you can adapt to the inevitable issues that come with a change in the workplace.", "\"I fully understand that when a change occurs in the workplace, some new problems may arise because of it. I embrace workplace change because it often gives me the opportunity to learn a new skill or even teach a colleague a new skill.\"", "\"I like to approach every day and situation as an opportunity to learn and grow, so even though it's uncomfortable, I like to think that there's something valuable to take away from the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career. Talk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job.", "\"Salary is important to me because I know that I am skilled and well educated. With that said, I do look at the full picture which includes factors such as benefits, work-life balance, perks, and company culture.\"", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job.  Compensation is a driving component of that along with company mission, culture, benefits, and location.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Tell me about a time you handled an incredibly difficult client. How did you come to a resolution with this person?", "answers": ["Remaining level-headed and staying professional is what the interviewer is looking for in your example. Give an example of how your excellent communication skills allowed you to handle a difficult client. If you haven\u2019t had an experience with a problematic client, explain how you would handle the situation.", "\"In my current position I am faced with challenging clients on a daily basis. I seem to always come to a good resolution by using my gift of gab. I ask questions and actively listen. A recent example would be when a very unhappy customer called in, wanting to speak with the manager. Our manager was away, and I  was the next best person for her to speak with. By listening and accepting responsibility for the company's actions, I was able to calm her down. We came to a solution that was great for everyone, and I was sure to follow up with her actively.\"", "\"I had a client call saying that we delivered a defective piece of merchandise valued at over $30k. Understandably, he was livid. He was threatening to not only stop doing business with us but also make sure no one else in his company or his contacts in the industry would give us the time of day. This was one of my best customers, previously, so it was a rough phone call.  I immediately took responsibility and asked pointed questions to try to get to the root of what was defective about the item, and assured him over and over that we would make it right. I went into a conference room, bringing the COO and Director of Ops with me, and we all assured him how we valued his business and would be sure to make it right. Not only that, we would put steps in place to ensure this type of thing did not slip through QA again. Ultimately, we had a satisfied customer who went on to grow in business volume and praised how we remedied the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "Tell me about one of the most rewarding experiences you had working on a team.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you feel accomplished through teamwork. Talk about a time when you felt fulfilled through a team setting or project collaboration. An example may be a time when you worked on a  team project in University, a recent work collaboration, or possibly an extracurricular experience such as coaching a little league team. Discuss the positive results of the teamwork and how you attained a positive outcome as a group.", "\"The most rewarding teamwork experience that I have had was in my last year of university. We were assigned a project in teams of 4 which accounted for quite a large part of our grade. I believe everyone pulled more than their weight because so much was at stake. Teamwork is very rewarding when everyone has something to win, or lose.\"", "\"My current team is made up of 4 incredibly talented mechanics and three knowledgeable sales experts. I find every day to be incredibly rewarding because my team is like a well-oiled machine. I can count on them, and they can count on me.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "If you were the successful candidate, how much notice would you require to give your current employer?", "answers": ["Every employer wants to know that you would give the professional cutesy of proper notice to your current employer. Keep your answer short and sweet, avoiding going down any rabbit hole surrounding your notice period.", "\"I would like to give my current employer the professional courtesy of 2 weeks' notice. I can begin immediately after that.\"", "If you have a vacation booked, this is the perfect time to discuss that as well. \"I am on vacation until December 27th and can begin immediately after that.\""]}, {"topic": "Electrical+Equipment", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Pick a weakness that is not a core skill for this position. You can be candid in your answer; recognizing that you aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve.  Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently I am at a beginner to intermediate level; however, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. We will see how stellar my skills are after that course!\"", "\"This is super cliche, but it's also true. I am not good at delegating to others. When I become submerged in a project, I don't like to give away any of the control. While this can be good, it can also definitely inhibit the outcome of the project and my growth as a team player and individual. \nI am currently working on this, as I know it is a deficit.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Some of our competitors use social media to promote their brand. How do you feel about the social media presence at Company ABC? Do you feel this type of marketing is relevant to our industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer is wondering how deep you have researched Company ABC before your interview. Your answer will also reveal how tech savvy you are. Be sure to check out popular social media platforms and take note of the company's online presence. If you have a suggestion for the company, be sure to keep it lighthearted and complete your comment with a compliment on their current efforts. Share your thoughts on the use of social media in this industry and how you think it could help boost industry exposure.", "\"I think that the use of social media in this industry is unconventional, but a great idea. It's just one way to stand out from your competitors. I like that you have a few YouTube videos showing some of the Company ABC equipment in action. I think this idea could be expanded to Instagram and even Snapchat by showing the general public some unique features of the equipment at Company ABC. Social media can be a great teaching tool!\"", "\"I believe that social media marketing is relevant to any industry, at this time. Social proof is an important factor in consumer decision making, even in the heavy machinery industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "We put a lot of effort into ensuring Company ABC uses only the best parts and materials available. What do you know about our cutting edge machinery?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants assurance that you have conducted substantial research on Company ABC before attending the interview. The more you know, the more it shows that you are excited about the position and engaged in this process. You should be able to find everything that you need from the company website. Feel free to ask the interviewer if there is anything they would like to add. The more information they can divulge to you, the better armed you are for the next interview!", "\"I have researched Company ABC and your machinery a great deal. I like that your best machinery is manufactured in the USA. This fact means high quality and more local employment opportunities. I also learned A, B, and C (use specific examples). Is there anything else you would like to share with me about your machinery?\"", "\"Your cutting edge machinery is absolutely world class, and it offers you the ability to deliver much faster to your clients. I look forward to learning more about your machinery and processes, as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creativity. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible, I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Tell me about a time that you have helped a co-worker accomplish an important goal.", "answers": ["Being goal-oriented and determined is essential. What do you do, outside of your own goals, to ensure that everyone on your team is successful? Assure the interviewer that you are always willing to keep the team, or company as a whole, in mind.", "\"As a Sales Manager my team is only as successful as the lowest producing employee. It is imperative that my entire team is motivated, engaged, and on point with their KPI's. Last month I hired a new employee who was struggling significantly with sales. I sat him down and realized that he didn't understand the product. We spent a few hours together over that next week learning the product. In the end, his sales increased by 64%, and he was significantly more confident. It helped the team morale as well.\"", "\" I help my co-workers accomplish essential goals on a daily basis. I believe that this is the most critical part of teamwork - being willing to help others achieve their goals. Just las"]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Our reputation is very important to us. In which ways do you feel Company ABC stands out from the crowd?", "answers": ["It is imperative that you research Company ABC and their business landscape before your interview. Take a good look at their competitors and make a note of any awards or recognition that Company ABC may have received. Be sure to compliment them on what they are doing right!", "\"Through some online research I see that your reviews are much stronger than those of your competitors. Your equipment is superior, and your reputation for prompt client service is unmatched. I am very excited to work for a company with such a great industry reputation.\"", "\"When I think of the industry leader, I think of Company ABC. I believe that this is due to your strong reputation for honesty in the industry but also the fact that your branding is consistent. This company has created an honest dialogue with its customers, and they have come to trust your expertise.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How do you prioritize multiple projects when they all seem equally important?", "answers": ["In answering this question, show the interviewer that you have a system in place that helps you to think through what needs to happen, and when. The better you can prioritize, the more productive you will be, making you an asset to Company ABC!", "\"I love to keep running lists of everything that I need to do, big or small. Mostly because I love crossing things off of the to-do list, but also because it helps me keep track of everything. Lately, I've started utilizing a free project management software that I use to make those lists, categorize the tasks, and mark them as a priority.\"", "Prioritizing is a skill that requires practice. There are many approaches you can take. Here are some suggestions:\n\n1) Make a list. By thinking through and writing down each item that needs to be completed, you can see it on paper.\n2) Mark what is urgent or important. Take into account deadlines and meetings.\n3) Order each task based on effort and estimated value. Considering due dates and how long it will take to do each item (also considering how much time you have)."]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How do you explain complicated concepts to those who may not understand?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of explaining complex ideas without being condescending to your co-workers or talking over their heads. Give the interviewer an example of how you break down information to make it more easily digestible for the average person. \n\nThink of a presentation about a complex topic, as a proposal to solve a challenging problem. The solution may seem obvious to you, but everyone else in the room is scratching heads trying to figure out what you're talking about. When you can define key terms and phrases to make them more relevant to your audience, you have skill! Not everyone can do this. \n\nPrepare an example that demonstrates your communication skills and your ability to convey complex information in easy to understand terms.", "\"I find that when there is a complicated concept to teach, visual aids are always the way to go. Did you know that 65% of people are visual learners and that presentations with visual components are 43% more persuasive? I took a course on creating effective info-graphics and will often implement those in my presentations.\"", "\"Keep it simple silly!  If you cannot explain a concept simply, then you do not understand it well enough.  I recently rolled out a complex compensation plan with many anomalies.  I took the approach to share a broad overview and provide detail for reference. I often try to make analogies or share complex information in the form of a story.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "What part of this career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (IE: a bus driver should not find driving to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"The part of my career that brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on my teams part. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that my clients are assisted properly.\"", "\"I probably bring myself the most stress because of my drive and desire for perfection in the workplace.  I manage this by focusing my energy on productive activities that are good for my career, and the business.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "What are your career aspirations beyond this job?", "answers": ["Everyone has some dream or aspirations on where their career could go. When you think about the future, what comes to mind? Openly share with the interviewer where you'd like to see your job take you. Be sure to include how you feel this particular company would fit in with those specific aspirations.", "\"I have some pretty lofty career aspirations, and after researching your organization and learning more about this position, I feel that this role fits with my future aspirations. I would love to see myself promoted based on my hard work and results, eventually managing my branch, then become a regional director.\"", "\"I want to get into a company that I can stay with an grow long term.  While change is good, I like the comforts of having something familiar or regular around me. I aspire to grow into a leadership position and teach newcomers the ins and outs of the business.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "At Company ABC we measure productivity in a variety of ways. In your opinion, what are the most important performance metrics for this position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can identify the most critical parts of this role and understand how those relate to the overall success of Company ABC. Reading through their job description, you should be able to pull out the key responsibilities in this role. These key responsibilities are connected directly to the success of the organization. Discuss what you think the key performance metrics are and how you plan to meet them.", "\"From reading the job description and overall responsibilities of the role, I believe that the most important metrics to measure in this role are A, B, and C. In my current position I am measured by these specific metrics. I am a consistent performer in my current role and plan to bring the same enthusiasm to this position.\"", "\"I believe the key metrics for this position are inventory turnover, receiving efficiency, and cost of carrying inventory. Is this correct? I have ten years' experience managing these exact metrics and am confident in my ability to improve these KPI's in the first 30 days after starting with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "At Company ABC we work with some of the largest scale machinery in our industry. Tell me about the types of machinery you are most experienced with.", "answers": ["The types of machinery that you are experienced with may be listed on your resume. Either way, the interviewer would like to see you be more specific about your exposure to certain types of machinery. Make sure that you understand which types of machinery Company ABC works with. If you are not clear on that answer, it is okay to ask the interviewer for further details.", "\"The machinery I am most experienced with would be A, B, and C. I am an expert in these types of machinery which I understand you work with at Company ABC. Are there any other types of machinery you are looking for experience in?\"", "\"I have experience in a variety of machinery, and from my research, I understand that your company primarily uses machinery A, B, and C. Is this correct? I do bring about five years' experience in each.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "When have you effectively delegated tasks to your employees?", "answers": ["Delegating tasks to employees is always a requirement when you are in a management type of role. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to delegate.", "\"I find that to delegate tasks effectively you first need to understand each employee's strengths. I will always delegate to someone's strength so that they will organically know how to complete the task. Delegation eliminates a lot of resistance and promotes effective and productive work.\"", "\"To date, my role hasn't included a whole lot of delegation of my tasks to others. However, I have been responsible for taking the workload and dictating who will take on which task, such as region, customer focus, or manufacturer. In either case, I believe it is important to recognize that everyone has their strengths and weaknesses. I believe it's important to identify those, provide opportunities for growth, and thereby prepare them for their next role.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to tell the interviewer a few things about yourself. You can begin with your recent education, family life, volunteer work, or talk about your travels. Bring up anything that is interesting and highlights your ability to be a responsible, reliable, and bright individual.", "\"A bit about me - I love to travel, read, and conduct research. I am a recent grad from Columbia University and have spent the past 12 months traveling the world. It was the best experience that I could have given myself as I was able to learn so much from seeing how the rest of the world lives. I returned to the US just last month and have been actively looking for work the past couple of weeks. I am looking forward to getting into the routine of a career again.\"", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit. On the professional side, I recently graduated with my heavy machinery operators' license and am a journeyman mechanic.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How would you describe your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Being a clear communicator, in written form, is a vital skill to master. Have you taken any courses in communication and writing? Are you confident in your written communication skills? Talk to the interviewer about your written communication abilities and support your answer with a brief example or story.", "\"I would describe my written communication skills as very strong and would rate myself as a 9/10. I have always had a penchant for writing and have taken university courses related to communication, writing, and journalism.\"", "\"My written communication skills are powerful. I often utilize written communications as a follow up to verbal communications. They provide a great resource for associates to go back to, and reference, plus they might answer any questions that come up along the way.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "We have a variety of shifts at Company ABC. Do you have any restrictions on your availability?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know what kind of flexibility you can offer Company ABC when it comes to your work schedule. If you have any restrictions on your calendar, this is an excellent time to address them. If there is a specific shift that you are looking for, be upfront about your preference.", "\"I am more than willing to be a flexible employee for Company ABC. Currently, I do not have many restrictions on my availability except for Tuesday evenings.\"", "\"For my family and personal life, I do prefer to work the afternoon shift. This allows me to get my kids to school and then my husband picks them up after school. We try to stagger our hours to accommodate our children's needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How will the knowledge gained from your most recent position help you succeed in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the skills and knowledge you have gained in your current role and how those skills will help you to succeed in this position with Company ABC. It's a great idea to start with the core skills mentioned in the Company ABC job description and talk about how you currently exercise those skills.", "\"I see that you are looking for a candidate with strong leadership skills. Currently, I lead a team of 15 technicians with great results. Since taking a leadership role with my current company, our productivity has increased by 23%, and our employee turnover has decreased by 46%. I am excited to apply my leadership successes to this role with Company ABC\"", "\"In my current position, I am exposed to a lot of decision making when it comes to internal process. I believe that this has greatly increased my ability to make sound decisions based on profitability, customer satisfaction, and employee retention. I look forward to lending this knowledge to my role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "The health and safety of our employees is top priority at Company ABC. How would you react if your supervisor asked you to perform a task that you were not comfortable with?", "answers": ["This situational question will give the interviewer a firm idea of the morale you bring to the workplace. Safety is so important to Company ABC, so be sure to acknowledge that you understand the importance of workplace safety. Discuss how you would handle being asked to do something that makes you uncomfortable.", "\"If I were asked to perform a task that I was not comfortable with, I would have a sincere discussion with my supervisor about why I was not comfortable. I believe that open communication is a key part of safety. Under no circumstance would I perform a task I did not feel comfortable doing.\"", "\"I do not waiver when it comes to safety in the workplace. If I were asked to perform a task that I was not comfortable with, I would discuss it immediately with the person who initiated the request. If things needed to be escalated to upper management, I would not hesitate to do so. Processes and policy are there for a reason, and there are no excuses for cutting corners in the workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Our motto at Company ABC is to work smarter, not harder. If you had a workplace motto, what would it be?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to have some insight into your workplace values and personal morale. Before your interview, conduct some research on Company ABC via their website, job postings, and online reviews. Take note of any common keywords they use when describing their workplace culture and company goals. Try to incorporate those keywords when you answer this question. This strategy will help the interviewer to see that you are an excellent fit for the position!", "\"I fully agree with your company motto. Efficiency and productivity go hand in hand. If I had a workplace motto, it would be a quote by Jim Rohn: 'Don't wish it were easier. Wish you were better.' I am a big advocate for continued education and constant achievement.\"", "\"My workplace and personal motto are one in the same; 'Happiness is an attitude.' I believe that we choose how we feel in a day, for the most part. Thus, I choose to be happy, confident, and enthusiastic.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Do you have experience working in a unionized environment? What are your thoughts on union based roles?", "answers": ["While Company ABC may have some or all, unionized employees, it's best to answer this question as diplomatic as possible. Avoid complaining and try to focus on the perks that might come from working in a unionized environment.", "\"Personally, I have not worked in a unionized environment; however, I have heard that unions are a great way to ensure continuity in the workplace. From what I understand, they offer security to employees which is always a bonus.\"", "\"I currently work in a unionized environment. There are some kinks to be worked out, but overall, I am certainly open to working in another unionized environment. If executed properly, unions can be great!\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "What was the biggest change you have had to deal with in your career?", "answers": ["You will likely face change in your career from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you can adapt to substantial changes in a professional manner.", "\"The biggest change that I have faced in my career so far would be when my previous company went through a major merger. We had to adapt to new processes and management which was quite challenging. In the end, it worked out well for the company, in a financial perspective, so the changes were well worth the challenges we faced initially.\"", "\"The biggest change I have dealt with in my career is when my company closed their PA location, and I was asked to relocation to VA. It was a risk on my part, but I chose to follow the company to their new location. It paid off as I continued another five years of success there.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for us?", "answers": ["Bragging about yourself in an interview can be tough to do, but this is your time to shine! Which characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a stand-out candidate? Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given individual accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer.", "\"I am the best candidate for you because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current company. In addition to these successes, I have excellent cold calling skills which I will put to work immediately after being hired by your company.\"", "\"I believe I'm the best candidate for Company ABC because of my decade of experience at your competitor. I have experience in the specific department in question, as a team leader, and I look forward to building on those leadership skills with your organization.  I know I can make an immediate, and long-term, impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How would you describe your relationship with your customers or clients?", "answers": ["Do you value your client and customer relationships? How do you nurture them to ensure that they are happy and continue to come back? Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for steady customer and client relationships.", "\"My customer and client relationships are open and honest. I believe that the more upfront and transparent you are with your clients, the more likely they are to return. I most definitely value my clients and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"I have strong relationships with my clients and customers. I treat them with respect and am sure to utilize their feedback in ways that make myself, and the organization, better.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Looking at your resume, you've had a number of job changes. What would make me think that you will stay with our company?", "answers": ["Most hiring managers will consider more than two jobs in the past five years to be frequent movement. Take some time to explain your career progression to the interviewer. Be sure to avoid speaking poorly of any of your previous employers. This question is not the time to ramble on about how your former company did you wrong. Short and sweet is most appropriate here.", "\"Leaving Company X was due to a merger, and my role was eliminated. Company Y was a seasonal role, and I am now looking for a new position because my contract with Company Z is complete this March.\"", "\"In my career, I have made progressive moves to advance in my field of expertise. I am looking for a company that I can grow with long-term, and contribute value to, for many years to come.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, the decisions do not always come easily. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. \n\nProblems that require you to act quickly can be emergency situations such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out a small grease fire in the company kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. \n\nGoing with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"When an urgent problem arises at work, I always try to respond in a calm and assuring manner. I am a natural leader which means that my team often looks to me for answers. One instance of my fast-thinking was just last week when we had an administrative employee no-show on a critical and busy day for us. I called a temp agency, and they had the position filled in just one hour.\"", "\"I react swiftly in emergency situations. Perhaps my skills come from my years as a parent, having to think fast and put out fires! If a quick solution is required, I will do a fast overview of the facts and make a decision based on risk factors.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "If you were given a choice, which work related task would you leave for last? Why?", "answers": ["Often we will leave the tasks that we don't like for last in the act of procrastination. Other times, we will mindfully move a particular responsibility for last because we feel that it makes the most sense. Help the interviewer to determine which personality type you are by answering this question.", "\"If given a choice, I would leave my documentation tasks for last. I say this because I like to spend my time selling and hitting targets so anything to do with documentation during business hours - I feel takes away from my business development tasks. I do understand the importance of it, though.\"", "\"I tend to leave the hardest assignments for last.  It is not because I dread them, but because I can make a lot more people happy by completing their small requests first and getting them back to work.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "With your experience, what contributions do you believe you will make to our department?", "answers": ["Do you plan to make an immediate impact on the organization if you are hired? Talk to the interviewer about the contribution that you are going to make should you be the successful candidate.", "\"After meeting with you, and getting to know your organization on a deeper level, I am confident that I will make a strong contribution to this years' sales goals. I understand that you have set ambitious goals for the company and I can get you there through my existing network and a strong portfolio.\"", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. My contributing goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly if hired.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be tricky as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I put a heavy focus on honesty and trustworthiness in the workplace, as well as in my personal life.  Because I strive for complete honesty, I will rate myself as a 10/10. My values are solid.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"It does not take a lot to keep me motivated. If I work in a positive environment with a forward-thinking team, I am a very happy employee. If you see me going above and beyond, a quick thanks or small recognition of my hard work is good enough for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Tell me about a time when you improved communication between yourself and a co-worker or client.", "answers": ["Possessing the skills to improve communication in the workplace is a precious asset. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to enhance communication in the workplace.", "\"In my current position I have one particular client who was an exceptionally brief communicator. If I asked two questions, he would answer just one. I learned that he would not acknowledge anything for which he did not have a direct answer. I began to ask him questions in a different way. For example, I would say 'Do you have an answer for me on question X?' and he would say yes or no. We would then go from there. This solution was an effective method of communication for that particular client.\"", "\"Recently, we were working with a client who continued to change the direction of our work.  Our team was heading down one path and before we knew it, the client expected us to go another direction.  We resolved to hold a weekly status touch base call to ensure two-way communication with our team and the client. When work was not done, we could explain why and if the client wanted changes made, we could catch them before wasting time and resources.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "How do you handle situations that could cause you to be late or miss work?", "answers": ["Proper planning will get you far, but sometimes life happens, and you'll need a plan B. Think about some of the variables in your life that could affect your ability to arrive on time for work. Sick children, traffic, car breakdowns... the list goes on.  It may not be possible for everything to work out so smoothly, getting your shift covered or still making it to work on time. Your interviewer is looking to see that you are proactive and that you can handle the stress of unexpected situations that can arise.", "\"I stay calm and composed when issues arise. Just last week, I was in a car accident while commuting to work. I called my boss immediately to let her know that I was going to be late. This call gave her time to move my work volume to other employees so that our clients were not left hanging for call-backs and quotes.\"", "\"I hope never to be late! When I started working at a restaurant at sixteen years old, we were taught the adage of \"if you're on time, you're late,\" so I've worked to implement that into my life. I always try to arrive 15 minutes early, but there are unforeseen circumstances that can arise. I handle surprises using common sense and keeping courtesy to others top of mind.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "What types of activities keep you busy, outside of work?", "answers": ["Having hobbies and interests outside of work is a vital part of maintaining a healthy work/life balance. Talk to the interviewer about the activities that interest you outside of the workplace.", "\"I have a variety of hobbies that keep me busy outside of work hours. First, I have two children who are involved in basketball and gymnastics. I also play in a baseball beer league, I volunteer at our community church and like to read.\"", "\"I am a very physically active person, with a passion for outdoor sports. I love to ski, snowboard, and skate. I play in an adult hockey beer league, as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Heavy+Machinery", "question": "Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career. Talk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job.", "\"Salary is important to me because I know that I am skilled and well educated. With that said, I do look at the full picture which includes factors such as benefits, work-life balance, perks, and company culture.\"", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job.  Compensation is a driving component of that along with company mission, culture, benefits, and location.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "List for me the machinery that you are most accustomed to operating.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like assurance that you can handle the type of machinery that they operate at Company ABC. Talk to the interviewer about your exposure to machinery and any manufacturing specific experience that you may have. Be sure to ask the interviewer if they are looking for a particular type of machinery. This question will allow you to overcome any potential objections later. If specific machinery experience is requested in the job description, be sure to address that as well. \n\nIf you have the right experience: \"I see from your job description that you are looking for experience in machines X, Y, and Z. I have run these specific pieces of equipment for the past 12 years and consider myself an expert with them. Are there any other machine operating skills that you desire?\"", "\"I see from your job description that you are looking for experience in machines X, Y, and Z. I have run these specific pieces of equipment for the past 12 years and consider myself an expert with them. Are there any other machine operating skills that you desire?\"", "If you do not have the exact experience, they are seeking: \"I am most experienced in X which is very similar to Y, which I believe you frequently operate here. I am also an expert operator in A, B, and C machinery types. Are there any other skills that you desire?\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What do your team members think of you as the team leader?", "answers": ["It is essential to be aware, and honest, about your strong points and shortcomings when it comes to your leadership skills. Talk to the interviewer about what you honestly feel your team would say about your leadership skills.", "\"I often ask my team members for feedback on my leadership skills. The points that consistently come up are that I am a clear communicator and that I am approachable. One thing that I could work on would be my ability to be more concise in my direction, but I have been working on that and feel that I have improved significantly. \"", "\"I hope that my team sees me as a positive example, whether I am in a leadership role or not. I enjoy teaching and guiding others so I believe they would say that I am a collaborative leader who values mentorship.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "When do you best demonstrate yourself as a leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are confident about your leadership abilities and that you understand when your leadership abilities have been most useful.\n\nPerhaps you best demonstrate yourself as a leader when your manager is away. Maybe you often jump into a leadership mindset when a co-worker is struggling. Think about a recent time when an employee on your team was successful at something because of your leadership skills. Discuss the scenario and how your leadership skills made the difference.", "\"I best demonstrate myself as a leader when I know that a coworker could use my assistance. I seem to be a natural teacher and mentor which means that when someone is struggling, my first instinct is to train them. Just recently, I coached a new employee on a sales technique that helped her to achieve her quota for the first time. I look forward to working in this role with you because it will allow me to take on further leadership opportunities.\"", "\"In my current position, every time my current manager is away, I take on the role of leader for our team. This leadership opportunity takes place usually one day per week. When you call him for a reference, he will be able to tell you that I have naturally stepped into the responsibilities associated with being a leader.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "At Company ABC we manufacture thousands of SKU's. How do you plan to learn about our product range?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have a plan in place to succeed in this position with Company ABC. Discuss with the interviewer how you plan to learn their vast product range. Highlight your ability to study, memorize, and retain information. Display to the interviewer that you are genuinely interested in what Company ABC manufactures.", "\"I have already taken a keen interest in your products and am confident in my ability to learn the range of SKU's very quickly. I noticed that you have an online catalog, so I already started learning a lot about your product. Are there any other learning resources that you would recommend? I am a quick learner and great at retaining information. If you hire me, you will not be disappointed in my strong product knowledge abilities.\"", "\"Your product range is impressive, and I understand that it is going to take some time for me to become familiar with the large range of offerings you have here. I have a strong ability to memorize facts, and so I plan to create flashcards and cheat sheets for myself to help with my initial training.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include capabilities that will potentially benefit this potential new employer.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "Here are some additional transferable skills you may have acquired in your last position: \n\n- Leadership experience \n- Delegating tasks to other employees\n- Researching \n- Analyzing data\n- Written and verbal communications\n- Terminations and onboarding"]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of competition in me as well.\"", "\"I am delighted that you have asked this question! It just goes to show that you are a thoughtful employer. I am motivated by fun contests led by reaching KPI's and other important targets.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire individuals who are invested in their professional development. Walk me through any industry related coursework you have attended.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have taken any formal education and training related to their industry. Your reply will help the interviewer to assess your commitment to Company ABC and their industry.", "\"I have taken a variety of coursework related to the manufacturing and engineering industry. In addition to my Bachelor's degree in Engineering, I also have a Project Management certificate. I am fully dedicated to forging a strong career in this field and look forward to bringing my knowledge to work for Company ABC\"", "\"The majority of my training is in leadership and human resources within a manufacturing environment. I appreciate that Company ABC takes an interest in professional development because that aligns nicely with my plan to further my knowledge in safety and training for factory environments.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Tell me about the inventory software you have worked with. Are you familiar with the programs we use at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Direct experience with the exact software or programs used at Company ABC may not be a \"must-have,\" but do take some time to find out which programs they use, and discover how your technical skills may be a match. \n\nIf specific technical skills are essential for the success of this role, the desired skills will be listed in the job description. Be sure to ask the interviewer if they want to see any specific technical skills. This question will allow you to overcome any objections the interviewer may have later regarding your exposure to their particular programs.\n\nIf you have the right experience: \"I see from your job description that you are looking for experience in program X, Y, and Z. I have used all three of these programs for the past five years and would rate myself as an intermediate level user. Are there any other technical skills that you desire?\"", "If you do not have the exact technical experience, they are seeking: \"I am a fluent user in program X which is very similar to program Y. I am also an expert user of Excel and most other Microsoft programs. Are there any other technical skills that you desire?\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for us?", "answers": ["Bragging about yourself in an interview can be tough to do, but this is your time to shine! Which characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a stand-out candidate? Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given individual accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer.", "\"I am the best candidate for you because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current company. In addition to these successes, I have excellent cold calling skills which I will put to work immediately after being hired by your company.\"", "\"I'm qualified and passionate about your cause.  I am excited about the idea of delivering value to your organization and will hustle for the opportunity to go above and beyond for your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What challenges are you looking for in this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that this role will be challenging enough for you to stay with Company ABC long term. \n\nBe sure that you understand the job description. Take a close look at the duties and responsibilities that could pose a more significant challenge for you. Sometimes the hardest part is balancing all of the tasks you're expected to manage. \n\nExplain to the interviewer that you are prepared and looking forward to learning from difficulties as they arise. Be specific to show your understanding of the expectations of the role.", "\"I understand that working as a (your position) comes with a lot of challenges. As a new graduate, I have been eagerly awaiting my opportunity to jump into the job market and take on any challenge presented to me. I see the challenges of this position as opportunities to grow and learn.\"", "\"I am eager to be challenged in the workplace and am particularly looking forward to challenges pertaining to marketing, and product development.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "How did you bring value to your last position?", "answers": ["This question is similar to 'Why are you the best candidate?' Think about the strengths and skills that made you an asset in your last position. Maybe you influenced changes that saved the company money. Perhaps you were the top grossing sales person on the floor. Think of your strengths in action! If you are reliable, talk about how consistent your work has been and how you are in constant support for coworkers. If you have a strong work ethic, share how you accomplished a project in the midst of harsh obstacles.", "\"There were several ways I was able to bring value to my company. First, I successfully passed each sales goal in my department. Second, I was able to motivate other members of my team and share my sales techniques with them. Third, I introduced two new procedures to the sales manager that helped us eliminate employee idleness between sales calls.\"", "\"I bring value to my current position by being a knowledgeable and reliable employee. I bring a great attitude to work every day and am always open to teaching new employees as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "At Company ABC we put great pride into the quality of our products. In your opinion, what do we do best?", "answers": ["When a company takes great pride in the quality of the products they manufacture, they want to know that the individuals they hire are passionate about quality as well. Show the interviewer that you have invested some time in getting to know the products at Company ABC.", "\"I can certainly see the pride that this company puts into the products you manufacture. After researching your range of products, I believe that you have the biggest market strength because you keep so much of your work local.\"", "\"From my experience, so far, I feel that Company ABC is fantastic when it comes to how you treat your employees. Happy employees will put out great products. A healthy workplace culture is a great way to stand out!\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "At Company ABC we have employees from all branches of manufacturing including food, chemicals, textiles, machines, and equipment. What type of experience best defines your background or specialty?", "answers": ["This question is designed for the interviewer to draw out any transferable skills you may have. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your background. Be sure to highlight any experience in manufacturing, whether or not the industry is a direct fit with what Company ABC does.", "\"My previous employers have focused on food manufacturing; however, I am very familiar with many of the processes that transfer to the chemicals manufacturing industry. My safety training, as well as my machinery experience, will be a major asset to your company, should you choose to hire me.\"", "\"I am newer to the manufacturing industry so feel that I could quite easily land on my feet in a multitude of focus'. If I could choose one particular area that I was most passionate about, I would prefer to work on the machining side.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "We want you to find a fulfilling career with Company ABC. Where could you see yourself 5 years from now?", "answers": ["Before your interview, be sure to visit Company ABC career opportunities online. Take note of the range of job possibilities. Perhaps there are opportunities in other locations? What kind of growth is available in the particular department with which you are interviewing? Assure the interviewer that you desire a long-term opportunity with Company ABC by discussing the career path you would like.", "\"I saw a few leadership opportunities posted on your company website that seemed very interesting. Ultimately, I would like to work my way into a management role that offered leadership opportunities. I am very interested in working for Company ABC because of the multiple growth opportunities present here, and I look forward to proving my capabilities to you.\"", "\"Ideally, five years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Company ABC works with some very well-known and respected brands. How will you do your part to contribute to our strong reputation?", "answers": ["This question is designed for the interviewer to find out if you have researched Company ABC before your interview and also to see if your customer service philosophy matches their company values.\n\nBe sure to research the brands that Company ABC works with, or represents. Of those brands, discuss with the interviewer the ones with which you are most familiar. If something about them stood out to you during your research, be sure to mention this. \n\nNext, assure the interviewer that you are capable of upholding their strong reputation through your morale and customer service expertise.", "\"Part of the reason why I applied to work here is that of your impeccable industry reputation. The biggest brands that you work with are some of the brands that I currently work with already so if you hired me; you would be hiring someone with an applicable background. I would uphold your strong reputation by continuing to bring dedication and deep product knowledge to the job.\"", "\"I plan to do my part in upholding your reputation by bringing my absolute best to work every single day. I will treat your customers, vendors, and suppliers with utmost professionalism and respect.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Workplace safety is incredibly important to us at Company ABC. What kind of safety training do you have?", "answers": ["Chances are, your safety training is listed on your resume. The interviewer is looking for a brief overview of your safety training. Take a few minutes to walk them through your experience. Also, if you have any statistics to share on your safety record, this is a great time to discuss those successes.", "\"Just this year I renewed my safety training in X, Y, and Z. My current company was rigorous on safety, so I come from a strong environment where safety always comes first. I was the first production supervisor to have an accident free year which is something that I am proud of.\"", "\"I am new to my career, so I have not completed many noteworthy safety courses yet. I am CPR, and First Aid Certified and have taken Fall Arrest training. Could you share with me the courses that you feel I need so that I can gain a head start in the on-boarding process?\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Company ABC manufactures a multitude of products. Which to you think is our best seller?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your depth of knowledge on Company ABC and their products. How you answer this question will quickly reveal to the interview how much, or how little, research you have done before the meeting. \n\nStart by researching the company website and look for any special mentions. Generally, a company will highlight their best seller or most popular product. Next, Google search the company name and see if any particular product comes up in your search. Lastly, check customer or client reviews to see if there is a consistent theme. \n\nGive your answer by demonstrating your research, and logically backing your answer. You should ask the interviewer what their best selling product is, as well. This question could open up a great conversation between yourself and the interviewer while providing you with additional information that will be helpful for any upcoming interviews with Company ABC.", "\"I noticed, when researching this organization, that product X stood out above the others. Your company website has a page dedicated to it, and there are many customer mentions of this product online. I believe this must be your best seller. Is this correct? I would love to learn more about your products and which ones are the most popular.\"", "\"Because you have so many great products, it is hard for me to guesstimate which of your products is a best seller. Personally, product A stands out the most to me because it is unique and multi-functional. Could you share with me what your best selling products are?\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision-making requirements in this possible position. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in tech support, you faced problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you might have required to know how to negotiate and make decisions on prices and benefits you can give your customers. \n\nYou may have faced decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision-making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"I regularly made decisions regarding pricing and discounts for customers.  I had a standard set of criteria that I created, and I tried to let that guide me for consistency.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What was your greatest cost-cutting measurement you accomplished at your previous employer?", "answers": ["If you are in a management type of role, you will often be asked to keep your eyes open for cost-saving opportunities. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of understanding the importance of this practice and give a strong example of a time when you have done so.", "\"I have been able to present cost-cutting suggestions many times to my previous employer. The one that I feel had the biggest impact was when I suggested additional warehouse staff. We had three various shifts and still an average of 100 hours of overtime per week. I presented to my employer that we hire one more warehouse employee for each shift, keeping the hours to just 120 regular vs. 100 hours of overtime pay (@1.5x) This recommendation saved the company $31,000 per year. They implemented this change across 15 warehouses the following year, amounting to nearly half a million dollars in savings per year.\"", "\"The greatest cost-cutting measurement that I accomplished at work was through new suggestions for theft prevention. Since we implemented some of my suggestions our loss, due to theft, has decreased 12%.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I am not one for regrets or looking back; however, if I could change anything about my career path, I would have been more aggressive in my path to leadership earlier on.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What experience do you have using team-based messaging applications?", "answers": ["There are many options for communication software and messaging applications. Give the interviewer a brief overview of the apps you have experience using and assure them that you can learn their internal system, should it be new to you.", "\"I have used a variety of team-based messaging applications. I am best versed in Brosix, AOL Instant Messenger, and Freedcamp. No matter which system you use I am sure that I can pick it up very quickly.\"", "\"I have not used team-based messaging applications in my past positions; however, I am very technically savvy and experienced with multiple programs such as A, B, and C. I look forward to learning your systems as well!\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "How would you describe your relationship with your customers or clients?", "answers": ["Do you value your client and customer relationships? How do you nurture them to ensure that they are happy and continue to come back? Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for solid customer and client relationships.", "\"My customer and client relationships are best described as open and honest. I believe that the more upfront and transparent you are with your clients, the more likely they are to return. I most definitely value my clients and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"I build and keep excellent relationships with my clients! These relationships are key to the success of my employer which means that I need always to be putting my best foot forward.  I am honest with my customers, helpful, and always try to deliver earlier than they anticipate.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Do you ever used your sense of humor to diffuse a situation at work?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can diffuse a tense situation if needed. They also want to see a bit more of your personality! Stress and fast-paced work environments can cause people to feel overwhelmed and sometimes even angry or upset. Think of a time when you took a much more lighthearted approach to diffuse a tense situation.", "\"I would say that I use my sense of humor often at work. This humor could be by poking fun in friendly ways, or adding a bit of good sarcasm. Humor does seem to make things a bit lighter and more fun on the floor, allows everyone to shake off whatever's bringing us down, and move on to the next issue to tackle.\"", "\"Humor is one of those universal things to which everyone can relate. When used properly, it can help bridge a gap or bond a relationship. I use it, with good taste and professionalism, often in my communications. At the end of the day, it is important to enjoy what you do, and humor is a big component of that.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What steps do you take when you have to make an immediate decision without all the relevant information?", "answers": ["Sometimes we have to make decisions without all of the pertinent information at our fingertips. The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of taking educated guesses and that you are confident enough in your abilities that you can make a good decision without all pieces of the problem being present.", "\"When I need to decide without all of the information present, I weigh the pros and cons and come up with a solution that makes the most sense. Common sense can take you a long way!  Next, I may ask the opinion of someone I trust to see what they think. Even though I trust my decision-making ability, I still think it's important to get a second opinion when it comes to situations involving money or decisions that make a significant impact on others.\"", "\"I am a strong believer in following my gut, and for the most part, it has not steered me wrong. I try to gather as much information as possible, but when all of the pieces are not accessible, I assess the situation using my prior knowledge of similar situations, and I follow my intuition. If I'm not certain or feel conflicted, I don't hesitate to bring in another person or persons to help me come to the best, most effective decision.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "We have had concerns with employee theft recently.  What would you do if you caught a coworker stealing? \n co-worker stealing?", "answers": ["Some businesses have trouble with employee theft, and they need to make sure that they are hiring someone who is honest and trustworthy. Talk to the interviewer about the steps you would take if you caught a co-worker stealing.", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\"", "\"If I caught an employee stealing, I would report the incident immediately. As a previous manager, I understand the value of employee honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "How competitive are you?", "answers": ["Being a competitive person is an excellent thing if you are appropriately competitive in the workplace. Assure the interviewer that you have a tremendous competitive edge when necessary but are still able to balance that competition healthily.", "\"I think that on a scale of 1-10, I would rate myself as a 7 when it comes to being competitive. I love a great competition in the workplace when it comes to sales goals and breaking through last years' numbers. I am not competitive to the point that it would hurt my team or colleagues.\"", "\"I am not overly competitive when it comes to my ego. My competitive nature kicks in when I have a deadline to meet or a client who wants to be impressed by my level of work and service.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "How do you deal with a coworker when they stand in the way of your progress at work?", "answers": ["Even some of the best coworkers who are hard-working and entertaining can distract you from getting things done at work. The funny and entertaining coworkers who like to chat online and send you YouTube videos over email are often the ones who can get in the way of your productivity. How do you respond?\n\nThis question gives you a chance to talk about how you set healthy boundaries at work. It can be a difficult task, but you can handle it! Show off your ability to listen and communicate what you need from your coworkers, especially when you need space!", "\"I typically just set the boundary and tell my coworker that I need to focus, but I'd love to catch up with them at lunch. I've learned to set aside time to take breaks and spend time with coworkers, so I usually just let them know when I'll be available.\"", "\"I understand that coworkers can be distracting at times. I have no problem expressing that I am in a time crunch and asking my coworker if I can catch up at a later time.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "If you had a co-worker call in sick and you were asked to take over their project requiring overtime from you, how would you react? Where do you draw the line when it comes to being a team player?", "answers": ["Show your confidence to your interviewer by explaining your willingness to be part of the team and not being afraid to pick up the slack when needed, but make sure you don't allow someone to take advantage of you.", "\"I will always choose to be a team player. If I had a co-worker call in sick, I would take over what I was capable of doing. The only time I would draw the line would be if I felt I was being taken advantage of for any reason. For example, if they were purposefully being inefficient and expecting me to pick up the slack. For the sake of the company, I am always willing to go above and beyond the expectations.\"", "\"So long as my willingness to jump in is not taken advantage of, I am happy to help when my company is in a pinch. When the tables turn, and I may be ill, it would be nice to know that someone will be there to help me out as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Manufacturing", "question": "Why were you fired or let go from your last job?", "answers": ["Being terminated does not have to be an embarrassing or shameful thing. Be open and honest with the interviewer regarding your dismissal. Be sure to let the interviewer know that you can provide positive references despite a previous termination.", "\"I was terminated from my last position due to my inability to relocate to the new plant that my company was opening. It was unfortunate, but I am confident that I will find the right fit again shortly. Despite my termination, I can provide you with strong work references.\"", "\"Unfortunately, I was part of the 300 layoffs that occurred after a competitor acquired our company. It was a disappointing experience to go through; however, I am excited about the opportunities that await me.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What sources do you look to when you need to solve a complicated problem?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can think outside the box, or even ask for help when you are stuck on a complicated problem.\n\nMaybe you look to a mentor or boss for advice. Perhaps you have handbooks, manuals and systems you turn to for help. Offer some relevant examples based on your industry. If you work in the medical field, you may turn to textbooks, online research, colleagues or even patient's history to find the right solution. If you work in customer service, you may ask the customer what they need to find the best way to solve the problem. \n\nShow the interviewer that you are knowledgeable and equipped to handle these types of scenarios.", "\"When faced with a complicated problem, I will look to the resources that my current company has provided me. The answer is almost always in there. If it's more of a moral dilemma vs. a knowledge-based dilemma, I will ask my supervisor for his thoughts and opinion since I value him as a mentor and expert in our industry.\"", "\"If there's a complicated problem, I'll write out what I think the possible solutions would be, and make a note of what my gut tells me to do. Then, I will weigh those potential solutions against one another and list the complications that may arise as a result of each choice. Also, I am always open to input or suggestions from those with more experience than I and look to my mentors, their experience, and the training resources, as well as potentially talk the problem out with coworkers or my boss.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "When have you made a mistake delegating tasks to your team members?", "answers": ["Being able to delegate to your team correctly is a critical part of successful management. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have appointed in error. Be sure to discuss how you repaired the mistake.", "\"Earlier in my career I would delegate tasks at random, thinking that everyone had the skills to complete any company-related task. I found that these employees would procrastinate on these tasks if they seemed overwhelming or if they did not understand them. After a bit of time, and some learning, I began to delegate based on personality type and skill-set. This method proved to be much more effective, and I follow this delegation style to this day.\"", "\"I am usually cautious when delegating tasks because putting the wrong person in the wrong function can be a dangerous, and expensive, mistake. A few years ago I put an employee on the incorrect piece of machinery, thinking that he was certified in operating that bit of equipment. I am now sure to double check credentials before delegating.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["We all like recognition in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Share with the interviewer how you would want credit for your hard work. Through gifts? Financial perks? Public recognition? Kind words? Title promotions?", "\"I am very much an over-achiever and find that the best way for me to be recognized for a job well done is words of kindness and recognition. I am easily encouraged, and the best reward for me is to know that my hard work is being noticed.\"", "\"I do not like public recognition all that much as I prefer to do my job well, regardless of being recognized. When I have a major achievement, I would prefer a phone call from my supervisor saying a good job. Also, I like to be awarded additional responsibilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Company ABC is committed to transparency, whether that means full disclosure to our board, the government, or audit committee. Do you consider yourself a transparent and honest individual?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are an honest individual who will respect the values and environment created at Company ABC. When a question like this is asked of you, it's a great idea to offer up your references as well.", "\"I consider myself honest, and quite a transparent individual. I believe it is always best to have your intentions and desires known. In turn, I appreciate my employer being honest with me. I have prepared some references for you, and I'm confident they will speak to my honest character as well.\"", "\"I am told quite often that I am an honest and trustworthy individual, and you will be able to hear that directly from my supervisor when you call for a reference. I hold honesty and trustworthiness as fundamental virtues.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Integrity is a key value at Company ABC. When have you shown great integrity at work?", "answers": ["Integrity is best displayed through honesty and consistent moral values. Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you show your integrity in the workplace.", "\"In my last position, I was responsible for the cash deposit on a daily basis. There was never a discrepancy, in the four years that I worked there. I best show my integrity by being a consistently reliable employee.\"", "\"I show great integrity in all that I do. It's important in this industry, to be honest, and allow people to know what to expect from you. Being a person of integrity is very important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Give me an example of a time when your communication style helped you to be a more effective leader.", "answers": ["Everyone has their style of communication. Whatever your style, show the interviewer that it is useful. Your response should demonstrate your ability to articulate constructive criticism, encourage your team, or relay policy changes in a way that makes them exciting!", "\"I gave my employee some negative feedback because he appeared to be slacking off on the job. Rather than telling him, I thought he was lazy; I said, 'I've noticed that it's been taking longer for you to turn in those reports. What's going on? Is there anything I can do?' I always start by asking questions instead of making accusations. He was very appreciative and told me how he was struggling with motivation. I asked him what would motivate him and we were able to find a solution that worked for both of us.\"", "\"I love to play to other's strengths. Everyone communicates differently, so I am sure always to send written as well as give verbal communication. Usually, that looks like a small, informal huddle outlining our topic or concern and I follow that up with a quick email detailing the discussion. This way the team hears and reads all expectations. Also, it allows for those who are vocal to share in a group setting as well as allows for the quieter few to ask their questions in the privacy of an email.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "At Company ABC we understand that our industry can be a volatile one. In your opinion, what is the outlook for the metals and mining industry in the next year?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have a keen interest in the industry and that you are up to date on some of the challenges and wins that Company ABC may be facing. You do not need to give an incredibly long and drawn out answer but be sure to highlight a couple of interesting points. \n\nWrap up your response by asking the interviewer their personal opinion on the outlook for the industry. This question from you could start an insightful and helpful conversation", "\"I read in an article a short time ago that mining was one of 2016's best performing sectors despite a slow start to the year. Citi analysts are predicting another solid year. How do you feel the outlook will be for this industry in the years to come?\"", "\"Although the prices for many commodities have declined over the years, I feel that we will be bouncing back again very soon. According to the Financial Post, 2018 is going to be a solid year for the metals and mining industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Every step counts for a successful project so at Company ABC we prefer to hire those who come highly trained. Do you have any post-secondary education related to project management or environmental affairs?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you come equipped with the knowledge level appropriate for this position. If you do not have a post-secondary education, then be sure to make a statement regarding your ability to perform the tasks required of you for this role with Company ABC.  \n\nIf you have project management or environmental related post-secondary education: \"I am PMP Certified from the Project Management Institute. In addition to this certification, I also possess a degree in Business Management from Strayer University. These education related successes have helped me to learn more about multitasking during complex projects, anticipate product needs, and put safety at the forefront of a project.\"", "\"I am PMP Certified from the Project Management Institute. In addition to this certification, I also possess a degree in Business Management from Strayer University. These education related successes have helped me to learn more about multitasking during complex projects, anticipate product needs, and put safety at the forefront of a project.\"", "If you do not have project management or environmental related post-secondary education: \"My formal education related to environmental affairs is limited; however, I bring 15 solid years' experience in the industry. My knowledge level is healthy, and I am confident in my ability to surpass your expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Company ABC likes to bring out the best in our employees. What type of manager brings out the best in you?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you are self-aware and understand the type of manager or employer that brings out the best in you. Some individuals prefer a close working relationship with a lot of accountability while others prefer space and autonomy. If you are unsure of the management style at Company ABC, try to leave your answer as open as possible. You can certainly ask the interviewer to describe their management style.", "\"I have worked with a wide range of personalities and management styles with great success. If I could express a preference, I feel that I perform best in an independent and autonomous environment. Can you describe the management style here?\"", "\"I work best with managers who are patient, like to teach and are clear communicators. Because I am newer to my career, I do hope to work for a manager who can mentor me.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision-making requirements in this possible position. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in tech support, you faced problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you might have been required to know how to negotiate and make decisions on prices and benefits you can give your customers. \n\nYou may have faced with decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision-making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"I regularly made decisions regarding pricing and discounts for customers.  I had a standard set of criteria that I created, and I tried to let that guide me for consistency.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "How often do you discuss work with your colleagues in order to think up new systems and styles of working?", "answers": ["Do you use your creative mind with your colleagues to discuss ideas and systems in the workplace? Talk to the interviewer about how you have used creative thinking in the workplace.", "\"I have a policy with my team that if they have an innovative and helpful idea they can bring it to me at any time. If my team members' idea or system is something that I think could work, we then create a plan together to present it to our head office. This policy has generated some compelling ideas in our office over the past three years including a work-share program and some health and safety initiatives.\"", "\"I think it is important to discuss work with colleagues in a collaborative nature to encourage all types of ideas to come forth.  Often, when people put their heads together, they will create something better than something one individual could have done alone.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "At Company ABC we put safety first when it comes to our employees and the handling of our products. How important is safety to you?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are as concerned about safety as they are. In which ways do you put safety first? Talk about the importance of security in the workplace.", "\"One of the reasons why Company ABC stands out to me as a potential employer, is your dedication to workplace safety. I feel that safety should be the number one consideration in this industry. It determines employee engagement, company profitability, and ensures a strong industry reputation.\"", "\"Safety is of utmost importance to me! I take regular precautions in the workplace, and I continue to attend safety training while keeping my tickets and certifications valid.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Company ABC seeks to hire those who are up to date on the industry. Our industry is a competitive one with policy changing frequently. How do you keep up with industry trends and policy changes?", "answers": ["The interviewer is seeking for proof that you have a genuine interest in their particular industry. When you have a real interest in a topic, you will spend time dedicating yourself to grow your knowledge base. \n\nDiscuss with the interviewer a couple of ways that you keep yourself updated on industry trends and policy changes. It's also a great idea to ask the interviewer about the ways they keep prefer to stay on top of industry topics. You never know what other resources are out there and you may learn something new!", "\"There are many great resources dedicated to the metals and mining industry. At the moment, my favorite resource is miningmagazine.com. I visit their website frequently and also subscribe to their blog. What is your favorite resource for industry related news?\"", "\"I subscribe to a variety of print, and online, publications such as Mines to Markets, Mining Global and Cobalt News. Could you share with me some of your favorite resources? I always like to learn about new industry resources.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "In your opinion, why is our industry a fundamental one?", "answers": ["Employees who see value in their company, and industry, are going to be happier and stay longer. The interviewer is looking for your opinion on why the metals and mining industry is an important one. Show the interviewer that, if hired by Company ABC, you would have a sense of pride in what they do.", "\"I strongly believe that the metals and mining industry provides an excellent boost in the economy; especially in those regions and states where mining activity is concentrated. Minerals and metals are what make nearly everything we have so without this type of mining, many of the products we know and love would not exist.\"", "\"I believe the biggest reason why mining is necessary is that minerals and metals can rarely be substituted for anything. They are vital to our everyday lives. If mining stopped, we would not have other resources for some of the most important things we use every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "At Company ABC we take every step possible to be a leader in our industry. In your opinion, who are our competitors and what sets us apart from them?", "answers": ["It is incredibly important to research the company before your interview. You should learn who the company's competitors are. Discuss your findings with the interviewer and be sure to speak highly of Company ABC while answering this question.", "\"I have researched Company ABC and see that you truly are an industry leader in the metals and mining arena. From my research, I believe what sets you apart is your incredible dedication to safety, and to the environment.\"", "\"From my understanding, your biggest competitors are companies A, B, and C. I believe that Company ABC is different because you put safety above all else. Your public safety records are impressive, and I am excited at the possibility to join such a responsible company.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What do you know about corporate governance practices in the metals and mining industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to understand the depth of your experience and knowledge when it comes to rules of engagement in the metals and mining industry. Show the interviewer that you have exposure to corporate governance but avoid giving a long-winded answer. Briefly state the level of exposure you have had with each industry related company on your resume.", "\"Corporate rules and practices were governed heavily in my last three positions. In all three positions, our Board of Directors created Corporate Governance guidelines that strongly supported the integrity of our operations. I believe Corporate Governance practices always need to be in line with the stockholders' best interests. Corporate Governance should also provide oversight of the company's accounting and financial reporting processes.\"", "\"As I am new to this industry, I do not have a vast amount of knowledge when it comes to corporate governance. With that said, I have started to study these, using government websites as a resource. If you have any suggestion for me on what to study, I am very open to suggestions.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Social responsibility is important to us. In your opinion, what is the best environmental effort Company ABC has launched in the past 3 years?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have a keen interest in what they do at Company ABC and that you're up to date on their latest company news and efforts. \n\nVisit the Company ABC website or Google the company name to see what you can find in regards to their latest environmental efforts. Keep your answer brief and complimentary. It's okay to ask the interviewer some questions on their environmental initiatives as well. This inquiry could be a great way to start a meaningful conversation.", "\"I like that Company ABC takes social and environmental responsibility so seriously. In my opinion, the best environmental effort that this organization has made in the last few years would be the mine land restoration program that you rejuvenated in 2015. Which environmental effort are you most proud of?\"", "\"Your organization has many great efforts focused on environmental sustainability. I would say that the most impressive efforts I have seen from your organization are the reduction of your energy and water consumption while maintaining a focus on minimizing land disturbance.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "How has your current job changed over the years?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know more about your career progression. Additional responsibilities, promotions, and changes in the title all indicate that you were competent and successful in your role. \n\nTake some time to highlight any successes for the interviewer. This question gives you an opportunity to go more in-depth about how your role has evolved. If nothing has changed much over the past couple of years in your position, focus on what you have learned. Are you better at managing teams now that you have gone from supervising one to five people? Are you exceptionally good with problem-solving now that you've learned to troubleshoot IT related problems? Talk about how the changes in your job have taught you new skills and helped you develop the ones you already have.", "\"When I initially started my job four years ago I was a junior level operator. Today, I am responsible for leading a team of 8 operators. My role does not look the same at all, and I am thankful for the growth opportunity that my current company has offered me. In addition to the change in leadership responsibilities, I have also enjoyed two major promotions. I attribute this to hard work and dedication.\"", "\"Change is a constant for me in my current company. I am given new responsibilities quite regularly which include training new employees, hosting lunch and learns, and writing a new policy. The pace of growth is complementary to my career goals.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Do you consider yourself a patient person? How do you increase your patience level in challenging situations?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you consider yourself a patient individual. Impatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in coworkers, so it is imperative that you can showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations. \n\nPatience is indeed a virtue but can be challenging to maintain when it seems that situations continue to push your buttons. Show the interviewer that you possess the ability to keep your cool in challenging conditions.", "\"I do consider myself a patient person. I would rate myself an eight /10 for patience because I certainly have room to grow, but I do have a very long fuse. If I need a boost of patience in a challenging situation, I will take a step away, count to 10 and then return to the situation. I recently read a book, 'The Power of Patience' by M.J. Ryan which also gave me some excellent new methods for coping with stress.\"", "\"I was once working with a group that could not quite get along, and it tested my patience a bit because it prevented us from staying on track and focusing on the goals.  I went above and beyond in helping the group get along by scheduling lunches as a team and helping to mediate situations that needed it.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "We are looking for a long term fit at Company ABC. Where do you see yourself five years from now?", "answers": ["It's impossible to know where you will be in 5 years but does assure the interviewer that, given all possible circumstances, you could see yourself as a long-term fit for their position.", "\"Ideally, five years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\"", "\"In 5 years I would like to be seen as an authority in our industry. I would like to be well-connected and trusted when it comes to my work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Strong communication skills are important for any role with Company ABC. Rate your communication skills from 1-10.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Discuss with the interviewer why you chose that particular rating for yourself. Be sure to highlight that your exceptional communication skills will make you a success in this role with Company ABC!", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My current supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything. I look forward to bringing my strong communication skills to Company ABC.\"", "\"I will rate myself an eight because I value communication but, just like most people, I have things to learn. Some ways that I ensure clear communication are by utilizing multiple methods of delivering messages, and I give ample time for questions before implementing changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Considering your background is in an industry different from Company ABC, what skills and characteristics do you have that qualify you for this industry?", "answers": ["There are many ways that you can be a fit for a position, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit Company ABC, despite the industry background you may have. These are your transferable skills, and they can include sales abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities.", "\"Although my background is not in the metals and mining industry, I have worked with many clients who have been in your industry. I bring excellent transferable skills that qualify me for this position. These skills include my advanced abilities in Excel, my outstanding cold-calling abilities as well as my proven background in team leadership.\"", "Here are some transferable skills that could qualify you to work in the metals and mining industry:\n\n- Conflict Resolution \n- Time Management\n- Project Management \n- Hiring and Onboarding\n- Supervising Others\n- Presentation Giving \n- Advising"]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "We believe in giving Company ABC employees honest, open, and regular feedback. What feedback did you receive at your last job?", "answers": ["Every manager has a different approach to giving feedback. Some prefer to save it for the performance review while others dish it out on the regular. Your response to feedback is much more important than the input itself. Even if it was negative, if you can take it as constructive criticism, you can improve yourself and your skills.", "\"My previous manager told me that I was spending too much time on the details of a project. I realized that I could be such a perfectionist that I lose track of time and hyper-focus on things that aren't that important. I taught myself to prioritize better so that my results are successful on projects, both large and small.\"", "\"I regularly received feedback from my supervisor relating to areas of customer satisfaction. For the most part, the feedback was always very positive. On the odd occasion, I was asked to improve my documentation which I worked very hard to do.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Tell me about the most challenging problem you have encountered in your professional career.", "answers": ["Everyone has had their share of challenges in their career. The interviewer knows that you are not perfect; however, they need to know that you can professionally overcome work-related roadblocks. \n\nMaybe you had a significant project that almost went sideways. Perhaps you had a conflict in the workplace that you could have handled more professionally. Explain your approach to resolving the issue and be sure to highlight the steps you took to reach that resolution.", "\"The most challenging problem I have encountered in my professional career was with my most recent employer. I had an incredibly important project that made up the majority of my annual budget. The client was challenging to work with as he was rarely available for comment, due to extensive international travel. I needed this deal to work out so, for the 6-month span of the project, I made my work hours reflect his time zone. This allowed us to communicate via Skype on a daily basis. This meant a fair share of late night and early morning calls for me! It was a sacrifice; however, I would do it again. I understand that sacrifices need to be made for successful outcomes to happen.\"", "\"The most challenging problem that I encountered in my career was when my former company experienced a major merger. It was a lot to adjust to but, after some time, I was able to get a good pace again.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role with Company ABC.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"I define success by what we achieve as a team. The project, as a whole, needs to deliver on expectations before I consider the job a success.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What is your personal mission statement?", "answers": ["Not everyone has a mission statement or personal mantra just off the cuff. In business, especially when entering leadership, this is an important question to ponder. Do you have a quote that inspires you or a saying that you grew up with that resonates with you?", "\"My mantra is that 'people who shine from within do not need the spotlight.' I feel that it is incredibly important to be a humble leader and I take this mission statement very seriously. I want my team to be in the spotlight rather than being the kind of leader that takes credit for good work.\"", "\"I am not sure that I have a personal mission statement; however, my mission is to always treat people with respect and kindness. Kindness will always win, and people appreciate the gesture.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What steps do you take when you have to make an immediate decision and you do not feel you have all the relevant or necessary information?", "answers": ["Knowing how to look for the right information and where to look when the clock is ticking is what makes you a problem solver! Walk the interviewer through your process of seeking out the relevant information you need to make that quick decision. Explain the steps to give the interviewer a clear picture of your thought process.", "\"I have a pretty routine process I follow to make quick decisions. I weigh the pros and cons and come up with a solution that makes the most sense. Next, I ask the opinion of someone I trust to see what they think. Even though I trust my decision-making ability, I still think it's important to get a second opinion when it comes to situations involving money or if it could make a significant impact on others.\"", "\"I am an organized individual, so I do have a checklist that I follow for all policy related decisions and changes. If I do not have all necessary information, I can usually find it in our company resource database.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "If you had a co-worker call in sick and you were asked to take over their project requiring overtime from you, how would you react? Where do you draw the line when it comes to being a team player?", "answers": ["Show your confidence to your interviewer by explaining your willingness to be part of the team and not being afraid to pick up the slack when needed, but make sure you don't allow someone to take advantage of you.", "\"I will always choose to be a team player. If I had a co-worker call in sick, I would take over what I could. The only time I would draw the line would be if I felt I was being taken advantage of for some reason. For example, if they were purposefully being inefficient and expecting me to pick up the slack. For the sake of the company, I am always willing to go above and beyond the expectations.\"", "\"Teamwork is important to me, and I am always willing to go above and beyond the call of duty for the good of the organization for which I work. So long as I am not being taken advantage of, then I will happily step in to assist.\""]}, {"topic": "Metals+and+Mining", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"Yes. I am eager to return to work and am actively seeking my next opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Tell me about a time when you had to troubleshoot to solve a problem.", "answers": ["Troubleshooting is like reverse engineering - it takes skill, effort, and patience. You have to understand the problem to know how to work backward from it to find a solution. \n\nKnowing how to solve problems with technical equipment is always a solid skill, and a great way to demonstrate your example. Show that you are insightful in your approach.", "\"Last week, while operating the RT Scanner, I was receiving a repeated error. I entered in a few different codes, but that didn't solve the issue. I then did a hard reset. Then, I referred to the online manual for additional suggestions. It took a little time and patience, but I was able to resolve the issue without calling a technician.\"", "\"We do not have an IT department in my current office so whenever an issue arises, I am the person that my team calls. Troubleshooting is fun for me  - it's like a new challenge every time. Google and IT related forums are often my best friend!\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Have you ever worked in a unionized environment? How do you feel about unions?", "answers": ["You may love unions, or you may have adversity towards them. The best thing to do when you are asked a question like this is to give an answer that is positive, either way. Like there are always two sides to a story - there is still a positive to find from either side. Talk about your experience in a union environment; however, if it was not a positive one, it's highly recommended that you avoid complaining. Pick a positive note and focus on that.", "\"I feel that unions have their place in many situations. I worked in a unionized environment for three years with Company ABC, and the union created a smoother and more organized environment.\"", "\"Although I have never worked in a unionized environment, I do understand why unions are required in some facilities. They create order, process, and help to uphold expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Judging by your resume, you appear to be overqualified for this position. What would keep you here, if you were offered the position?", "answers": ["Sometimes, hiring an overqualified individual can mean that they will leave when a better opportunity arises. Talk to the interviewer about why this position would be satisfying for you, long-term.", "\"I do have more years' experience than what you have outlined in your job posting; however, there are aspects of this position that would be new and exciting for me as well. For example, I would enjoy the exposure to more public accounting and government-related accounts. Despite my level of experience, there would be much for me to learn here.\"", "\"The job titles in my last two roles make it appear that I am overqualified for the role. They were big titles but, rest assured, this position is very much in line with my current skill level.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we have a variety of packaging equipment, forklifts, and other machinery on site. What equipment are you most accustomed to operating?", "answers": ["Your equipment experience is likely listed on your resume. The interviewer would like further details on your range of experience and how you would rate yourself on each piece of equipment. \n\nIf you are unclear, it is okay to ask the interviewer what type of equipment they run at Company ABC. Asking that question is a great conversation starter and will allow you to highlight your experience on the equipment they currently run.", "\"I am most experienced in equipment A, B, and C and would rate my level of expertise as a 9 out of 10. I am certified in a variety of equipment operation including X, Y, and Z. I have brought my tickets and certifications if you would like to take a copy of them for my file. What would you say is the most frequently used equipment in your facility?\"", "\"I have a plethora of experience operating heavy equipment. I am most versed in Raymond reach, stand up, and also have experience with a zoom boom.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to advance our hardest working employees. What growth opportunities would you like to see with us?", "answers": ["The interviewer would love to have a specific answer when it comes to the career growth that you would like to see within their organization. This insight will show that you are engaged in the process and excited about what the future holds with Company ABC.\n\nBefore your interview, conduct some research on the range of career opportunities that are available at Company ABC and see if any of this stand out in your mind. You can quickly do this by combing through the company website, company LinkedIn page, and any other online job boards.", "\"I see that Company ABC has had a couple of great management opportunities open. I would be very interested in discussing with you how I can eventually work my way into a leadership role here. I see a long-term fit with Company ABC and want to prove my abilities to you right from the start.\"", "\"I would like to learn how to operate a wider variety of machinery and equipment. From my understanding, your organization can help me become third-party certified in the operation of a range of equipment.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $60,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one-sided hunt. You must also feel as though this is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer what your ideal employer looks like. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "\"I am looking to join a company that is forward-thinking and interested in being better every single day. An employer who is open to mentoring me, as I am newer to my career, is ideal.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Have you ever taken the fall for a situation, where it was really not your fault, in order to protect a coworker?", "answers": ["Taking the fall for a situation, to protect a co-worker, is a tricky situation. It can show teamwork, but it may not be the most honest thing to do. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on taking the fall for something you did not do.", "\"I do not believe in 'taking the fall' for people based on protecting them. Transparency is always a good idea, and if something went wrong, then it needs to be addressed to prevent it from happening again. When it comes to clients, I will apologize on behalf of the company for errors. In that case, I will do what it takes to protect the company's reputation.\"", "\"I have taken the heat for a situation that was not my fault. Honestly, it wasn't anyone's fault, and I understand that sometimes the blame needs to land somewhere when corporate is looking for answers.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Working at Company ABC can become stressful some days. How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we load up to 1100 packages per hour. What volume of work are you accustomed to?", "answers": ["This question is an excellent opportunity to talk about the KPI's and other productivity expectations in your current, or most recent, position. Talk to the interviewer about your workload and what you believe you can handle successfully in a day.", "\"1100 packages per hour is around the same as my current company. In my current role, we have measured on our hourly packaging rate as well as units packed per day. I am confident that I could handle the workload expectation here at Company ABC.\"", "\"I am accustomed to working in a high volume role, so 1100 packages per hour will be no problem for me. I do prefer a fast-paced work environment because it keeps the days exciting, and moving along quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Considering your background is in an industry different from ours, what skills and characteristics do you have that qualify you for this position in this industry?", "answers": ["There are many ways that you can be a fit for a position, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit another employer, despite the industry. These are your transferable skills, and they can include sales abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities.", "\"Although my background is not in your precise industry, I have worked with many clients who have been in your industry. I bring excellent transferable skills that qualify me for this position. These skills include my advanced abilities in Excel, my outstanding cold-calling abilities as well as my proven background in team leadership.\"", "\"I have a variety of transferable skills that could be very well utilized in this position, regardless of the industry I come from. For instance, I am fantastic with project management, delegating in the workplace, and analyzing data.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["We all like recognition in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Share with the interviewer how you would want to be recognized for your hard work. Through gifts? Financial perks? Public recognition? Kind words? Title promotions?", "\"I am very much an over-achiever and find that the best way for me to be recognized for a job well done is to be given words of kindness and recognition. I am easily encouraged, and the best reward for me is to know that my hard work is being noticed.\"", "\"If I am doing a great job, I appreciate a pat on the back. Also, if you feel that I am ready for additional responsibilities, then that is another way to show me you appreciated my hard work.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "When have you used an inventive method to stretch company resources beyond the normal level?", "answers": ["If you have an expense account or resource allowance, it is very respectful to the company to be as thoughtful with that allowance as possible. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been able to stretch company resources.", "\"I have recently implemented a schedule that allows for ride-sharing rewards which have cut down on our company's fuel expense by $9000 per month. I am quite proud of this initiative because it is not only financially responsible but also environmentally friendly.\"", "\"This is a practice I often utilize to maximize company resources and optimize value to the clients. I recycle a lot of company materials to make the most of our resources. I also do this with people regarding cross training and sharing understanding across departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a fellow worker or subordinate?", "answers": ["One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to people which whom you work. Whether it is providing a less than positive work review or terminating someone -these tough conversations never come easy. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of task in a transparent, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I certainly do not enjoy communicating bad news to a co-worker, but I do have experience in doing so. When this type of task is required of me, I make sure to practice empathy. Truth is always key, so I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. For instance, if I am to terminate someone's employment, I will not sugar coat the reasons why. It's best they know so that they can learn from the experience.\"", "\"I have found that communicating with respect and the intent to support the associate is the best approach.  It is important to communicate what behaviors are off track and what resources are available to the associate to get back on track.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "This position may require you to lift up to 50 pounds, bend, and stand throughout the day. Are you able to meet the physical requirements for this role at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can safely handle the physical requirements of the job. The best way to answer this is to talk about the physical demands of your current / most recent position. Alternately, you can discuss the ways you ensure you're in peak physical condition.", "\"Yes, I can meet these physical requirements. In my current position, I lift up to 65 pounds throughout the day. I have never had a physical injury in the workplace.\"", "\"I can stand for long periods of time, and lift up to 50 pounds. I do have a previous knee injury, so I wear a brace to help me remain injury free.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "We have a few local competitors. Why do you think that Company ABC has the best product?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you have researched Company ABC and it's products before your interview. Your knowledge of their product will show that you are engaged in this process and excited about the opportunity. This question should not be taken as an opportunity to speak poorly of the competition; instead, focus on the ways that Company ABC stands out from the crowd.", "\"I have seen your product first hand and recognized that it is higher quality than most. Because your company started as a small family-owned business, I believe your focus on quality is superior to many of your competitors.\"", "\"I believe that you have the best product of your competitors because your quality assurance standards are the highest in the industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC our facility runs 24/7. What is your availability? Do you have a preferred shift?", "answers": ["If Company ABC runs a morning, afternoon, and evening shift then you should go into the interview being very clear on your preference and availability. \n\nThe last thing you would want to do is be offered a role that isn't a fit for your lifestyle. Keep your answer to the point. There is no need to over-explain your scheduling needs.", "\"My wife and I like to arrange our work schedules around our children's needs. For that reason, I am seeking an afternoon shift. This way I can continue to drive them to school in the morning.\"", "\"I am open when it comes to my availability and so appreciate as many overtime hours as possible. Which shifts do you have available at this time?\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we put safety first in all situations. What would you do if you saw a co-worker performing unsafe work?", "answers": ["The interviewer is wondering how you would react in a potentially unsafe work situation. If Company ABC is putting a lot of effort and resources into employee safety, they need assurance that you will appreciate those efforts and help to uphold their high safety standards. Answer this hypothetical question by using a real-life example, if possible. Otherwise, give a theoretical answer. Be sure to compliment them on their safety efforts.", "\"If I saw a co-worker performing hazardous work I would act according to Company ABC policy. If the individual reported to me, I would kindly ask them to stop what they were doing and would re-train them on the correct behavior. I would be sure to document the situation as well. In my opinion, there is no room for safety shortcuts in the workplace, and I appreciate that Company ABC puts so much effort into safety efforts.\"", "\"I believe that safety is the most important factor to a successful workplace. For that reason, if I saw a co-worker performing hazardous work, I would ask them to stop immediately. I would then report the situation. Unsafe behavior affects us all.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we work hard to create a unified work environment. Describe your personality to me and why you think you will be a fit here.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you honestly see yourself when it comes to your workplace personality. Before your interview, do some research on the leadership team, the company values, and any mission statement they may have. Through your research, you should get a great idea of the qualities that Company ABC values. Try to tie those values into your answer.", "\"I would describe myself as an approachable, knowledgeable, and team-driven person. After researching Company ABC I believe that this is a great fit because of the open energy and strong emphasis on teamwork that you have created within your organization.\"", "Here are some words you could use to describe your personality:\n\n- Adaptable\n- Balanced\n- Charismatic\n- Decisive \n- Efficient \n- Focused\n- Good-natured\n- Honest\n- Innovative\n- Kind\n- Loyal\n- Meticulous\n- Non-authoritarian\n- Organized\n- Patient\n- Reliable\n- Self-sufficient \n- Thorough \n- Upbeat\n- Well-rounded"]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "At Company ABC we respect a healthy work/life balance. How would you react if you were asked to work overtime every now and then?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to gauge your willingness to go over and above the call of duty, from time to time. Maintaining a healthy work/life balance is essential but will you be a team player when necessary? If you can, give an example of a time when you went out of your way to help your employer by working overtime.", "\"I am happy to be a team player and work overtime when it's for the good of the company. In my current position, I will work an overtime shift at least once per week when volumes are high. I have no problem helping out when needed.\"", "\"I  would appreciate as many overtime hours as possible, to be honest. I am saving to return to night school and will take any hours you can offer me.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Tell me about your relationship with your previous boss.", "answers": ["When you answer this question be sure to remain positive, even if your experience wasn't. Avoid talking about any previous drama and do not speak poorly of your employer. Keep your answer short and respectful. \n\nIf you had a good relationship with your previous boss: \"I had a very healthy relationship with my previous employer. She was easy to approach, and we would bounce ideas off of each other quite often. I would sum it up as a relationship lead by strong mutual respect.\"\n\nIf you did not have a good relationship with your previous boss: \"I have had healthier relationships in the past with previous employers, but we did the best that we could. Our communication styles were very different which made it challenging at times.\"", "\"I had a very healthy relationship with my previous employer. She was easy to approach, and we would bounce ideas off of each other quite often. I would sum it up as a relationship lead by strong mutual respect.\"", "\"My previous boss and I had a great working relationship.  We were in sync when it came to accomplishing things we needed to do in our department.  We scheduled weekly touch base meetings to stay current on our progress and address any issues that came up along the way. I learned a lot from them on leadership while adding great value to the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Why is this job right for you at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"This job is right for me at this time in my career because I am prepared and ready to take on a management position. I feel that your company would nurture my desire for growth and prepare me for the appropriate training.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I am satisfied with my career progression.  Everyone, including me, hits roadblocks or setbacks, but I have been able to push through them and stay on track.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "How do you get along with others at work?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to gauge if you can maintain healthy relationships in the workplace. They want to know more about the dynamics with your coworkers. Think about what you enjoyed about some of your relationships with past coworkers. Excellent communication, sense of humor, and support are all great qualities that make co-worker relationships healthy and harmonious.", "\"I get along great with my coworkers. I try to maintain a positive attitude and be supportive, whether I am offering to assist someone who is overwhelmed, or if I am taking time to listen to someone who is having a bad day.\"", "\"I generally enjoy the people I work with and can get along with anyone. I have made some of my closest friends from different workplaces, and I know how important relationships in the office are for not only camaraderie but also for accomplishing tasks within your team.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I think I missed ten days, counting vacation time. Of those, five were for my vacation.  For three days, I was excused under a doctor's note.  The other two absences were pre-approved family days.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "What would you do if you were made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from Company ABC?", "answers": ["Companies want to know they are hiring loyal employees. Make sure that you illustrate in your answer that you would do the right thing and represent the company for which you are working.", "\"Unfortunately, dishonest employees are everywhere, and I certainly would not consider myself a 'whistle-blower' in the workplace. If I found that a co-worker was stealing, or doing anything to harm the company, I would approach them directly to ask what was going on. There is a good chance of the situation being a simple misunderstanding. If it wasn't a misunderstanding and the co-worker was outright defiant with their damaging actions, then I would bring it, professionally, to the appropriate parties.\"", "\"If I were made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing, I would report the situation right away. There is no sense in aggressively approaching someone when they are doing wrong in the workplace. It's better that HR or the appropriate party handle these situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Have you had the opportunity to teach an important skill to a co-worker?", "answers": ["Interviewers want to hear that you have experience teaching or mentoring other employees one-on-one.  \n\nYou may have taught a new hire all of your department's standard processes. Perhaps you taught a long-standing employee how to use Excel. You may have mentored an employee who was struggling to hit their monthly goals.  All of these scenarios are great examples to draw on.  Better yet, if you have personally seen someone struggling with workplace skills or knowledge, approached them, and offered to mentor them, it is a shining example of leadership!  \n\nWhatever your scenario may be, tell the interviewer what you helped the person with, while highlighting the positive outcome of their skills improvement.", "\"Last week our company introduced a new module in our SAP system. I could see that our contracted HR Assistant was having some troubles with the new module. I was familiar with it already, so I offered to help him learn the module. We spent his lunch hour for the next three days working on it. He perfected the module and our company was so impressed with his dedication to learning that they are now trying to find room to hire him on a full time, permanent basis.\"", "\"Absolutely! In each of my two previous roles, I have been tasked with leading a small team. I have worked on everything from appointment setting and overcoming objections to price negotiations with those respective teams. What's more, I always look for an opportunity to connect with the new folks to the team to ensure them that I can be a resource to them.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have the particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all, but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Do you prefer to work in a team based position or individually?", "answers": ["In which situation are you the happiest and most productive? Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself).", "\"I have found, in the past, that I work best in an individually driven environment; however, I can certainly be productive in a team-based setting as well.\"", "\"I am a fan of team-based positions where everyone has something unique to offer. It creates a great diversity and generates ideas that may not have occurred in an individual based work environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creativity. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible, I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "When have you worked among a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"I would say that pretty much every company I have worked for has valued diversity.  Working with people from all walks of life help shed different perspectives and identify potential problems faster.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "How do you believe you will complement our department, if you were hired?", "answers": ["If you were awarded the position, what would you bring to the department or organization? Assure the interviewer that you are the right fit for this position.", "\"If hired, I feel that I would compliment your organization in a few significant ways. First - I am a fast learner, and I already bring six years' experience in this industry. The time to train me will be reduced. Also, I will bring a robust portfolio of clients with me which will make a financial impact almost immediately.\"", "\"If I were hired, I will compliment your department by adding value to the important initiatives we have prioritized.  I will find ways to make our team better that make sense for the company and share knowledge about the great work we are doing across other departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Packaging+and+Containers", "question": "Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking and proofreading are essential parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean, work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is vital to submit error-free work.\"", "\"I am so accustomed to working under pressure and tight deadlines that I do forget to double check my work at times. This habit is one that I have consciously been working on to improve.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Can you explain a possible problem that may arise with processing tablets?", "answers": ["While there are any number of issues that may arise when processing medications, there are a few that are more common when processing tablets.  Those include: capping, lamination, and moddling.  Explain what happens during one of this issues.", "\"One of the problems I can think of that may arise when processing tablets is lamination.  Lamination is the term used to describe the separation of tablets into two or more layers.\"", "\"There are a few complications that come to mind when I think about tablet processing.  Capping is either a partial or complete separation of a tablet top or bottom crown.  Another possible problem I can thing of is mottling, which is unequal colour distribution of a tablet.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What are some types of additives, and can you provide an example?", "answers": ["Additives are used to increase the stability of a solution.  Types of additives include:  preservatives, anti-oxidants, and synergists.  Explain what one of these types of additives does and give an example for the interviewer.", "\"One example of an additive is an anti-oxidant.  It is  used to prevent the auto oxidation of a drug in the formulation.  An anti-oxidant may be ascorbic acid.  Synergists are another additive that is used to enhance the activity  of anti-oxidants.  An example of a synergist is \ntartaric acid.\"", "\"Preservatives are a type of additive that are used to prevent microbial growth in the drug formulation.  Phenyl mercuric acetate is an example of a preservative, as well as benzalkonium chloride.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What may one of your previous bosses or co-workers say is one of your weaknesses?", "answers": ["This is often a very hard question for a candidate to answer.  The idea behind this question is to approach the weaknesses, or particularly the comments on those weaknesses, in a positive manner.  When you answer, try to find a positive remark regarding something that may otherwise seem negative.", "\"One of my previous co-workers constantly told me that I was too much of a workaholic.  Personally, I don't see that as a weakness.  I have, however, learned to work and accomplish things as assigned and then take on additional work, when time permits, so that things are not left undone.\"", "\"I think if anyone was asked what my weakness is, it is probably in delegating responsibilities.  It's not that I don't know how or that I am unable to make judgment calls on who could do a specific job.  I believe that 'weakness,' if you want to call it that, is because I don't like to impose on others and that often leaves me trying to handle multiple things at once.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What makes you think you will be successful at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Rather than just sharing how you have gone above and beyond expectations in the past, focus on how your qualities will help you to meet and exceed expectations with Company ABC. Discuss the reasons why will you be great at this job. Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and mentorship. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am well-prepared for this next step in my career.\"", "\"I believe my success with Company ABC will come from having all of the hard skills that you are looking for, whether learned in school or gained through work experience.  I know all the key players in this region and stay informed of best practices.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What can you tell me about buffering agents?", "answers": ["Buffering agents dissolve within a solvent and are used to help enable a solution to resist any change in pH should an acid or an alkali be added.   Understanding different agents that may be used in a drug is important for those developing them.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"A buffering agent is used to help balance the pH in a solution.   Examples include citrates or phospates.\"", "\"The choice of a buffer depends on the pH of a solution and the buffering capacity needed.  They should have a low toxicity and be non-irritant  A few examples include carbonate, gluconates, and lactates.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Company ABC has facilities in multiple locations.  Would you be willing to locate if a position is available in a different city/town?", "answers": ["While relocation may not be a requirement for the job for which you are applying, if Company ABC has  more than one location, the interviewer will almost always ask this question.  The important thing to remember with this question is be honest.  If you don't want to move, that's fine.   It's better to say that now than to accept the job and then have conflict later if you are asked to relocate.  The interviewer can make note of your  location preference while trying to find a suitable position for you.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  Also, most of my family live in other states.  Because of that, I am open to the possibility of relocation.  I would love to hear about any opportunities within Company ABC and where you feel I could be an asset.\"", "\"While I am  not opposed to relocating, I would like to stay within 75 miles of this location.  My parents are older and I like to be able to look in on them and be close enough that I can to them within an hour or so if an emergency should arrive.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What are some different types of coatings agents?", "answers": ["Coating is a process by which an essentially dry, outer layer of material is applied to the surface of a dosage form.  Function of coating agents include protection, masking, ease of swallowing, identification etc.", "\"Coating agents are used for a number of reasons such as making pills easier to swallow.  A few types are film coating and sugar coating.\"", "\"Different types of coating agents are compressed coating and film coating.  These help protect that medication and make them more pallatable.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "While Company ABC would like to hire employees who plan on working with us long-term,we do understand that things happen and plans change.  Do you anticipate any significant changes in your life within the next 2-3 years that may affect employment with us?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Still, if you don't plan on being in the same geographical area two or three years from now, it's is be to say that now.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"While unexpected things may arise, I don't anticipate any changes that would affect me being able to continue employment with Company ABC.  I have close ties to the community here and a large family who live nearby.  My hope is to be able to find a position that will allow me to become rooted with Company ABC and grow.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is a humectant, and can you provide an example?", "answers": ["A humectant attracts and retains the moisture in the nearby air via absorption, drawing the water vapor into and/or beneath the organism's surface. Humectants absorb water vapors from the atmosphere until a certain degree of dilution is attained. Aqueous solutions of humectants can reduce the rate of loss of moisture.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"Humectants attract moisture to help an organism achieve a desired level of dilution.  Two types of humectants are  inorganic humectants and organic humectants. Inorganic humectants  Because of compatibility problems and their corrosive nature, inorganic humectants are not frequently used in cosmetics. Calcium chloride is an example.   Organic humectants  are widely used in cosmetics. The most commonly used organic humectants are glycerol, ethylene glycol, polyethylene glycol (PEG), diethylene glycol, tri ethylene glycol, propylene glycol, dipropylene glycol, glycerin, sorbitol, mannitol, glucose.\"", "\"Humectants are used to dilute a substance by attracting and retaining moisture.  One type of humectant is metal organic humectants.  These are limited used in cosmetics because of compatibility problems, corrosive nature and pronounced taste. One example of this class of humectants is sodium lactate.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Can you explain what an excipient is and one of its possible uses?", "answers": ["An excipient is a pharmacologically inactive substance formulated alongside the active pharmaceutical ingredient of a medication.   Excipients have various uses.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"An excipient is a substance that has no active value that is used with the active ingredient of a pharmaceutical medication.  One use of excipients is as a binder.  Binders hold the ingredients in a tablet together.\"", "\"Excipients are used in the production of a medication for multiple reasons.  They have no value as far as an active ingredient, but are used along with the active ingredient.  They are often used as fillers. Fillers typically also fill out the size of a tablet or capsule, making it practical to produce and convenient for the consumer to use.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is your greatest strength?", "answers": ["This is your time to shine.  However, remember the interviewer is looking for work related strengths. Mention a number of them such as being a good motivator, problem solver, performing well under pressure, being loyal, having a positive attitude, eager to learn, taking initiative and attention to detail.", "\"I believe one of my greatest strengths is my communication skills.  I enjoy  meeting new people and getting to know them.\"", "\"One of my strengths is that I work well under pressure.  Instead of allowing myself to feel easily overwhelmed in a tough situation, I try to take time to evaluate a situation and find a way to resolve any issues without become frustrated.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is a parenteral medication?", "answers": ["Parenteral medications are sterile dosage forms administered by injections thorough one more layers of the skin.  Give the interviewer an example of a parenteral medication or route of administration.", "\"Parenteral medications are medications that are given through layers of the skin, such as IV therapy or an injection.  If the medication is administered correctly, it will be sterile.\"", "\"Parenterals are any medication that are given through the skin.  A Rocephin injection is one example.  Also, intravenous medications are considered parenterals.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is the difference between a vial and an ampule?", "answers": ["Understanding the difference in how medications are packaged is important.  Explain your understanding of the differences between a vial and an ampule.", "\"Injectable medications come in ampules or vials.  Ampules have a single dose of medication in them and vials are multi-dose packages.\"", "\"Ampules and vials have injectable medications in them.  A vial has multiple doses of one medication, such as Rocephin, and a vial contains a single dose of medication.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What would you like for people recognize about your personality when they meet you?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two things that are closely related.  For instance, someone with an honest character or good work ethic will tend to be more open about his or her beliefs as well as personal and professional expectations.  The interviewer is looking for ques as to what character you may bring to the table, so to speak.  It is important to remember body language speaks volume and eye contact is a big indicator of your self-esteem, and your self-esteem is reflected outwardly in your personality.  Be confident when you answer and make eye contact with the interviewer.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive.  I would like to think that people who meet me can quickly see that I am easy to get along with.\"", "\"I believe when people meet me they see that I am easy-going and not self-centered.  It is easy to get caught up in the 'me syndrome' and forget that others are important.  That is something I try to  make an extra effort to not do.  I want people to feel like I am someone they can get to know and can work well with.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What type of pharmaceutical excipient is carboxymethyl cellulose?", "answers": ["Carboxymethyl cellulose is an example of a disintegrant.  Disintegrants are added to drug formulations, which assist to breakup tablets and contents of capsules into smaller particles for quick dissolution when it comes in contact with water in the GI tract.", "\"Carboxymethyl cellulose is a disintegrant excipient.  It helps to break down medications in the gastrointestinal tract.\"", "\"It is classified as a disintegrant.  Disintegrants, ideally, exhibit poor solubility and poor gel formation capacity.  They are useful in the digestive tract where they mix with water and hellp to break the contents of capsules or tablets into pieces that are smaller are more easily absorbed.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Why did you choose a career in pharmaceutical manufacturing?", "answers": ["There are many career opportunities within the pharmaceutical industry.  Questions like this give the interviewer an opportunity to know you.  Share your thoughts about your career choice.", "\"I always wanted a career in the healthcare industry, but I wasn't sure if a hospital setting was for me.  I did some research into different health-related career opportunities and really felt like working with pharmaceutical manufacturing would be an opportunity for me to provide a way to help people.\"", "\"I have always been fascinated with chemistry.  I also wanted to do something to provide care for others.  I felt like manufacturing pharmaceuticals would allow me to do both.  I have never considered any other career.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Do you know what a viscosity imparting agent is?", "answers": ["Viscosity imparting agents are used when it is necessary or desirable to increase or decrease the viscosity of a liquid either to make it more palatable or to improve pour ability.", "\"Viscosity imparting agents are also called thickening agents.  One type of viscosity imparting agents is a viscosity enhancer.  Enhancers increase increase the thickness to help improve the taste and make it easier to pour.\"", "\"Viscosity imparting agents help to make a liquid easier to pour and improve the taste.  Viscosity enhancers make liquids thicker and viscosity modifiers make them thinner.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What are some examples of solvents?", "answers": ["A solvent is a substance that can dissolve a solute resulting in a solution. A solvent is usually a liquid but it can also be solid or a gas.  Share your knowledge of solvents and how they are used with the interviewer.", "\"Solvents are used to help create a solution.  The most often used solvent is water, which can be used to improve solubility and stability.\"", "\"Solvents can be in solid or gas form.  They are used to create a solution.  Some solvents are non-aqueous like glycerol and ethanol; they are generally used for a lipophilic drug.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Have you ever had a disagreement with a co-worker, and how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "If you could travel anywhere in the world, where would you go?", "answers": ["Employers realize that there is life outside of work.  Getting to know employees/potential employees and what interests them gives employers an opportunity to develop a relationship with them.  Share what you like.  Have you been to a destination you'd like to return to?  Is there somewhere you've always dreamed of going?  This is also an opportunity for you to get to know the employer.  Ask questions to show your interest in building a relationship.", "\"Without a doubt, I would go to Italy!  I have always wanted to travel and Italy will be one of the first places I go to once I have time to go and really experience it!  Have you ever been to another country?\"", "\"When I was younger, I went on a mission trip to Brazil.  I have always wanted to return and spend time with the missionaries who are still there.  I came back with such an appreciation for the opportunities and conveniences that we have here.  What about you?  Have you ever traveled abroad?\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Company ABC values its employees and strives to create a team atmosphere.  Do you consider yourself a \"team player\"?", "answers": ["Almost everyone says yes to this question. But it is not just a yes/no question. You need to provide behavioral examples to back up your answer.", "\"Yes, I do consider myself a team player. I believe when we all work together we can accomplish so much more than if we try to do things by ourselves without insight from others.\"", "\"I am glad to know that Company ABC values the efforts of teamwork.  I have always made an effort to work well with others and to contribute my strengths to the group in an effort to accomplish a goal together.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "If your previous employer were here, what would he say about you?", "answers": ["Leaving previous employment on good terms is always a good idea.  Interviewers may ask this question and then call the same employer for a reference.  So, while this may not be a time for full disclosure, it is a time to be honest.  Stay positive and focus on your strengths that a previous employer  may share when asked about you.", "\"I believe my previous employer would say I am a hard worker and that I always pull my own weight.  I also feel like he would say that I am trustworthy.\"", "\"I know my previous employer would give me a good reference.  I feel like she would tell you that I am hardworking and dedicated.  I am confidant that she would speak positively about me because she told me the door is always open if I wanted to come back to work with them.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What are some key factors to consider in a manufacturing facility's design?", "answers": ["Facility design is very important in ensuring  the flow of production is done effectively and runs smoothly. Understanding some of the key design essentials is important.  Share any knowledge you may have regarding design importance.", "\" In the critical areas, the flow of air should be in one direction with enough velocity to prevent the particles from closing the area. Also, temperature, as well as humidity, should be regulated.\"", "\"If any contaminants are being generated in an area, there should be an efficiently working HVAC system to remove and prevent the contaminants from spreading to other areas. Ventilation dampers and other services should be positioned for maintenance purpose in a place away from the production area for easy access.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "At Company ABC  we like to encourage employees to have a healthy balance between work and their personal lives.  What are some things you like to do to help you unwind and create balance in your life?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.   The writings in my journal are private and my way of 'letting it all out.'  The blog articles, on the other hand, are my way of using creative writing to share stories with my followers.\"", "\"I really enjoy working out at the gym and, I also take a kickboxing class twice weekly.   After a good workout or class, I always feel like I can rest better and wake up energized and ready for the next day.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is a motivator for you to do well on a job?", "answers": ["This is a personal answer.  The interviewer is getting to know you and what makes you want to do well.  Share your thoughts.", "\"I like the sense of achievement I feel when I do a job well.   I challenge myself daily to do a better job than the day before.\"", "\"I like the feeling of working with a team and accomplishing a goal together.  Knowing that other people count on me as part of their team is a big motivator to perform well.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Why do HEPA filters have a 0.3 micron pore size?", "answers": ["HEPA (High-Efficiency Particle Air) filters are an essential part of the pharmaceutical and healthcare industries, where sterile environments are mandatory.  Share your understanding of their importance.", "\"The smaller the micron, the harder it is to filter out of the air.   Bacteria can be as small as 0.3 microns, which is why 0.3 micron HEPA filters are used in pharmaceutical companies.\"", "\"A standard air filter usually eliminates medium to larger particles from the air.  However, they don't have the capabilities to almost completely eradicate tiny micron size particles from the air as a HEPA filter does.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What are some reasons that could cause chipping in tablet manufacturing?", "answers": ["Chipping occurs when there is breaking of the edges of the tablet during the manufacturing process. . Chipping can occur as the tablet leaves the press or during subsequent operations such as coating.  Share some reasons that chipping may occur and any remedy, if possible.", "\"Chipping could occur during tablet manufacturing by the tablet sticking to the punch face, which could be as a result of poor lubrication, or insufficient drying.   Respectively, the remedy to this cause of chipping would be to properly dry the granules and to use the right amount of lubrication.\"", "\"One cause of chipping could be that the granules are too dry granules which results in chipping when the tablet is under the pressure of the press.   Promoting plasticity through moistening the granules should help resolve this issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What is the difference in a syrup and a suspension?", "answers": ["There is a slight difference in syrup and suspension products that can cause ineffective use in clinical effects.  Understanding the difference between the two is especially important when educating patients on proper use.  Show your understanding of the differences.", "\"In syrups, drug particles are distributed evenly throughout the solution.  In suspensions, the drug particles do not completely dissolve in the solution which means they are not evenly distributed.  It is important to educate patients who are using a suspension to shake the bottle well before dispensing the prescribed amount.\"", "\"Syrups are often viscous due to a high concentration of sugar which makes them more palatable, especially for younger children.  Because drug particles in a suspension do not completely dissolve in the solution, they often settle at the bottom of the bottle making the suspension have two layers.  Properly shaking a suspension before administration is helpful in combining the particles in the poured solution.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "What effect might humidity have on the stability of a tablet?", "answers": ["The level of humidity has a great effect on the stability of pharmaceutical tablets. Tablets and capsules are protected for moisture by their packing. Degradation of tablets and capsules starts when they get a high moisture content.  Share some examples of effects caused by humidity.", "\"When moisture is absorbed into the tablets, it affects physical stability which causes it to be ineffective. The product may then be considered a degradation product.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceutical+Manufacturing", "question": "Company ABC likes to reward employees for their hard work and experience.  How would you feel about someone having the same job title as you making a higher salary because of years of experience?", "answers": ["Most employers do offer higher salary incentives to get more seasoned employees.  This is not meant to devalue a person's knowledge or experience, but rather paying for more experience.  It is important to note that the interviewer is not saying you will definitely make less than someone with more experience.  Many times this question is to see how you respond and how badly you want a position.  If an employee is willing to put in the work and earn the pay increase, employers often see them as someone worth investing in.  This is a good time to ask what the beginning salary is and discuss options that are negotiable such as benefits and paid time off.", "\"I understand that years of experience are often rewarded with higher earning.  I feel, given the chance to demonstrate my knowledge and skills, you will find that I am capable of doing the job as well as some of the more experienced employees.  Having said that, I will not turn down an offer of employment because of a difference in pay based on my present lack of experience.  With that in mind, what benefits are available for someone coming on board with your company with my resume?\"", "\"I appreciate the fact that Company ABC rewards employees for hard work and experience.  While I am confident of my skills, I respect the fact that I may need to effectively show my skills by working here before being offered a higher salary.  I am excited about the prospect of becoming part of a team here at Company ABC and have no doubt that my knowledge and skills will become quickly apparent.\""]}]